<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</guid><description>Data Plane Status Panel The previous release added a pop-up table that displayed statistics about a node’s connections to other node such as gateways. We’ve now moved most of this information to a new panel dedicated for this purpose.
Hovering over the Data Plane status indicator next to the node name still includes basic details about the number of gateways known and connected. And it includes a link to the new panel for more detail:</description></item><item><title>March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</guid><description>Data Plane Panel Improvements In the February 2022 release we introduced the Data Plane status panel for investigating connections between edge and gateway nodes. With this release we’ve added some tools to this panel. The new Ping and Test Performance tools are linked in the far right column of each gateway’s row.
Gateway Ping The gateway ping tool will launch a ping inside the data plane tunnel between the node and the gateway, similar to ICMP ping.</description></item><item><title>May</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</guid><description>Trustgrid Permissions Restructuring Trustgrid’s portal and API have used Role based permissions to manage access within the Trustgrid system. As Trustgrid has expanded our feature set, adding features like containers, and our user base have grown the predefined role structure has become a poor fit. Many times these new features required Trustgrid Support to grant access to users. Additionally, what each role could and could not do was opaque to customers.</description></item><item><title>June</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</guid><description>Faster Node Overview Graphs With this release we have reduced the time it takes for the initial Overview graphs to load when you first navigate to the node.
New Time Range Selector Previously the Trustgrid portal used a few different time range selectors on different pages, none of which were the most user friendly. Trustgrid is standardizing on a new selector shown below which some key new abilities:
Change from Local (browser) time zone to UTC Switch from an Absolute (e.</description></item><item><title>August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</guid><description>Resource-Scoped Permission Policies The May 2022 release enabled the creation of more granular permissions policies. With this release we’ve added the ability to grant permissions to specific node or cluster resources. This enables you to limit a user to only see specific devices with very limited permissions.
Polices now have a Resources section. This can be populated with a list of Trustgrid Resource Names (TGRN) to limit where the defined permissions are applied.</description></item><item><title>October Third Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</guid><description>Repository Performance Improvements This release includes a significant overhaul of the the repository control plane service. This service is responsible for providing upgrade packages and pushing/pulling container images.
Data Plane Stats for Private and Hub Gateways Prior to this release, viewing the Data Plane stats such as tunnel latency and [network hops](https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/ would not display. These stats will now be displayed the just like edge and public gateway stats.
Changing Configured Master (Active) Logging With this release, if a user changes which node is configured as the master (active) member of the cluster it will be logged on Changes for the cluster.</description></item><item><title>October Second Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</guid><description>Order Management Improvements This release is primarily focused on making improvements to our order management system.
Notification of Changes in Open Orders Previously if more than one user was making changes to the same order it was possible the second user to save would overwrite the changes of the first.
Now the system will notify you if someone has changed an order while you have it open. You would then need to refresh the page to see the changes made.</description></item><item><title>October</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</guid><description>Cluster Improvements Cluster Site Health State With this release we introduce the concept of Cluster Site Health State. This addition makes it more obvious when there is an issue with a cluster at a site and possible to configure alarm filters to notify your team when changes occur.
We display the cluster health on the list view:
And on the cluster overview:
Unhealthy notice on cluster overview ![cluster unhealthy notice](cluster-unhealthy-notice.png) Offline notice on cluster overview !</description></item></channel></rss>