<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Troubleshoot on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/troubleshoot/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshoot on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/troubleshoot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Operations Runbook</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cluster Failover Response</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/cluster-failover-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/cluster-failover-response/</guid><description>When the active (master) member of the cluster goes unhealthy the standby member will take over the active role. This process should be automatic and not require manual intervention. However, in certain circumstances, such as the unexpected failover of a public gateway, it is worth investigating to confirm traffic is in a healthy state.
Possible Messages Master role assumed - failover
Indicates the master role has moved from the designated master (primary) to the backup/secondary node Master role reclaimed by expected master</description></item><item><title>Control Plane Disconnect</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/control-plane-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/control-plane-disconnect/</guid><description>When the Control Plane is disconnected there is no way to utilize remote tools to resolve the issue so you will need to contact the End-user technical resource for the site to troubleshoot
When troubleshooting the control plane it is a good idea to familiarize yourself with the Edge Node Startup Process.
Network Requirements In order to connect to the Trustgrid Control Plane, the following outbound traffic must be allowed from the node’s configured primary interface IP address TCP Port 443 and TCP/UDP 8443 to: 35.</description></item><item><title>Node Down Response</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</guid><description>This process is intended to help customer support personnel quickly identify the scope of a node down problem and get services back online as quickly as possible.
Node Down Triage Triage Checklist Determine Production Status of the Trustgrid Node
Confirm High Availability or Disaster Recover is Functioning
If clustered, is the partner active and working
If there is a second site, confirm if it is active
Determine the type of outage (Control Plane, Data Plane or Both)</description></item><item><title>Site Failover</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/site-failover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/site-failover/</guid><description>The below processes should be used to move traffic between sites in event of a complete site down scenario. This is handled by the Virtual Network Route Table.
In the examples below, xxxEdgeCluster is the primary site and xxx-edge3 is the secondary/disaster recovery site. Manual Failover When a customer has selected manual failover, a portal user will need to adjust the destination of all routes currently pointed at the failed site.</description></item></channel></rss>