<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Machines on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Machines on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Images</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/images/</guid><description>The images section allows a user to add/delete virtual machine images.
The Downloaded column shows whether or not an image is present on the node. Field Name Description Display Name Friendly name associated to the image. Description Description for the image. Image File Image file selected from the node data store. Operating System Operating System for the image. This is rather important to optimize the virtual machine configuration. If an incorrect Operating System is selected for the image, the virtual machine might not be able to detect install media or perform critical device controller operations Delete Image If the image is present on the node, executing a delete of the image will prompt the deletion of the image from the node.</description></item><item><title>Volumes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/volumes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/kvm/volumes/</guid><description>Volumes are used to allocate disks or to attach CD-ROMs to virtual machines.
Field Name Description Name Name for the volume. Device Type Virtual machine type.
Disk CD-ROM Device Bus Bus for the device.
IDE VirtIO SCSI SATA Size (Only for Disk) Size in GB, MB, KB, or Bytes for the disk. Disk Provisioning (Only for Disk) Allocation method used for provisioning a disk.
Thin Provision - Disk starts small and expands as more disk space is required up to the size specified.</description></item></channel></rss>