<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Customer Responsibilities</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</guid><description>Trustgrid and our customers share the responsibilities of securing the Trustgrid network. Trustgrid assumes and automates a significant part of the overall security challenges. These challenges range from the cloud to the firmware on hardware appliances. Our customers are responsible for securing physical environments, identity and access management, and all security aspects of the environments where Trustgrid is installed.
Trustgrid Secures the Cloud All cloud management components are secured and monitored by Trustgrid.</description></item><item><title>Trustgrid Support's Node Access and Data Plane Security</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</guid><description>Trustgrid takes security and privacy seriously. Trustgrid teams do not have access to any data that traverses the Data Plane. All customer data moving through the Data Plane is encrypted and inaccessible to Trustgrid staff, including support and engineering teams.
For a clear understanding of the difference between the Data Plane and Control Plane, see the Basic Architecture section.
Node access is strictly limited to maintenance and troubleshooting activities, and only applies to the Control Plane.</description></item></channel></rss>