<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Management Operations on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/</link><description>Recent content in Management Operations on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Changing Node Status (Enabling / Disabling)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</guid><description>Trustgrid nodes can be in two states:
Enabled - In this state the node will connected to the Trustgrid Control Plane and any Data Plane gateways the node is configured to use. Disabled - This is a reduced functionality state that cause the node to only attempt to connect to the Trustgrid control plane. It can be managed to a limited extent but many other Trustgrid features will not function in this state Disabling a node allows for additional security if a device is in transport and can also be used as an easily reversible way of verifying a node is no longer in use before fully deleting the node.</description></item><item><title>Restart the Trustgrid Service on a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</guid><description>Restarting the Trustgrid service is faster than a full node reboot and resolves many non-recurring problems.
Go to the Node detail page for the node affected.
Select Restart located in the top right corner of the page
After clicking, type in the name of the node and click Confirm to execute the action the node agent will restart (Node host will not restart)
Expect the node to alert for disconnection and connection.</description></item><item><title>Reboot a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</guid><description> Click on the Node from the node page you wish to reboot Select Reboot from the top right corner of the page Type in the name of the node in the text box, and click the confirmation button The node will reboot within 60 seconds Node agent will start automatically on reboot Expect the node to alert for disconnect/connect Does not require a cloud gateway</description></item><item><title>Force Node to Pull Down Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/update-node-config/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/update-node-config/</guid><description>Update Node Config button Trustgrid nodes are notified when configuration changes are saved in the Portal. However, if multiple changes are made in a short period of time, the notification will delay for a minute to reduce configuration churn and include all changes. This reduces the number of requests made by each node and the number of configuration changes the node has to process.
If you have made multiple changes to a node&amp;rsquo;s configuration (or its cluster configuration) and want to force the node to pull down the most recent configuration you can use the &amp;ldquo;Update Node Config&amp;rdquo; button.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Trustgrid Appliance Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</guid><description>How an Appliance Node Upgrades The upgrade process will:
Upgrade the Trustgrid application package. As part of this process the node will backup the current running version. Apply security updates to install operating system packages. Reboot the Trustgrid node appliance. For details on what this looks like from a network level see the Node Upgrade Process KB article.
Frequently Asked Questions Is the upgrade disruptive? - Yes. While the appliance is upgrading services will remain available, though performance may be degraded.</description></item><item><title>Deleting Trustgrid Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</guid><description>Be advised: Deleting a node is an irreversible action. Delete nodes only after you are certain it is no longer needed. Best Practices Disable the node(s) for several days prior to deleting. This way if it is discovered that it is still needed it is simple to re-enable. Update any status tag to indicate the node(s) is being decommissioned. Before deleting, remove any virtual network routes with the node as a destination.</description></item><item><title>Deleting Trustgrid Clusters</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-clusters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-clusters/</guid><description>Be advised: Deleting a cluster is an irreversible action. Delete clusters only after you are certain they are no longer needed. Best Practices Remove all members for a period of time to ensure the configuration is no longer needed. Update any status tag to indicate the cluster(s) is being decommissioned. Before deleting, remove any virtual network routes with the cluster as a destination. While these can be removed later, they will be easier to find while the cluster is still listed as the destination.</description></item></channel></rss>