<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network Interface Tools on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/</link><description>Recent content in Network Interface Tools on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS Interface ENA Stats</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-interface-stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-interface-stats/</guid><description>The AWS Stats tool displays Elastic Network Adapter (ENA) statistics for AWS-hosted nodes. These statistics help identify when AWS is throttling network traffic due to instance limits being exceeded. Access requires the service:network-status permission.
Overview When running Trustgrid nodes on AWS EC2 instances, network performance is subject to instance-type-specific limits for bandwidth, packets per second, and connection tracking. The AWS Interface ENA Stats tool allows you to view counters that indicate when these limits have been exceeded, helping diagnose network performance issues.</description></item><item><title>AWS Route Tables Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-route-tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-route-tables/</guid><description>The AWS Route Tables interface tool queries AWS for route tables associated with the selected interface and shows the current route definitions. Use it when validating cluster route failover behavior or investigating unexpected routing.
Accessing AWS Route Tables Open the target node in the Trustgrid portal. Go to Network -&amp;gt; Interfaces. In Interface Tools, click AWS Route Tables. Interface Tools with the AWS Route Tables button highlighted In the service prompt, confirm the interface and click Execute.</description></item><item><title>TCP Port Test</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/tcp-port-test/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/tcp-port-test/</guid><description>The TCP Port Test tool initiates a TCP session with a target IP address and port to confirm fully layer 4 connectivity. This would be similar to using netcat or telnet to test connectivity to a TCP port.
Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity. Select Interfaces under the Network section. Click the Interface TCP Port Test button Selecting TCP Port Test Update the host with the target IP address and the port with the target TCP port.</description></item><item><title>ARP Ping Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/arping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/arping/</guid><description>The arping tool allows you to send an ARP request to a specific IP address on a local interface. This tool is useful for troubleshooting connectivity issues such as confirming if the interface is in the same layer 2 broadcast domain as the target IP address.
Using ARP Ping Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to send an ARP request. Select Interfaces under the Network section.</description></item><item><title>Sniff Traffic Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</guid><description>The Sniff Traffic tool allows you to monitor traffic on a local network interface in realtime within the Trustgrid portal. Only the header information such as source and destination IPs, TCP flags, sequence numbers, etc. are displayed.
Using Sniff Interface Traffic Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to view traffic. Select Interfaces under the Network section. Then from the dropdown select the interface whose traffic you want to monitor.</description></item><item><title>Traffic Capture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/traffic-capture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/traffic-capture/</guid><description>The Traffic Capture tool performs a traffic capture on the selected node, which can help troubleshoot connectivity issues.
Summary The Sniff Interface Traffic tool allows you to monitor traffic in realtime but there are certain instances where you need to be able to capture traffic to a file for further analysis. For example, intermittent issues may require leaving a capture running for an unknown period of time. Or, perhaps you need to review the application data within the packet payload.</description></item></channel></rss>