<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Working with Trustgrid Support</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/</link><description>Recent content in Working with Trustgrid Support on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Help-Center: Submit a Support Request</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/submit-support-request/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/submit-support-request/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Trustgrid support is available 24/7/365 with a commitment to respond to any Emergency Support request within 30 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="to-contact-support">To contact support:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Email: &lt;a href="mailto:support@trustgrid.io">support@trustgrid.io&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Phone: 888-308-8995 x2&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="authorized-support">Authorized Support&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid can only provide support to customers with a Trustgrid Portal account commensurate with the account&amp;rsquo;s permission level in the portal. To receive support the user must be able to respond to an email at the account&amp;rsquo;s email address in the portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="enable-support-for-trustgrid">Enable Support for Trustgrid&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid customers can prohibit Support access to Nodes in the Portal. It may be required to enable this support to resolve certain issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Authorization to Request Support</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/request-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/request-support/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To prevent unauthorized users from potentially compromising the control plane, Trustgrid has implemented a policy to approve customers&amp;rsquo; staff for access to technical support services. Trustgrid will not refuse support completely in cases when unauthorized staff request it, but will limit the disclosure of confidential information and will refuse to make configuration changes without approval from an authorized support contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>All staff who request support must have a portal login.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Trustgrid support staff will not execute any change requested by staff that exceeds that staff members access to portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a. Monitor Access: Staff can alert of issues and request remote assistance but no change in the portal can be requested or made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. Operator Access: Staff can alert of issues and request remote assistance but only changes limited to the Operator role can be requested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. Administrator Access: Staff can request any system change.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>