<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</guid><description>Data Plane Status Panel The previous release added a pop-up table that displayed statistics about a node’s connections to other node such as gateways. We’ve now moved most of this information to a new panel dedicated for this purpose.
Hovering over the Data Plane status indicator next to the node name still includes basic details about the number of gateways known and connected. And it includes a link to the new panel for more detail:</description></item><item><title>March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</guid><description>Data Plane Panel Improvements In the February 2022 release we introduced the Data Plane status panel for investigating connections between edge and gateway nodes. With this release we’ve added some tools to this panel. The new Ping and Test Performance tools are linked in the far right column of each gateway’s row.
Gateway Ping The gateway ping tool will launch a ping inside the data plane tunnel between the node and the gateway, similar to ICMP ping.</description></item><item><title>March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</guid><description>Improved Identity Provider Integration Trustgrid has supported SAML integration to manage portal access for some time. As we began supporting additional services, such as Remote Access applications, more flexibility was needed.
OpenID Support OpenID is a newer standard for managing communication between an application and an Identity Provider (IdP). It offers additional functionality compared to SAML including the ability to simplify integration.
At this point, Trustgrid supports simplified integration with Google G Suite and Microsoft AzureAD which includes the ability to synchronize groups and group members.</description></item><item><title>May</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</guid><description>Trustgrid Permissions Restructuring Trustgrid’s portal and API have used Role based permissions to manage access within the Trustgrid system. As Trustgrid has expanded our feature set, adding features like containers, and our user base have grown the predefined role structure has become a poor fit. Many times these new features required Trustgrid Support to grant access to users. Additionally, what each role could and could not do was opaque to customers.</description></item><item><title>June</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</guid><description>Faster Node Overview Graphs With this release we have reduced the time it takes for the initial Overview graphs to load when you first navigate to the node.
New Time Range Selector Previously the Trustgrid portal used a few different time range selectors on different pages, none of which were the most user friendly. Trustgrid is standardizing on a new selector shown below which some key new abilities:
Change from Local (browser) time zone to UTC Switch from an Absolute (e.</description></item><item><title>August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</guid><description>Resource-Scoped Permission Policies The May 2022 release enabled the creation of more granular permissions policies. With this release we’ve added the ability to grant permissions to specific node or cluster resources. This enables you to limit a user to only see specific devices with very limited permissions.
Polices now have a Resources section. This can be populated with a list of Trustgrid Resource Names (TGRN) to limit where the defined permissions are applied.</description></item><item><title>August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</guid><description>Tag Improvements Two major improvements regarding tags.
Cluster Members Inherit Tags Previously you had to set tags at the node and cluster level which required a lot of duplicate effort. Now when you configure tags at the cluster level the member nodes inherit this tag.
Tags Searchable in the Nodes Table With this release if you add a tag as a column to the nodes table, you can then search the table for matching values.</description></item><item><title>September</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</guid><description>Container Improvements Trustgrid has greatly enhanced the container features we support and this release makes these features available to all users.
Container Management You can now stop and start individual containers running as a service from within the portal.
Container Volumes and Mounts Containers on Trustgrid now support creating persistent volumes and mounting them within the container. These volumes can even be encrypted using Trustgrid managed, software-based encryption.
Container Privileges It is now possible to run containers as a privileged user or specify the user/group the container should execute as.</description></item><item><title>Changing Node Status (Enabling / Disabling)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</guid><description>Trustgrid nodes can be in two states:
Enabled - In this state the node will connected to the Trustgrid Control Plane and any Data Plane gateways the node is configured to use. Disabled - This is a reduced functionality state that cause the node to only attempt to connect to the Trustgrid control plane. It can be managed to a limited extent but many other Trustgrid features will not function in this state Disabling a node allows for additional security if a device is in transport and can also be used as an easily reversible way of verifying a node is no longer in use before fully deleting the node.</description></item><item><title>Review Node Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/review-node-events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/review-node-events/</guid><description>When troubleshooting a problem on edge or gateway nodes, reviewing node events can provide critical information about the nature of the problem.
Choose the node that may be causing the problem Scroll down to Events Look for any critical problems Events for the currently viewed node For issues affecting multiple nodes, review events across the organization to detect patterns or issues.
Choose the Operations tab View Events across the organization Organization wide events</description></item><item><title>Basic Architecture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</guid><description>Nodes The basic building block of a Trustgrid network is a node. Nodes are deployed on-premises or in your cloud provider and connected to each other to build a data plane on top of which additional services such as virtual networking, ztna access, and compute can be provided.
Nodes can be deployed either as an agent, a service running in an existing operating system, or as an appliance which bundles the operating system and Trustgrid software together.</description></item><item><title>October Third Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</guid><description>Repository Performance Improvements This release includes a significant overhaul of the the repository control plane service. This service is responsible for providing upgrade packages and pushing/pulling container images.
Data Plane Stats for Private and Hub Gateways Prior to this release, viewing the Data Plane stats such as tunnel latency and [network hops](https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/ would not display. These stats will now be displayed the just like edge and public gateway stats.
Changing Configured Master (Active) Logging With this release, if a user changes which node is configured as the master (active) member of the cluster it will be logged on Changes for the cluster.</description></item><item><title>October Second Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</guid><description>Order Management Improvements This release is primarily focused on making improvements to our order management system.
Notification of Changes in Open Orders Previously if more than one user was making changes to the same order it was possible the second user to save would overwrite the changes of the first.
Now the system will notify you if someone has changed an order while you have it open. You would then need to refresh the page to see the changes made.</description></item><item><title>October</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</guid><description>Cluster Improvements Cluster Site Health State With this release we introduce the concept of Cluster Site Health State. This addition makes it more obvious when there is an issue with a cluster at a site and possible to configure alarm filters to notify your team when changes occur.
We display the cluster health on the list view:
And on the cluster overview:
Unhealthy notice on cluster overview ![cluster unhealthy notice](cluster-unhealthy-notice.png) Offline notice on cluster overview !</description></item><item><title>Request Trustgrid Trial Account</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/request-trial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/request-trial/</guid><description>The process below will guide you through requesting a free trial account.
High-Level Steps Sign up for a Trustgrid trial account Verify email Sign in Prerequisites Email address Chrome-based browser Step 1 - Create a Trustgrid account Using Chrome or a similar browser navigate to https://portal.trustgrid.io/signup Provide the requested information. Note that the account will be created based on the provided Company Name. A verification email will be sent to the provided address.</description></item><item><title>Node Agent Deployments</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/agent-deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/agent-deploy/</guid><description>Supported Operating Systems Linux Ubuntu 22.04 LTS x86-64/AMD64 At this time only x86-64/AMD64 based operating systems are supported. Container The Trustgrid agent can be deployed as a container on Linux systems. This provides an isolated environment for the agent without requiring a full operating system instance.
Trustgrid provides a Docker image that contains the agent pre-configured and optimized to run in Docker or similar container hosting environments like Kubernetes.
Agent Installation Installation instructions are also shown in the portal after adding an agent.</description></item><item><title>December</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</guid><description>Data Plane Status Table Previously Trustgrid had a visual indicator on the Node detail page to show the Data Plane health of a node, but it only showed the state as Connected, Degraded or Disconnected. While connected and disconnected were clear, there was little information on why the status was Degraded.
With this release hovering over the Data Plane status icon will bring up a pop-up screen showing all the peers and and their connection status.</description></item><item><title>Support Responsibility Matrix</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</guid><description>The matrix below defines the primary responsible party for troubleshooting and resolving different types of issues. Trustgrid support can be engaged to assist in resolving issues not directly in scope of their responsibility.
Organization and Roles Trustgrid Trustgrid is a software and services provider that operates a multi-tenant cloud management system and assists customers and end-users with the deployment and management of a data transfer plane.
Customer Customers have a direct, contractual relationship with Trustgrid to utilize Trustgrid’s software and services.</description></item><item><title>Debug Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/debug-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/debug-logs/</guid><description>What are debug logs? Debug log files contain detailed technical information about the operation of a Trustgrid node. They are useful for Trustgrid support engineers to troubleshoot issues. If your node is experiencing problems, generating logs at that time may help identify the root cause.
Generating Log Files The Debug Log button is located in the top right of a Node Details page. Debug Logs button The Debug Log dialogue will show any previously generated log files.</description></item><item><title>Restart the Trustgrid Service on a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</guid><description>Restarting the Trustgrid service is faster than a full node reboot and resolves many non-recurring problems.
Go to the Node detail page for the node affected.
Select Restart located in the top right corner of the page
After clicking, type in the name of the node and click Confirm to execute the action the node agent will restart (Node host will not restart)
Expect the node to alert for disconnection and connection.</description></item><item><title>Site Requirements</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/site-requirements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/site-requirements/</guid><description>Trustgrid’s architecture consists of Nodes deployed at the Edge (on-premise) and management infrastructure built in AWS. Nodes create tunnels to other nodes for data transfer, and to the management infrastructure for control. All tunnels are TLS connections and must be permitted by any firewall between
Network Requirements for All Nodes In order to connect to the Trustgrid Control Plane, the following outbound traffic must be allowed from the node’s configured primary interface IP address</description></item><item><title>Working with Trustgrid Support</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/</guid><description>Paying Trustgrid customers can contact our support team for assistance for Tier 2 support requests and assistance with Tier 1 support requests as defined by the support responsibility matrix.
Support Hours Production impacting issues (P1 Severity): 24/7/365 support All other issues: Monday-Friday 8:30am-5:30pm Central Time (excluding US holidays) To contact support: Below are the methods or requesting support from Trustgrid:
Request support via the Portal - ** This is the recommended method to request support.</description></item><item><title>Reboot a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</guid><description> Click on the Node from the node page you wish to reboot Select Reboot from the top right corner of the page Type in the name of the node in the text box, and click the confirmation button The node will reboot within 60 seconds Node agent will start automatically on reboot Expect the node to alert for disconnect/connect Does not require a cloud gateway</description></item><item><title>Implement Access Policy Restrictions</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/access-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/access-policies/</guid><description>When designing a network from a zero-trust, least-privilege mindset, all agents and appliances should restrict access as much as possible both to each other and their adjacent network resources. Trustgrid allows for granular control over what traffic is permitted across the virtual network using access policies. The default virtual network was created with an &amp;ldquo;Allow All&amp;rdquo; policy to facilitate initial connectivity during the trial period.
In this section, we will update the policy to restrict traffic between the two agents.</description></item><item><title>Node Deployment</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/deployment/</guid><description>Nodes are available in two form factors:
Appliance - This is a combination of a fully managed operating system and Trustgrid software pre-installed. Agent - This is a software package that can installed on supported operating systems. Users can install additional software and configure the operating system as needed. Functionality Agent Appliance Gateway Capabilities None Data Plane or ZTNA Operating System Multiple Supported OS, install additional software Fully managed OS and Trustgrid service, no additional software permitted Updates Managed by user via OS native tools OS and Trustgrid updates managed via Trustgrid Interface IP Management Managed by user via OS native tools Configurable via Trustgrid portal or local console Layer 3 VPN Single Virtual Network connectivity Support for multiple Virtual Networks Layer 4 Proxy Full Support Full Support Compute Commands only Commands, Containers or VMs supported Nodes can be deployed in a variety of ways, including as virtual machines, containers (as agents), or bare metal servers.</description></item><item><title>Force Node to Pull Down Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/update-node-config/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/update-node-config/</guid><description>Update Node Config button Trustgrid nodes are notified when configuration changes are saved in the Portal. However, if multiple changes are made in a short period of time, the notification will delay for a minute to reduce configuration churn and include all changes. This reduces the number of requests made by each node and the number of configuration changes the node has to process.
If you have made multiple changes to a node&amp;rsquo;s configuration (or its cluster configuration) and want to force the node to pull down the most recent configuration you can use the &amp;ldquo;Update Node Config&amp;rdquo; button.</description></item><item><title>Network Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</guid><description>Flow logs are a records of for network traffic that passes through a node. They can be used to troubleshoot connectivity issues, or to monitor traffic patterns.
What are flow logs? Flow logs are records containing metadata about each network traffic flow, or conversation, from the initial connection (e.g. the first SYN packet for TCP) to the closing of the connection (e.g. FIN or RST packets for TCP). Flow logs do not contain any payload data for the flow which makes them much smaller and more secure than a full packet capture of the same flow.</description></item><item><title>Networking</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</guid><description>Trustgrid delivers a software defined wide area network (SD-WAN) that enables connectivity between cloud environments, data centers, and edge or on-premise hosts. Our robust networking feature set provides layer 3 and layer 4 network overlays with cloud management tools.
Types of Connectivity Trustgrid establishes mutual TLS tunnels between nodes using mutual authentication. These tunnels between edge nodes and gateway nodes constitute the data plane of a Trustgrid network. Over this tunnel two distinct types of connectivity are supported, Layer 3 and Layer 4.</description></item><item><title>Configure Subnet Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/subnet-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/subnet-routing/</guid><description>The tutorial up to this point only demonstrated the ability to send traffic between the IP addresses assigned to the trustgrid0 interfaces on each agent. However, it&amp;rsquo;s quite likely that security and operational constraints will prevent the Trustgrid agent from being installed directly on the target server. Instead, the agent will need to route traffic destined for the target server&amp;rsquo;s local network.
In this section, we will configure an agent to route traffic destined for another network through the Trustgrid virtual network.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Trustgrid Appliance Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</guid><description>How an Appliance Node Upgrades The upgrade process will:
Upgrade the Trustgrid application package. As part of this process the node will backup the current running version. Apply security updates to install operating system packages. Reboot the Trustgrid node appliance. For details on what this looks like from a network level see the Node Upgrade Process KB article.
Frequently Asked Questions Is the upgrade disruptive? - Yes. While the appliance is upgrading services will remain available, though performance may be degraded.</description></item><item><title>Deleting Trustgrid Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</guid><description>Be advised: Deleting a node is an irreversible action. Delete nodes only after you are certain it is no longer needed. Best Practices Disable the node(s) for several days prior to deleting. This way if it is discovered that it is still needed it is simple to re-enable. Update any status tag to indicate the node(s) is being decommissioned. Before deleting, remove any virtual network routes with the node as a destination.</description></item><item><title>Deleting Trustgrid Clusters</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-clusters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-clusters/</guid><description>Be advised: Deleting a cluster is an irreversible action. Delete clusters only after you are certain they are no longer needed. Best Practices Remove all members for a period of time to ensure the configuration is no longer needed. Update any status tag to indicate the cluster(s) is being decommissioned. Before deleting, remove any virtual network routes with the cluster as a destination. While these can be removed later, they will be easier to find while the cluster is still listed as the destination.</description></item><item><title>WAN/ISP Redundancy Configurations</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/wan-redunancy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/wan-redunancy/</guid><description>The sections below provide examples of how Trustgrid nodes can be deployed to provide WAN/ISP redundancy Behind Firewall/Router with Multiple ISP Connections In this configuration the Trustgrid WAN interfaces are behind a firewall or router that has two independent ISP connections to provide internet access.
The firewall or router is responsible for either failing over outbound traffic in the event of an ISP failure, or to route different nodes to utilize specific ISP connections.</description></item><item><title>December 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-12/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251124-2340 20251124-234159.0f29e39 n-2.23.3 This is a minor release that fixes the following issues:
There was a situation where a bad certificate for the control plane could cause a device to stop attempting to connect. Simultaneous disconnections of the cluster heartbeat connections could cause a device to enter a deadlock state where it would not attempt to reconnect to its cluster peers. Resolves an issue where non-cluster appliance nodes would log an error about looking for a cluster IP address.</description></item><item><title>November 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-11/</guid><description>Validation Fixes Portal now allows CIDRs for interface IPs to have a /31 subnet. Previously, broadcast and network address validations prevented this from saving. Fixes the client field validation for BGP configuration. Cluster Config Changes Cluster configuration sent to nodes (appliances) now includes a version counter managed in the control plane. This prevents split brain scenarios where a node that is unable to connect to the control plane could repeatedly attempt to become the active member, even when the connected member has been designated active.</description></item><item><title>November 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-11/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251105-2319 20251105-135239.a7de5ae n-2.23.2 Cluster Fixes and Improvements Fixed an issue where, after the configured active cluster member was changed while the original active node was offline, the returning node could incorrectly claim the active role. This occurred because the returning node was unaware of the change and briefly assumed the active role before releasing it, but the newly configured active node did not reclaim the role.</description></item><item><title>October 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-10/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251006-2299 20251006-145121.01eb7c5 n-2.23.1 Resolve Inaccurate UDP Events and Debug Logs This release will fix an issue that caused some nodes with UDP enabled to generate a large number of events indicating:
UDP Tunnel has timed out for node &amp;lt;nodename&amp;gt; and endpoint &amp;lt;endpoint&amp;gt; UDP Tunnel connection has been re-established for node &amp;lt;nodename&amp;gt; and endpoint &amp;lt;endpoint&amp;gt; These events were inaccurate and could be safely ignored. UDP tunnel traffic was NOT disrupted.</description></item><item><title>August 2025 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-08/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250813-2291 20250813-201825.ef18f9a n-2.23.0 DNS Health Appliances being able to successfully resolve DNS is important for their overall functionality and reliability. Ensuring that DNS queries are properly handled can prevent a range of issues, especially regarding connections to the Trustgrid control plane.
To ensure newly provisioned nodes can connect, even if their provided DNS servers are not immediately reachable, the node has a DNS cache for critical control plane services.</description></item><item><title>July 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-07/</guid><description>Authentication Fixes Address an issue causing some users to get a 502 Bad Gateway on login if their users had very complex policies attached. Fixes an issue that caused Internal Server Error messages when a user attempts to logout.</description></item><item><title>June 2025 Major Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-06/</guid><description>VLAN Sub-Interface Improvements Adds SNMP support for VLAN interfaces, enhancing monitoring capabilities. Removes the node-level restriction on VLAN interface assignments. Infovisor Redesign This release includes a significant redesign of the Infovisor, providing a more intuitive and user-friendly interface. Some key improvements include:
Info is now grouped into multiple panels that can be collapsed or expanded, and even added/removed for easier navigation. All info fields now include a copy button when hovered over, allowing for easy copying of information.</description></item><item><title>April 2025 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-04/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250415-2266 20250415-213243.4a224c3 n-2.22.0 Hop Monitoring Improvements This release makes some significant improvements to Hop Monitoring. Previously the Hop Monitoring ran every 20 seconds providing only 3 samples per minute. This was not enough to provide accurate data for some applications. This release increases the sample rate to every 5 seconds. This allows the Hop Monitoring to provide accurate data for applications that require a high sample rate.</description></item><item><title>April 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-04/</guid><description>New Hop Monitoring Options This cloud release when combined with the April 2025 major appliance release, adds the following new Hop Monitoring options in the Gateway &amp;gt; Client panel.
Other Improvements and Fixes Fixes an issue preventing setting the cluster heartbeat IP on Google Cloud Platform appliances.</description></item><item><title>March 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-03/</guid><description>Other Improvements and Fixes Takes additional steps to prevent issues that lead to control plane outages in February 2025. Fixes an issue that prevented some models from saving their Gateway configuration changes.</description></item><item><title>February 2025 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-02/</guid><description>Permissions and Policies Condition Scoped Policies With this release we expand our permissions model to allow for using tags to scope the policy. This allows for more granular control of permissions, or as an alternative to specifying TGRNs in the policy.
For example, if you wanted to limit a group of users to only see the nodes and cluster for a specific client, you could create a policy that looks like this: Tag Scoped Policy based on ClientID tag Any cluster or node with this tag would have the permissions granted by this policy.</description></item><item><title>January 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-01/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250109-2213 20250109-221438.4c724ae n-2.21.1 Other Improvements and Fixes Fixes an issue where connections to the Trustgrid control plane could get stuck in a CLOSE_WAIT state. This could cause the node to show as disconnect despite a working data plane connection. Adds an early release feature to allow clustered Azure-based appliances to manage a floating, local cluster IP address similar to on-premises appliances. Currently there is no UI support for this feature.</description></item><item><title>November 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-11/</guid><description>Upgrade Manager This release makes available the Upgrade Manager to orchestrate upgrades across large numbers of devices. The Upgrade Manager can target specific nodes and clusters based on tags and provides a single pane of glass for monitoring the upgrade process.
Upgrade Manager also automates Cluster upgrades by starting with the standby node in the cluster, triggering a failover once it that node has completed the upgrade, and then upgrading the other member of the cluster.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot High Tunnel Latency</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/latency-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/latency-troubleshooting/</guid><description>Active Incident Triage Steps These steps should be performed as soon as possible while the incident is occurring.
Latency issues are frequently temporary and if you do not gather this information at the time of the incident it will prevent deeper analysis. 1. Enable Hop Monitoring Requires permissions to modify the edge node config. If your user is read-only skip to Step 2.
Hop monitoring uses TCP SYN packets to continuously monitor the path between an edge node and all it&amp;rsquo;s attached gateways.</description></item><item><title>October 2024 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-10/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20241010-2172 20241010-161952.c6810b2 n-2.21.0 Force Node Health Check Refresh In the July 2024 cloud release Trustgrid exposed warnings in the portal if a node was unable to connect to its configured DNS server, the Trustgrid update repository (repo), or if SSH had been reconfigured to listen on an IP other than localhost. These health checks run automatically at the following times:
Repo Connectivity is checked every 24 hours DNS Resolution runs hourly SSH Lockdown is checked when the node service first starts With this release, rather than waiting for the health checks to rerun and update the state of each check you can now force the node to rerun each check.</description></item><item><title>October 2024 Agent Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-10/</guid><description>Package Version Release 0.2.20240905-2146 a-0.3.0 Disable UDP Tunnels This release introduces an option to disable UDP tunnels for agent-based nodes. This is useful for nodes that are behind a NAT or firewall that does not support UDP. Agent-based nodes will continue to have UDP enabled by default.
Other Fixes and Improvements Resolved an issue where agents running as containers would attempt to remove IP tables rules for layer 3 VPN forwarding that did not exist.</description></item><item><title>September 2024 2nd Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09-2/</guid><description>Removal of Select All Option As part of the July backend library a &amp;ldquo;Select All&amp;rdquo; option was introduced on tables, such as the nodes table. Trustgrid has determined this option creates risks of large changes with insufficient controls to prevent mistakes so we are removing it from all tables.</description></item><item><title>September 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09/</guid><description>Data Plane Status for Gateways A recent change to the data plane panel to display disconnected peers had the unintended side-effect that appliances acting as gateways would show a Degraded status if any of their clients wasn&amp;rsquo;t connected, even if that client was offline. As this is a pretty normal state the status was confusing for users. The data plane status indicator has been changed to only count the connections the node is responsible for initiating and does not count any inbound connections.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07-2/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240719-2112 20240719-202719.9cf7134 n-2.20.0 Configuration Retrieval Improvements Appliances retrieve their configuration from the control plane services. Before this release, it was not obvious if a node was unable to pull down its configuration which could lead to unexpected behavior. Two improvements have been made:
A new event called Configuration Update Failure has been created that the appliance will send if it is unable to connect to the configuration control plane API endpoint.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-07/</guid><description>Portal Backend Library Update With this release, we are updating the React library used in the Portal to a more recent version. This change should be mostly invisible to users there are a few notable improvements including:
Resizable columns: In most tables including the Nodes and Flow Logs tables. This will make it easier to read the data in the tables. Notifications are improved: Node actions show in-progress status and node alerts appear as stackable bottom-right alerts expanding on hover.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Agent Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-07/</guid><description>Package Version Release 0.2.20240709-2101 a-0.2.1 Certificate Expiration This release resolves an issue with an expired client certificate that can cause connectivity issues. It also takes steps to prevent future occurrences.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240704-2096 20240704-010918.2.b2a86bf n-2.19.3 Dynamic Routing Issue A recent release broke the ability of a node to announce a VPN Dynamic route to a peer. This release resolves that issue.</description></item><item><title>June 2024 Agent Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-06/</guid><description>Package Version Release 0.2.20240618-2083 a-0.2.0 Display Available Resource Statistics The agent has previously reported the percent utilization of CPU, memory, and disk space. With this release, we also report the total available resources to provide more context to those statistics. This information includes:
The number of CPU cores The total amount of memory The total amount of disk space This information is displayed in the Host Performance graph on the Overview page.</description></item><item><title>June 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-06/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240514-2064 20240514-213500.a967cd2 n-2.19.2 Issues Resolved Flow logs related to port forwards were not showing on the receiving device An issue was preventing some security packages from being updated Updated the AWS library being utilized in the AWS dependency package</description></item><item><title>May 2024 2nd Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05-2/</guid><description>Issues Resolved Nodes or Clusters with upper case letters were impacted by a number of UI bugs that prevented: Viewing the VPN configuration Creating modifying routes with upper case named nodes/clusters as the destination</description></item><item><title>May 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05/</guid><description>Introducing Alert Center A new Alert Center has been added to the node page to centralize alert messages and simplify resolving multiple alerts. This removes the alerts from the Infovisor menu and makes resolving multiple alerts easier. Example alert center with 3 open alerts Other Improvements and Fixes Further improvements in flow log query performance for faster results and resolved an issue that caused exports to not be complete. Detaching Policies now prompts for confirmation.</description></item><item><title>April 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-04/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240422-2039 20240422-165737.3d6b62c n-2.19.1 Abnormal Disconnect Messages limited to Clients Before this release, both the appliances that are acting as the gateway server and the edge node client would send abnormal disconnect events. This change limits abnormal disconnect messages to only be sent from the client to avoid excessive alert notifications on the gateway server.
VPN Communication with Out-of-date Peers A recently release version of the appliance introduced an unexpected change that caused out-of-date clients, running versions from early 2021 or older, to receive VPN packets they could not process.</description></item><item><title>March 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-03/</guid><description>Portal Notification Improvements This release makes several changes to how a portal user is notified of new events and commands (such as Restart and Reboot) related to the node being viewed. The toast pop-up notifications have a new look as shown below: Example notifications of a restart request and the resulting events The notifications will automatically close or can be dismissed by clicking the X at the top corner.
This release also will notify if a Restart request fails to complete successfully by showing a Failed status toast and a message in the center of the screen.</description></item><item><title>March 2024 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-03/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240306-1999 20240306-161006.62ba5a5 n-2.19.0 Dynamic Access Policy Evaluation Previously Access Policies were only evaluated at the time a flow was created. With this release, access policies will be re-evaluated in realtime for active flows. This allows dynamically changing policies to immediately take effect without requiring existing flows to timeout or reset.
System Resources Overview Appliances running this release will now share with the control plane the number of CPU cores, total system memory (RAM), and total disk size.</description></item><item><title>February 2024 Agent Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/agent/2024-02/</guid><description> Package Version Release 0.2.20240220-1987 a-0.1.0 This is the initial release of the agent-based Trustgrid node software.
Production Features include: Support for Ubuntu 22.04 Basic agent VPN functionality Layer-4(L4) Proxy support with services and connectors Beta Support: Running the agent in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 9 and in containers like Docker/k8s</description></item><item><title>February 2024 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-02/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240203-1968 20240203-071412.8f765f6 n-2.18.0 Removal of Local UI System The local UI functionality allowed users with direct physical access to an appliance network port to connect to a lightweight web server on the appliance to change the WAN interface IP and see the connectivity status. Several years ago, this solution was augmented with the Console Utility which has proved easier to use and has been expanded to provide much more functionality.</description></item><item><title>February 2024 Release Notes - Minor</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-02/</guid><description>Flow Log Performance Improvements This release further increases the performance of flow log search using our new database.
Other Improvements The MTR interface in the portal now supports selecting a source IP from your interface and cluster IPs. The Reboot and Restart buttons in the portal will now be disabled if a node is offline. This is to make clear you cannot perform these actions on an offline node. Other Fixes Resolves issue preventing adding Azure AD as an identity provider.</description></item><item><title>January 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/january-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/january-2024/</guid><description>Default Authentication Provider Change Trustgrid has previously utilized Auth0 as the authentication provider for customers who do not use a custom identity provider (IdP). With this release, Trustgrid has migrated to utilizing an internally managed authentication service to provide more control and stability.
This change will have no impact on customers using their own Identity Providers (IdPs) for portal authentication User Migration Process As part of this process users will be prompted to migrate their accounts from the previous Auth0 provider to the new internally managed authentication service.</description></item><item><title>December 2023 Appliance Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/dec-2023-minor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/dec-2023-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231206-1914 20231206-183238.65d2bde n-2.17.3 Disable UDP Rekeying A customer had a misconfiguration that led to the UDP rekeying messages being lost. This compounded the performance impact as the UDP tunnels had to be rebuilt frequently.
This release adds the ability for Trustgrid support to disable UDP rekeying on a gateway if needed. Trustgrid will make the UDP rekeying process more resilient and better able to handle lost key exchanges in the future.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Third Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-3/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issues:
Issues Fixed Fixes an issue that caused virtual network access policies to fail to respect configured line numbers.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Appliance Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/nov-2023-minor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/nov-2023-minor/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231122-1901 20231122-215335.d942235 n-2.17.2 Resolved Issues Fixes an issue introduced in the October 2023 release that caused the end time of flow logs to be incorrect Fixes an issue that prevented registering nodes in newer AWS regions</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-2/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issue:
Issues Fixed A function was deprecated in the last release as it was believed to be no longer needed but it was discovered that some methods of registration, such as the AWS CloudFormation template, still relied on it. This release removes the deprecation and restores the function.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023/</guid><description>Statistics Improvements Long Term Statistics Starting with this release the Overview graphs for nodes running the July 2023 release or newer will display 1 week and 1 month statistic views. Previously only 24 hours was visible in the portal. This allows viewing historical usage trends over longer periods of time directly from the node detail page.
1 week stats are aggregated into hourly data points 1 months stats are aggregated into 6 hour data points JVM Heap Metrics A new section called Metrics with a new statistic called JVM Heap to help make clear if the load on a node requires more memory than is currently allocated to the node process.</description></item><item><title>October 2023 Appliance Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023-1-minor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023-1-minor/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231017-1855 20231017-165331.5772aac n-2.17.1 Resolved Issues Fixed an issue where the appliance would stop responding to SNMP traffic on the virtual management IP if virtual network port forwards were configured.</description></item><item><title>October 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231003-1842 20231003-145438.e8103a2 n-2.17.0 Support for running Ubuntu 22.04 LTS This release adds support for running the Trustgrid node appliance on Ubuntu 22.04 LTS for new deployments on AWS, Azure and vSphere. The 18.04 appliances will continue to be supported and security updates made available via the Trustgrid repository.
There are no plans to support upgrading OS on deployed devices at this time due to the risks involved.</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Second Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230824-1797 20230824-150008.3c2d422 n-2.16.2 Update Fix This minor release resolves several issues:
Fixed an issue where client devices could experience increased CPU utilization if their peer gateways were offline or unreachable. Resolved issues with ARP on VLAN interface cluster IPs that could cause both active and standby members to respond to ARP requests. This prevented proper failover behavior. Resolved SNMP issues for VMware VM8 nodes that didn&amp;rsquo;t have all 8 virtual network interfaces attached to the virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/august-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/august-2023/</guid><description>Cluster Site Health Improvements Since introducing our cluster site health state feature there have been several instances where the state was being reported incorrectly. This release has taken steps to prevent that and has also introduced a new tool to force validating the health state in the event the state does appear incorrect. Validate Health action Data Plane Panel Improvements This release includes two improvements to the Data Plane panel:</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230731-1784 20230731-222839.d3f2205 n-2.16.1 Update Fix This minor release resolves an issue that prevented a security package from upgrading.</description></item><item><title>July 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/july-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/july-2023/</guid><description>Network Interface Panel Changes Interface Details Copy All Button Frequently Trustgrid users need to share the interface configuration information with people who do not have access to the Trustgrid portal. There is now a Copy All button that will load all of these details into your clipboard.
Copy All button Example WAN interface output:
IP: 172.16.11.31/24 Hardware Address: 00:50:56:8e:03:54 Gateway: 172.16.11.1 DNS1: 172.16.11.4 DNS2: 4.2.2.2 Public IP Removed from WAN Interface The WAN interface used to include a field labeled &amp;ldquo;Public IP&amp;rdquo; that was the IP address the Trustgrid control plane saw as the source IP for traffic from the node.</description></item><item><title>July 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230712-1762 20230712-200223.7cced96 n-2.16.0 New Event Types Several new event types are generated with this version of the node appliance software.
DNS Failure If the node is unable to resolve DNS via its configured DNS servers it will generate a DNS Resolution error event. Example DNS resolution events Interface Down Notification This event is triggered when any configured interface&amp;rsquo;s link state goes from UP to DOWN.</description></item><item><title>May 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023-2/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issues:
Issues Fixed The Overview graphs on a Node Detail page showing &amp;ldquo;invalid date&amp;rdquo; when you hover over a VPN data point. The Flow Logs Advanced Search did not display the correct flows when the &amp;ldquo;Newest First&amp;rdquo; flow log order was used.</description></item><item><title>May 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023/</guid><description>Accessibility Improvements Prior to this release we used only the color red to indicate if the control or data plane was disconnected. We now use different icons to indicate there is an issue with connectivity.
Control Plane Disconnected Control Plane Disconnect icon Data Plane Disconnected Data Plane Disconnected icon Change Audit Improvements Several improvements where made around our change auditing system including:
Tag changes are now audited. Change records can now be replicated into a customer&amp;rsquo;s AWS S3 bucket.</description></item><item><title>April 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023-2/</guid><description>Issues Fixed This minor release fixes the following issues:
Network Maps displayed peer nodes as disconnected New Orders could not be created if left open too long before the first save</description></item><item><title>April 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023/</guid><description>Documentation Trustgrid is moving away from our documentation previously hosted on Confluence to docs-as-code system at https://docs.trustgrid.io. This should enable us to more tightly integrate the portal UI with related documentation.
As a start, we&amp;rsquo;ve created a link called Documentation under the Management section of the main navigation bar that will open the docs in a new tab.
Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve created a section for release notes that will allow you to monitor release for Control Plane and Node releases via RSS feeds going forward.</description></item><item><title>Configure FTP and FTPS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/ftp-and-ftps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/ftp-and-ftps/</guid><description>FTPS &amp;amp; FTPS Using Layer 3 FTP &amp;amp; FTPS are supported in passive mode when using layer 3. This configuration requires the FTP server to be configured with the external IP address in the passive settings set to the Trustgrid virtual IP that corresponds to the FTP server.
FileZilla passive mode settings:
FTP Using Layer 4 FTP is supported in passive mode when using L4 Proxy, however FTPS is not. To configure FTP access through L4 Proxy, the Outbound L4 Service and/or L4 Connector need to be configured with FTP set as the protocol as shown below:</description></item><item><title>Ping Remote Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/ping-remote-node/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/ping-remote-node/</guid><description>This tool runs a ping from the gateway node to a remote edge node to verify the Trustgrid overlay network is functioning as expected.
Usage Navigate to the node from which you want to test connectivity.
Click the Data Plane link on the left hand side.
Among the gateways (in the case of an edge node) or edge nodes (in the case of a gateway), click Ping on the row of the node you want to test.</description></item><item><title>TCP Port Test</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/tcp-port-test/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/tcp-port-test/</guid><description>The TCP Port Test tool initiates a TCP session with a target IP address and port to confirm fully layer 4 connectivity. This would be similar to using netcat or telnet to test connectivity to a TCP port.
Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity. Select Interfaces under the Network section. Click the Interface TCP Port Test button Selecting TCP Port Test Update the host with the target IP address and the port with the target TCP port.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Network Hops to Peers</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/</guid><description>This feature collects traceroute-like data from all its connected peers and stores the results in the Trustgrid cloud for historical review.
Network hop monitoring as described below requires the August 2025 major appliance release or later. Versions from 20220808 until that version had no payload and were sent every 20 seconds How it Works The node will send out TCP SYN packets to each peer&amp;rsquo;s public IP and port (if a gateway) with incrementing Time To Live (TTL) values every 20 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Configure Layer 3 VPN</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/config-l3-vpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/config-l3-vpn/</guid><description>The VPN feature enables routing of IP packets by utilizing a virtual IP space that is configured on the nodes. In this configuration, the node can be used as the next hop for route destined for the virtual IP space, or the node can be used as the default gateway for a network. The virtual IP space is used as a transit network with NAT being utilized to translate IP addresses on to/from the virtual IP space on either side.</description></item><item><title>Enable SAML with Okta</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/saml-okta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/saml-okta/</guid><description>In Okta, switch to the Classic UI to be able to configure SAML applications.
Further Information on configuring SAML Application in Okta Classic UI: https://developer.okta.com/standards/SAML/setting_up_a_saml_application_in_okta/
Create an Application, then select Web and SAML 2.0.
When configuring SAML, enter the Trustgrid Portal and select EmailAddress for Name ID format and Email for Application username.
Complete the following survey questions and then download the IDP Metadata XML File by clicking on Identity Provider Metadata link.</description></item><item><title>Cluster Failover Response</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/cluster-failover-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/cluster-failover-response/</guid><description>When the active (master) member of the cluster goes unhealthy the standby member will take over the active role. This process should be automatic and not require manual intervention. However, in certain circumstances, such as the unexpected failover of a public gateway, it is worth investigating to confirm traffic is in a healthy state.
Possible Messages Master role assumed - failover
Indicates the master role has moved from the designated master (primary) to the backup/secondary node Master role reclaimed by expected master</description></item><item><title>Control Plane Disconnect</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/control-plane-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/control-plane-disconnect/</guid><description>When the Control Plane is disconnected there is no way to utilize remote tools to resolve the issue so you will need to contact the End-user technical resource for the site to troubleshoot
When troubleshooting the control plane it is a good idea to familiarize yourself with the Edge Node Startup Process.
Network Requirements In order to connect to the Trustgrid Control Plane, the following outbound traffic must be allowed from the node’s configured primary interface IP address TCP Port 443 and TCP/UDP 8443 to: 35.</description></item><item><title>Limit Node Functionality to Current Public IP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/limit-node-functionality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/limit-node-functionality/</guid><description>This security feature allows restricting full node functionality to the current public IP address. If the public IP changes the data plane connectivity will cease to function and no data plane traffic will pass. It is the equivalent to disabling a node in the trustgrid portal.
This feature should not be used on networks where the Public IP is controlled via DHCP. It should only be used where the public address is statically assigned to the node and is not expected to change.</description></item><item><title>Node Down Response</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</guid><description>This process is intended to help customer support personnel quickly identify the scope of a node down problem and get services back online as quickly as possible.
Node Down Triage Triage Checklist Determine Production Status of the Trustgrid Node
Confirm High Availability or Disaster Recover is Functioning
If clustered, is the partner active and working
If there is a second site, confirm if it is active
Determine the type of outage (Control Plane, Data Plane or Both)</description></item><item><title>Site Failover</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/site-failover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/site-failover/</guid><description>The below processes should be used to move traffic between sites in event of a complete site down scenario. This is handled by the Virtual Network Route Table.
In the examples below, xxxEdgeCluster is the primary site and xxx-edge3 is the secondary/disaster recovery site. Manual Failover When a customer has selected manual failover, a portal user will need to adjust the destination of all routes currently pointed at the failed site.</description></item><item><title>Check Trustgrid Services Status</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-service-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-service-status/</guid><description>View the status of all Trustgrid services on our Statuspage Account
Within the Trustgrid Portal, hover over the username in the upper right corner and then select Status.
Components Trustgrid components on the status page are broad and meant to communicate areas where there may be elevated error rates.
Node Node components affect services that nodes use to manage status, updates, and enroll.
Cloud Controller - signals nodes when to update their config and receives from nodes: events, flow logs, shadow updates Software Repository - provides both OS and Trustgrid package updates License Manager - responsible for enrolling new devices with Trustgrid Management Alerts - event collection and notification services Management Portal - the UI used to manage your devices User Management - the ability to sign in using Trustgrid native authentication Management Gateways - the ability to invoke interactive services on nodes</description></item><item><title>Find the Public IP Address of a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/find-ip-node/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/find-ip-node/</guid><description>The public IP address refers to the source IP address observed by the Trustgrid cloud when the control plane connections are established. This is the IP address after any NATs are applied to outbound internet traffic on the node&amp;rsquo;s WAN interface.
Nodes Table The public IP address is a default column in the Nodes table list. You can use search to filter the list to see the public IP of the desired node.</description></item><item><title>View Configuration Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/config-changes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/config-changes/</guid><description> Changes to the following configurations are audited: API Cluster Node Domain Certificate Org Profile Invite Audits record the event type (add/remove/change), the user name, the IP address, and the date of the change Audits are kept for 30 days Audits can be downloaded as CSV on the operations page</description></item><item><title>View Node Update Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/node-update-events/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/node-update-events/</guid><description> View node update events on the Operations page Node update events are kept for 30 days You can download a CSV of the node updates from the Operations page All Trustgrid node agent updates and OS package updates are logged</description></item><item><title>View User Authentication Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/user-authentication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/mgmt-logs/user-authentication/</guid><description> For every authentication event, we log: user agent user id user name IP address User authentication events include: Failed login attempts Successful login attempts API interactions Successful sign ups You can download all of the events for a 30 day period in the Operations page Authentication events are kept for 30 days If your organization is utilizing a third-party identity provider via SAML or OpenID, that provider is responsible for providing and storing authentication log records</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/api/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Redirecting... If you are not redirected automatically, follow this link to the new page.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agent-v-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agent-v-app/</guid><description>Nodes are available in two form factors:
Appliance - This is a combination of a fully managed operating system and Trustgrid software pre-installed. Agent - This is a software package that can installed on supported operating systems. Users can install additional software and configure the operating system as needed. Functionality Agent Appliance Gateway Capabilities None Data Plane or ZTNA Operating System Multiple Supported OS, install additional software Fully managed OS and Trustgrid service, no additional software permitted Updates Managed by user via OS native tools OS and Trustgrid updates managed via Trustgrid Interface IP Management Managed by user via OS native tools Configurable via Trustgrid portal or local console Layer 3 VPN Single Virtual Network connectivity Support for multiple Virtual Networks Layer 4 Proxy Full Support Full Support Compute Commands only Commands, Containers or VMs supported</description></item><item><title>Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</guid><description>An access policy is a list of rules that each allow, reject, or drop traffic at the VPN level.
If no rules are defined, traffic will not pass through the virtual network.
A rule can match traffic based on the following fields:
Field Name Description Action Whether to ALLOW, DROP, or REJECT the traffic. Protocol You can choose ANY, UDP, ICMP, or TCP. Source The source of the traffic. You can select a network object, a network group, or provide a CIDR.</description></item><item><title>Trustgrid User Account Management</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/users/account-mgmt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/users/account-mgmt/</guid><description>Below shows how to manage password and MFA settings for organizations relying on native Trustgrid user accounts, instead of a custom Identity Provider. These instructions assume you can authenticate successfully with your Trustgrid account. If not you will need to work with Trustgrid support.
Change Password To change your Trustgrid password:
Login to the Trustgrid portal using your current password and provide your MFA code From your user profile dropdown, select &amp;ldquo;Security&amp;rdquo; Security menu option Provide your current password, enter a new password twice, and click submit.</description></item><item><title>Agent Address Translation</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/vpn/nat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/vpn/nat/</guid><description>Enable Forwarding This check box determines if an agent will attempt to forward traffic to/from between the VPN tunnel interface and IP addresses and networks accessible via other interfaces on the agent.
Managing Forwarding This option is deselected by default. To enable, select the check box and click Save.
Network Address Translation By default, all forwarded traffic retains the original IP address local to the agent. It is common to want or need to translate these addresses to avoid IP conflicts or to maintain consistent IP address spaces.</description></item><item><title>Network Address Translation (NATs)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/nats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/nats/</guid><description>NATs allow Trustgrid to alter the source and/or destination IP address of layer 3 traffic as it enters or leaves the VPN.
Adding an Interface NATs are scoped to an interface. Add an interface from the Actions menu.
Add Interface dialog Field Name Description Network Interface Select the desired interface from the drop-down list of those available on the node or cluster. Description User friendly description of this interface attachment.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Options</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/advanced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/advanced/</guid><description>The Advance section provides additional configuration options for customizing the node behavior from the default settings. Default settings work in most environments and should only be changed if needed based on your specific requirements. Config Options Advanced Config Options The Config Options panel allows customizing various advanced settings for the node such as network flow defaults. Each setting provides a description of what it controls and the value field. Additionally, the button on the far right allows resetting a setting back to the default value.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Network Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/advanced-network-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/advanced-network-config/</guid><description>The setting below should be changed via the Trustgrid portal interface configuration if at all possible. These tools should only be used if the correct configuration is preventing successful communication to the control plane.. Modify Network Settings If the Trustgrid service is unreachable the normal Network Configuration will be unavailable and it may be necessary to manually edit the network settings on the device to change the IP and DNS configuration.</description></item><item><title>Running Agent Diagnostic Command</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/agent-diag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/agent-diag/</guid><description>The diag command is designed to determine if an agent has the required connectivity to connect to the Trustgrid Control Plane.
Running diag Command Connect to the machine with the Trustgrid agent installed and open a console. If running as a container you will need to use the appropriate tools to get command line interface (cli) inside the container not the host. Run the command tg-agent diag Review the output tg-agent diag -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -------------------------------------- DNS ------------------------------------- -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- keymaster.</description></item><item><title>Alarm Filters</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/</guid><description>Alarm Filters are used to determine which events trigger notifications and to define which channels should receive those notifications.
Alarm filters have the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The name should be unique. Description The description is displayed in the alarm filters table. Enabled An alarm filter must be enabled for matching event to be sent to the selected channel. Deselecting the check box can be handy if you wish to suppress a specific type of alarm.</description></item><item><title>Alert Center</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/alert-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/alert-center/</guid><description>The Alert Center provides a centralized view of open alerts for a node. Alerts can be resolved from this screen individually, or all can be resolved using the &amp;ldquo;Mark all as resolved&amp;rdquo; button. Example alert center with 3 open alerts</description></item><item><title>Alert Suppression</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alert-suppression/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alert-suppression/</guid><description>Maintenance and other planned disruptive activity can generate a large amount of alerts and notifications for no value. The Trustgrid system allows you to define alert suppression windows during which no alerts are triggered.
Define Alert Suppression Window Navigate to Alarms -&amp;gt; Alert Suppression.
Enter a message to users. During the window this will be displayed on the dashboard when users first log in.
Select a duration between 1 and 4 hours for your window.</description></item><item><title>API Access</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/api-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/api-access/</guid><description>Generating an API Key Navigate to User Management -&amp;gt; API Access, and click Regenerate API keys. This will invalidate your existing API key, if it exists. The API key is tied to your user and will have the same permissions.
The client secret key will only be available at time of generation - if it&amp;rsquo;s lost, the key will need to be regenerated
Using the API Key To use the API key in a request, pass it in as an HTTP header, like Authorization: trustgrid-token client-id:client-secret Anything that can be done in the Trustgrid Portal can be done with the API (except for generating an API token).</description></item><item><title>ARP Ping Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/arping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/arping/</guid><description>The arping tool allows you to send an ARP request to a specific IP address on a local interface. This tool is useful for troubleshooting connectivity issues such as confirming if the interface is in the same layer 2 broadcast domain as the target IP address.
Using ARP Ping Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to send an ARP request. Select Interfaces under the Network section.</description></item><item><title>Audits</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</guid><description>Node audits provide records when services on a node are invoked, or when upgrades are applied. This can be helpful to see the historical maintenance of a node.
Node audits can be viewed for a specific node by navigating to Audits under the History section on the node view.
Users will need audits::read:node permissions to view node audits.
Node audits can also be found for the entire organization by navigating to Operations-&amp;gt;Node Audits.</description></item><item><title>Authentication Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/authentication/</guid><description>Trustgrid records information for authentication attempts into the control plane. This information can be used to troubleshoot authentication issues, or to monitor for suspicious activity.
Authentication logs are available by navigating to Operations-&amp;gt;Authentication Logs. Only the most recent 25 records are shown, but the last 30 days of logs can be downloaded by clicking the link at the bottom of the page.
Successful logins from external identity providers are logged, but failed attempts are not.</description></item><item><title>AWS Requirements for HA Wireguard Cluster</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/aws-ha-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/aws-ha-cluster/</guid><description>Create EC2 Target Group and add both Trustgrid gateways with the target being wireguard server port (Default UDP 51820) The health check should be set to http with a path of /status and override traffic port to be port 80.
Only the active member of the Trustgrid Cluster will respond as healthy to the health check.
Create NLB (Network Load Balancer) with listener set to configured UDP wireguard server port (Default 51820) and forwarding to the target group created above.</description></item><item><title>Example Walkthrough of Azure CLI (az) Deployment</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/azure-cli-deployment/az-cli-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/azure-cli-deployment/az-cli-example/</guid><description>Below walks through creating a brand new resource group, virtual network, subnets and associated resources needed to deploy a Trustgrid appliance using Azure CLI commands. This is rarely appropriate for production environments but demonstrates the process.
It then walks through all the steps listed on the AZ CLI Deployment and shows the output of running the commands.
The output below may be modified to obscure unique ids for security purposes and truncated due to the verbosity of some response.</description></item><item><title>Azure AD</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/azure-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/azure-idp-fields/</guid><description>Setup Setting up the Azure AD integration requires the configuration of an Azure App registration. See Azure App registration configuration.
Field Name Description Issuer Specifies the Azure App OpenID metadata endpoint. Client ID Specifies the Azure App client ID. Secret Specifies the Azure App secret value (not the secret ID). This is the value that appears only once when you create a new client secret. Before being able to save the configuration, validation of the Issuer needs to be performed by pressing the Test button.</description></item><item><title>Best Practices for Monitoring and Alerting</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/monitoring/best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/monitoring/best-practices/</guid><description>Monitoring with Trustgrid Alarm Filters Alarm filters in Trustgrid help you ensure the right people are notified about the right events. Instead of documenting configuration steps, this section focuses on what you should monitor and how to organize your alerting for maximum effectiveness.
Recommended Alarm Channels Critical Channel: For alarms that require immediate action, such as issues with public gateways or core infrastructure. This channel should notify on-call or primary support staff.</description></item><item><title>BGP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/bgp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/bgp/</guid><description>Summary Trustgrid nodes can be configured to connect to an external BGP router to advertise and receive routes. This allows Trustgrid networks to be integrated into an existing routing fabric.
The BGP panel is listed under the Network panel group.
Configuration Router Configuration These are the settings used by the local BGP router.
Field Name Description Status Enabled/Disabled - Whether the BGP server is running on the node. ID The IP addressed used to identify the BGP router.</description></item><item><title>Node Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/changes/</guid><description>The Changes panel displays a history of configuration changes made to the node, including changes to network settings, system configurations, and more. This is the same data visible in the Operations &amp;gt; Configuration Changes but scoped to those changes applied to the current node.</description></item><item><title>Changing the WAN Interface IP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/wan-interface-ip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/wan-interface-ip/</guid><description>The WAN interface of a Trustgrid node is used to build connections to both the Control Plane and any Data Plane connectivity. Any change to this IP address is disruptive and presents a risk that the device will go offline if incorrect information is provided. This could potentially require a technical resource to go onsite to reconnect physical devices.
To make the below changes via the Trustgrid portal the user must have the Node Administrator or Administrator role.</description></item><item><title>Channels</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/</guid><description>A channel defines one or more method of delivering alert notifications to external systems.
Notification Delivery Channels Email Channel One or more email address (comma separated) that will receive messages from alerts@trustgrid.io
PagerDuty Channel Trustgrid will generate an incident via the PagerDuty API if provided a valid API routing key. To procure a routing key, create a service in PagerDuty and add an Events API V2 integration. After adding the integration, the Integration Key is your API routing key.</description></item><item><title>Gateway Client Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</guid><description>Settings on this page determine how a node&amp;rsquo;s client connection to gateway peers behave.
Settings Gateway Client settings Field Name Description Connectivity to Public Gateways Options are Allowed or Denied. If set to Denied this will cause the node to not attempt connections to public gateways. This might be desired if you want the node to only connect to configured private gateways. Or if you have private gateways that do not need to connect to the public gateways in your organization.</description></item><item><title>Cluster Heartbeat Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/cluster/</guid><description>Cluster configuration is only available for nodes that are members of a cluster. Heartbeat The cluster heartbeat defines a persistent connection between cluster members. The heartbeat is used to determine the health of the cluster and to determine which member is the active member. This configuration is required on cluster members.
Field Name Description Heartbeat Host The IP (bound to an interface) on which heartbeat communication will occur Heartbeat Port The port on which heartbeat communication will occur The same interface should be selected for all cluster members Status Endpoint (Optional) The Status Endpoint allows you to start an HTTP REST endpoint on a port on the WAN interface IP that will return a 200 response if the member is healthy and the active cluster member.</description></item><item><title>Cluster Site Health State</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/cluster-health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/cluster-health/</guid><description>A healthy cluster should have two online Trustgrid nodes in a healthy state. The Trustgrid control plane can monitor the member nodes and generate events when their state changes such that the health of the cluster is impacted.
Basics These events are based on the information reported by each member node to the control plane. Because of this:
There can be a delay between a change and the Cluster Site Health events.</description></item><item><title>Cluster-Only Configuration Items</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/cluster-only-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/cluster-only-config/</guid><description>Cluster IP The Cluster IP is a virtual IP address used by the cluster to provide a consistent endpoint for clients, even when the active node changes.
Availability Platform Supported On-Premise ✅ Yes Azure ✅ Yes AWS ❌ No Google Cloud (GCP) ❌ No On-Premise The Cluster IP is supported in on-premise deployments. The active member of the cluster answers ARP requests for the Cluster IP. Only the active node will respond, ensuring traffic is directed correctly in failover scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Configuration Update Failure Troubleshooting</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/config-update-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/config-update-failure/</guid><description>Symptoms Changes made via the portal or api are not implemented on the actual node In versions after 20240719, the Configuration Update Failure event will be sent by appliance nodes Example Configuration Update Failure event Causes Possible causes include:
The node is unable to resolve Trustgrid.io DNS names, in this case specifically gatekeeper.trustgrid.io The node is unable to connect to the the entire Trustgrid Control Plane networks on port 8443 Troubleshooting These steps should be performed via the Terminal or the appliance console Network Tools Shell.</description></item><item><title>Configuration Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/changes/</guid><description>Trustgrid records information about changes users make to all configuration. This can be helpful when troubleshooting recent changes.
Changes can be viewed for a specific node and for the entire organization. To view changes for a specific node, navigate to a node and select Changes under the History section. To view changes for the entire organization, navigate to Operations-&amp;gt;Changes.
The following information is shown for each change:
Field Name Description Date When the change was made IP The IP address from which the change originated Event The type of change (delete/create/change/action).</description></item><item><title>Connectors</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</guid><description>Connectors are configured in conjunction with services to define a local listening port for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Configuration Connectors are configured under the Networking &amp;gt; Connectors tab of the node or cluster configuration section in the Trustgrid Portal.
Add Connector dialogue Field Name Description Protocol The protocol that the listener for the connector will use. Options are TCP, UDP, FTP, and TFTP.
FTP must operate in passive mode when using L4 services and connectors.</description></item><item><title>Customer Responsibilities</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</guid><description>Trustgrid and our customers share the responsibilities of securing the Trustgrid network. Trustgrid assumes and automates a significant part of the overall security challenges. These challenges range from the cloud to the firmware on hardware appliances. Our customers are responsible for securing physical environments, identity and access management, and all security aspects of the environments where Trustgrid is installed.
Trustgrid Secures the Cloud All cloud management components are secured and monitored by Trustgrid.</description></item><item><title>Data Plane</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/data-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/data-plane/</guid><description>The Data Plane panel provides information about the tunnels between the agent and its gateway peers that allow for data plane communication.
Table of connected gateway peers and stats Each peer will show the following data: Field Name Description Status This field will display a green circle if connected and a red circle if disconnected. Name The name of the peer node. IP The IP address the peer node is advertising for connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Data Plane</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</guid><description>The Data Plane panel shows a list of all statistics known peers, their connection status, provides tools for testing connectivity and can display statistics for the connection between the node and the peer.
Export List of Peers You can export a CSV formatted list of all peers by clicking Actions -&amp;gt; Export Export button The CSV file will include columns for:
Connection status (true/false) Peer name Peer IP Path (if applicable) RTT - Return Trip Time or latency observed when the panel was opened or refreshed Mode - TLS or TLS/UDP Type - The role of the node to peer.</description></item><item><title>Viewing Agent Debug Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/debug-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/debug-logs/</guid><description>The Trustgrid agent generates debug logs that can be useful for troubleshooting issues. Many log entries are fairly self explanatory, but some may require the assistance to Trustgrid support to fully understand their context.
Viewing Debug Logs Viewing Log Files The agent log files are located in /var/log/trustgrid/agent. The active log file is tg-agent.log. Logs rotate every day, with the last 9 days kept in separate files appended with a number.</description></item><item><title>Deploy to vSphere</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-vsphere/</guid><description>Requirements Hardware Resources 4 vCPU 4 GB RAM 30 GB disk space Software Requirements vSphere 6.7 or newer (with VMWare support) Configuration Best Practices Backups Trustgrid recommends against backing up virtualized Nodes. Backups that utilize VMware&amp;rsquo;s Data Protection API will initiate a VM Snapshot that will pause all traffic through the VM for a short period of time. This can cause issues such as master failover in a cluster and disruption of existing network flows.</description></item><item><title>Gateway Diagnostics</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</guid><description>Traffic Volume Data This graph displays the traffic volume of all data plane communications between the node and its peers.
Gateway Diagnostics Page</description></item><item><title>Directory Creation</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/datastore/mkdir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/datastore/mkdir/</guid><description> Data store directory creation allows you to add new directories to organize your files in a hierarchical, tree-like structure.
The destination where the directory will be created can be changed by selecting a particular directory as the parent from the File Explorer sidebar. Field Name Description Parent Directory The data store location where this directory will created. Name The name of the directory to create.</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</guid><description>The DNS feature allows nodes in the virtual network to act as DNS servers for ingress VPN traffic. The node can resolve queries custom defines DNS zones and records, or forward queries to upstream DNS servers.
DNS Settings Field Name Description Enable/Disable DNS This field enables or disables the DNS feature on the virtual network. DNS Server IP This is the IP address that should be used as the resolver. There is no need to create a VPN route for this IP.</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dns/</guid><description>Nodes can act as domain name servers (DNS) for requests ingressing the virtual network on the node if DNS is configured at the virtual network.
VPN DNS Settings page DNS Status This setting must be set to Enabled on the node to process requests targeting the configured virtual network DNS server IP.
Upstream Servers If configured, the node will use these servers to resolve DNS requests for zones not configured at the virtual network level.</description></item><item><title>Documents</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/documents/</guid><description>Trustgrid and customers can share documents securely in the Documents section.
Adding or deleting documents requires documents::modify permissions. Downloading and viewing documents requires documents::read permissions. (show how to add and delete and download a document).</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dynamic-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dynamic-routing/</guid><description>Dynamic routing allows a node to export and import routes from other nodes in the virtual network. Find dynamic route definitions and change them under the Dynamic Routing section of the VPN configuration.
Dynamic Routing table Exports Export routes for other nodes in the virtual network to import.
Add Export Route dialog Field Name Description Destination The node to route traffic to. Destination CIDR The network to route traffic to. Metric The route metric.</description></item><item><title>Edge Node Behavior When DNS Resolution Fails</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/dns-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/dns-failure/</guid><description>Symptoms Node does not connect to the Portal Packet captures show repeated DNS queries for gatekeeper.trustgrid.io but no response Cause DNS servers configured on edge node are not accessible A firewall is blocking TCP/UDP port 53 between the edge node and the configured DNS DNS servers configured on edge node cannot resolve public DNS entries for the trustgrid.io domain Troubleshooting Steps Determine the configured DNS Servers - Connecting a monitor to the node will display the current IP configuration including the DNS Servers as shown below: (If possible) Capture traffic between the edge node and the internet and confirm you see both a DNS query (usually for gatekeeper.</description></item><item><title>Edge Node Behavior When SSL / TLS Certificate is Altered</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/ssl-tls-tampering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/ssl-tls-tampering/</guid><description>Products that alter SSL/TLS certificate chains will prevent the node from functioning normally.
Symptoms Node will not connect - This will occur if the SSL/TLS chain is altered on port 8443 Node will not update - This will occur if the SSL/TLS chain is altered on port 443 Packet captures will show something like the below repeating: TLS “Client Hello” Server (Trustgrid IP) will send a reset (RST) Cause The integrity of communication is a critical feature of Trustgrid’s network solution.</description></item><item><title>Event Types</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</guid><description>This page lists all event types that can be generated by Trustgrid nodes. Events are alphabetized and grouped by their filter type. For events that have both trigger and resolution states, the trigger severity and resolution severity are shown.
Contents All Gateways Disconnected All Peers Disconnected BGP Peer Connectivity Certificate Expiring Cluster Failover Configuration Update Failure Connection Flapping Connection Timeout Data and Control Plane Disruption Data Plane Disruption Deregister DNS Resolution Gateway Connectivity Health Check Gateway Ingress Limit Reached Gateway UDP Tunnel Error Metric Threshold Violation Network Error Network Health Check Networking Framework Memory Management Node Connect/Disconnect Node Delete Node Stop Error Order Commented Order Created Repo Connectivity Site Outage SSH Lockdown Unauthorized IP Event Types All Gateways Disconnected Trigger Severity: WARNING</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</guid><description>Events are emitted from nodes and from the Trustgrid control plane when actionable things happen. Events are the basis for alarms and notifications.
Events can be viewed for individual nodes by navigating to Events under the History section.
Events for the entire organization can be viewed by navigating to Events under the Alarms section.
Clicking the Test button will send the event through your configured alarms to help verify channels are configured as expected.</description></item><item><title>File Sync</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/datastore/sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/datastore/sync/</guid><description>File syncing allows a user to transfer files to the data store as well as upload files from the data store.
Transfer Files A user can populate the data store by transferring files from an Amazon S3 bucket or from an HTTP endpoint.
The destination where the file will be stored can be changed by selecting a particular directory from the File Explorer sidebar. Amazon S3 Transfer A user can select to transfer a file from an S3 URI.</description></item><item><title>Node Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/flow-logs/</guid><description>This page will show the most recent flow logs for the specific node being viewed and allow for advanced searches scoped to the current node.
See this page for more info on Flow Logs</description></item><item><title>Organization Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/flow-logs/</guid><description>This page shows Flow Logs from all nodes in an organization. See this page for more info on Flow Logs
Flow Log Export Trustgrid can export flow logs to any S3 bucket. Set your bucket name and apply the policy provided, and then Trustgrid will configure replication for your flow logs into your bucket.
Fields for configuring S3 replication Field Name Description AWS Account ID This is the AWS Account ID that contains the bucket you wish to have Flow Logs replicated to.</description></item><item><title>G Suite</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/gsuite-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/gsuite-idp-fields/</guid><description>Setup Setting up the G Suite integration requires a G Suite administrator to perform the configuration.
Once the integration has been successful, the user sync selection will be presented:
Sync all users - Syncs all available users along with all the groups associated to the users. Sync users from specific groups - Syncs all users from the selected groups. Disconnect G Suite - Deletes all users and groups and removes the G Suite integration.</description></item><item><title>GRE</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/gre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/gre/</guid><description>Trustgrid supports configuring GRE tunnels that can be used to establish connectivity to any appliance that supports the GRE protocol. A GRE tunnel interface is created which can then be attached to an interface on a node. VRFs can then be used to control the flow of traffic and how it should appear on the network.
Configure GRE Tunnel On a Trustgrid Node navigate to Tunnels under the Network Menu, select Add Tunnel, and then select GRE</description></item><item><title>Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/groups/</guid><description>User Management Groups defined can be used to make Remote Access applications visible to users.
Types of Groups Trustgrid-Native Groups These groups are created in the Portal via the Add Group button. Membership is managed directly within the Portal by administrators.
Identity Provider-Synchronized Groups These groups are created based on Identity Provider (IdP) configuration for select IdPs (currently G Suite and Azure OpenID). The IdP can be configured to sync all or select groups, and the sync process will update the group membership automatically.</description></item><item><title>Configure HA Trustgrid Gateway Cluster in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</guid><description>Deploy a pair of Trustgrid gateways. Deployment guide includes an example Cloud Formation template that can be used directly or customized for your environment or converted to Terraform if preferred. Gateways can be deployed in the same availability zone or different ones to provide greater redundancy across AWS. Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS.
Under networking &amp;gt; clusters create a cluster using a descriptive and unique name as seen below.</description></item><item><title>Images</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/containers/images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/containers/images/</guid><description>The images section shows the container images that have been downloaded to the node. They may be deleted to free up space.</description></item><item><title>Incident.io Webhook Integration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/monitoring/incident-io-webhook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/monitoring/incident-io-webhook/</guid><description>Trustgrid can be integrated with Incident.io using the generic webhook channel to send alerts based on Trustgrid events. This allows for streamlined incident management and improved response times. The guide below outlines the steps to set up this integration along with suggestions on gathering additional attributes for the alerts.
Setting Up the Integration The Incident.io site is subject to change so any screenshots or instructions may become outdated. Please refer to the official Incident.</description></item><item><title>Infovisor</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/infovisor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/infovisor/</guid><description>The infovisor displays details about the Trustgrid node and can be displayed by clicking the Info button in the top right or hitting the backtick ` key. Button to open Infovisor It displays the following information in a card layout broken up into a number of sections that can be expanded and collapsed, or removed from view. Example infovisor It contains the below information but can vary between appliance and agent-based nodes.</description></item><item><title>Network Interfaces</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/interfaces/</guid><description>The Interfaces page displays the network interfaces on the agent node and their IPv4 addresses. Agent Interfaces All fields have buttons to allow for easily copying the information into the clipboard. You can export all the interface data as a CSV file by clicking Actions-&amp;gt;Export Interface Information. Tools Sniff Traffic - Opens the Sniff Traffic Interface tool for viewing traffic on the interface in realtime.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</guid><description>Network Interfaces Navigate to a node, then select Interfaces under the Network section.
Interfaces panel The Interface dropdown at the top allows you to select which interface to manage.
ETH0 - WAN Interface This interface is always used to build the outbound TLS tunnels for control and data plane connectivity. If the node is deployed in a single interface configuration, this interface will also be used for local network connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Azure IP Failover</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/ip-failover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/ip-failover/</guid><description>How it works Trustgrid provides the ability for a floating IP address to be assigned to a Trustgrid cluster. When failover occurs, the floating IP address will automatically be assigned to the active appliance in the cluster. This feature works by creating a new Azure IP Configuration and associating it with the interface of the active cluster node.
Graceful Failover This describes the process of a graceful failover when the active member of the node is changed but both members are online and working normally.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network IP Pools</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/ip-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/ip-pool/</guid><description>Virtual Network IP Pools are used for automatically assigning virtual management to nodes. This is optional but makes configuration and management easier.
At this time only agent-based nodes support automatic IP assignment Address Assignment Addresses are assigned sequentially from the pool by Trustgrid. When a node is attached to a virtual network with an IP pool configured, it will automatically be assigned the next available IP from the pool. When a node is detached its IP is returned to the pool for reuse.</description></item><item><title>IPSec</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/ipsec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/ipsec/</guid><description>Trustgrid supports configuring traditional IPSec tunnels that can be used to establish connectivity to any appliance that supports the IPSec protocol. Once an IPSec tunnel is configured an IPSec virtual interface is created that can be attached to a node interface. VRFs can be used in conjunction to explicitly control what traffic is allowed (VRF ACLs) to pass and how it should look on the network (VRF NATs or Traffic Rules).</description></item><item><title>JSONinator Walk Through</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/tools/jsoninator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/tools/jsoninator/</guid><description>Notice: JSONinator is provided as a convenience tool for Trustgrid customers. It is not part of the core Trustgrid platform and is not covered by Trustgrid’s standard service level agreements (SLAs) or product guarantees. Support for this tool is provided on a best-effort basis. Report any issues via the GitHub repository issues page. JSONinator is a command-line tool designed to make bulk changes to Trustgrid nodes matching a configured filter.</description></item><item><title>Java Virtual Machine (JVM)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/default-settings/jvm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/default-settings/jvm/</guid><description>These settings only apply to appliance-based Trustgrid nodes Memory Settings The Java Virtual Machine (JVM) is responsible for managing the memory used by the Trustgrid service on appliances. Two key parameters that control this memory management are the minimum (min) and maximum (max) memory values.
Minimum Memory: This is the initial memory allocation for the JVM. When your Java application starts, the JVM allocates this amount of memory right away.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/location/</guid><description>Trustgrid uses each node&amp;rsquo;s public IP address to derive location information. If it&amp;rsquo;s incorrect, the fields can be set manually. If set manually, IP changes will not update the node&amp;rsquo;s location when viewed from the nodes table or the network map.
To change the Node Location: Change the details to desired settings then click Save when done.</description></item><item><title>Manage Cluster Members</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/manage-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/manage-members/</guid><description>Add Member This will add the selected node to the cluster and gain any configuration defined at the cluster level.
Click Actions &amp;gt; Add Node. Action &amp;gt; Add Node Select the desired node from the list. This is a type-ahead field that will filter the list as you type. Click Add Node. Member node selection list You are prompted if you want to configure cluster heartbeat settings. Prompt to configure heartbeat settings No - The node is added to the cluster and you will manually need to navigate to the node&amp;rsquo;s cluster settings and configure the heartbeat before it will be healthy.</description></item><item><title>Additional Metrics</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/metrics/</guid><description>The Metrics page will be used to display additional available statistics that are not displayed on the overview page. Similar to the overview page these stats are viewable in 1, 2, 6, 12, and 24-hour views, and 1 week and 1 month views.
JVM Heap The Trustgrid service on appliance-based nodes runs via the Java Virtual Machine (JVM). When launched the java process claims a minimum amount of memory from the operating system.</description></item><item><title>Network Flow Default Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/default-settings/network-flows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/default-settings/network-flows/</guid><description>Timeouts The table below details the time the Trustgrid network process waits before terminating a flow. Flows are matched based on the IP tuple (source ip, source port, destination ip, destination port).
Protocol States Time(seconds) Description TCP SYN_SENT, SYN_RECEIVED 15 Covers flows that have not yet completed a 3-way TCP handshake. e.g. (SYN, SYN/ACK, ACK) TCP CLOSE_WAIT, TIME_WAIT, FIN_WAIT 60 Covers flows that have started the TCP close process. TCP ESTABLISHED 900 Covers established flows.</description></item><item><title>Network Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</guid><description>A network group is a list of network objects that allows for easier rule management.
A network group requires a name to be set. This will be used to reference the group in access policy rules.
Navigating into a network group allows management of the group’s member objects.</description></item><item><title>Network Objects</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</guid><description>A network object allows naming a CIDR inside a VPN for easier rule management.
A network object requires the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The label to use when referencing this object. CIDR Specifically an IPv4 CIDR. Multiple network objects may be clustered into a network group.</description></item><item><title>OpenID</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/open-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/open-idp-fields/</guid><description>
Field Name Description Issuer The OpenID issuer URL. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider. Client ID The OpenID application client ID. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider. Client Secret The OpenID application client secret. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/overview/</guid><description>The overview page for agent-based nodes shows several graphs and provides a table of recent flow logs.
Example Overview panel for an agent Graphs Node Performance - This section shows graphs of CPU, memory, disk, and network usage over time for the agent node. Agent Process Performance - This section shows the CPU, memory, and disk IO usage of the actual Trustgrid agent process. Traffic Throughput - This section shows the total sent and received traffic in megabits per second (Mbps) for all interfaces on the agent.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/overview/</guid><description>Stats The Node overview page shows performance and network traffic data.
Supported time windows are selectable at the top. VPN and network statistics can be targeted to specific virtual networks and interfaces.
Field Name Description Node Performance shows CPU, disk, and memory usage percentages VPN Traffic Volume shows data usage sent and received, across all VPNs and for the selected virtual network Traffic Volume shows data sent and receives, across all interfaces and for the selected interface Connected Peers shows the number of other nodes connected.</description></item><item><title>Password Complexity and MFA Requirements</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/users/password-complexity-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/users/password-complexity-requirements/</guid><description>Invited users utilize Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s native authentication provider for password complexity and multi-factor authentication.
Users authenticating via a custom identity provider will use that system&amp;rsquo;s password complexity and MFA requirements.
Password Complexity At least 10 characters in length Lower case (a-z), upper case (A-Z) and numbers (0-9) Special characters (-!@#$%^&amp;amp;*) No more than 2 identical characters in a row Cannot reuse the last 5 passwords Cannot be in the list of the 10,000 most common passwords Cannot include the user’s name, username, or email address Multi-factor Authentication Requirements The Trustgrid native provider utilizes a One-time Password via applications such as Google Authenticator or similar to provide multi-factor authentication during login.</description></item><item><title>Ping Remote Virtual Host</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</guid><description>Prerequisites Both the source and destination nodes should have a virtual management IP configured There should be a unique IP under Node &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; VPN &amp;gt; Virtual Management IP In the virtual network route configuration in your domain, a route should exist with the following settings: Destination: node name (even if part of a cluster) Destination CIDR: virtual management IP with a /32 suffix Metric: 1 Use the View Virtual Route Table tool to verify both the source and destination nodes have valid, available routes to each other&amp;rsquo;s virtual management IP Need to know the virtual IP address of the inside NAT if targeting a local IP on the destination network Need to know the virtual management IP address of the destination node if only verifying VPN network connectivity The Ping Remote Node tool allows you to verify data plane communication by node name Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Policies</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/</guid><description>User Management Policies define what an authenticated user is allowed to do within the Trustgrid system. Policies either allow or explicitly deny specific actions by the user.
Types of Policies Trustgrid Managed Policies These policies start with the prefix builtin-tg and are created and managed by Trustgrid to provide a starting level of permissions based on common user types. Descriptions of the user types for each role are listed below.</description></item><item><title>Node Behavior When Port 443 is blocked</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/upgrade-process/443-blocked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/upgrade-process/443-blocked/</guid><description>Symptoms Node will not update either automatically or when manually triggered Node will not be able to pull down container images from the organization repository Node cannot send up debug logs Cause The Trustgrid node cannot connect to repo.trustgrid.io on port 443 to update packages Troubleshooting Connectivity Either of the below methods can be used to verify connectivity:
Use the Interface TCP Port Test tool. Make sure the WAN interfaces IP is the source, repo.</description></item><item><title>Port Forwarding</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/port-forwarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/port-forwarding/</guid><description>Port forwarding allows a node to expose an L4 TCP service on the virtual network.
Port Forward listing Field Name Description Virtual IP Address The IP to expose the service on the virtual network. Virtual Port The port to expose the service on the virtual network. Local Service The service to expose. Alternately, you can specify an IP and port.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network Port Forwards</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</guid><description>Virtual Network Port Forwards allow a virtual IP address to be associated with a TCP Layer 4 service on a remote node or cluster without the need to specify a route for that virtual IP address. Example Virtual Network Port Forward Description As noted above, a Virtual Network Port Forward (or remote port forward) associates a service defined on a node or cluster with a virtual IP address within the virtual network without needing to specifically route that IP to the node/cluster.</description></item><item><title>Production Status Tags</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/tags/prod-status-tag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/tags/prod-status-tag/</guid><description>It is recommended that customers use a tag to indicate if nodes are currently in production or not. For example, you may wish to have a tag such as prod_status with possible values like
deploying for devices still being deployed production for devices actively in user decommission for devices that are being removed It’s important to have these tag names and values be consistent within the organization including case. Production and production would be viewed as two different values, as an example.</description></item><item><title>Remote Console Registration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/remote-registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/remote-registration/</guid><description>This feature is currently available as a preview and requires Trustgrid support to grant portal users access to activate nodes. Overview The remote console registration process allows for a Trustgrid Node running a generic image to be registered with a valid Trustgrid account.
Requirements Console access to the Trustgrid Node. This could be achieved via: For physical devices either keyboard and monitor connections or serial console For VMware or Hyper-V remote console access For Azure and AWS serial console access via each providers management portal Portal access with the appropriate permissions to activate nodes.</description></item><item><title>Repositories</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/repositories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/repositories/</guid><description>Summary Trustgrid provides a fully managed private container registry for each customer account. This allows customers to deploy containerized applications securely to their Trustgrid node appliances.
Container Namespace Each customer is isolated to their own container namespace that is listed at the bottom of the Repositories page.
To push a container to your private registry it must be named with your namespace as a prefix when tagged.
Example Trustgrid repository namespace List View Uploaded container images may be viewed by navigating to Repositories in the portal.</description></item><item><title>Restart Agent Node Service</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/restart-agent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/restart-agent/</guid><description>Restarting the agent service is sometimes necessary to reload configuration changes or restart the agent process. The steps to restart the agent service depends on the operating system.
Restarting the agent service will disrupt traffic across the node. Restarting Linux Agent Restart Ubuntu Agents Gain console access to the agent host system via SSH or local console with a user with sudo access to run the below commands. Run the command sudo systemctl restart tg-agent Copy</description></item><item><title>Review Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</guid><description>Because changes to a domain virtual network affect all nodes, domain configuration changes must be reviewed before applied, and are applied all at once.
After making changes to a virtual network, you can review outstanding changes. A list of changes will show who made each change, with a before/after table if appropriate.
Individual changes can be rejected by clicking the delete icon at the top.
Once changes are applied, outstanding changes will disappear from the review page, and nodes will receive the configuration updates.</description></item><item><title>Azure Route Failover</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/route-failover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-azure/route-failover/</guid><description>How it works Trustgrid provides the ability for a cluster of Azure based appliances to published routes to one or more Azure route table. When failover occurs, the Trustgrid appliance will automatically update the next hop IP address in the route table to the active appliance in the cluster.
Graceful Failover This describes the process of a graceful failover when the active member of the node is changed but both members are online and working normally.</description></item><item><title>Routes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</guid><description>Routes configured under Domains determine to which node or cluster the Trustgrid virtual network should route traffic for a specific subnet.
Virtual Network Routes Routes defined a the virtual network level allow creating a global route table shared with all nodes and clusters attached to the virtual network. This table is then used to evaluate where to send VPN traffic for a specified destination CIDR.
Route Fields A Route has the following fields:</description></item><item><title>SAML</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/saml-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/saml-idp-fields/</guid><description>When configuring a SAML IDP, the provider will often provide a metadata XML file to simplify configuration. If provided, you can upload that on the SAML configuration page, which will automatically populate the fields necessary for SAML authentication.
Field Name Description Issuer A URL that will point to the IDP, typically with some identifying information so the IDP can determine the source of the request. This will be provided by your SAML identity provider.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/search/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gateway Server Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</guid><description>Gateways servers are nodes that are configured to receive connections from other Trustgrid nodes (clients). These are the only nodes that need to have ports open and listening on the internet or WAN network.
The server sub-panel provides the settings controlling if a node will act as a server and if so how clients will connect to it.
Gateway Server Types A gateway server can be one of three types:</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</guid><description>Services are configured in conjunction with connectors or port forwards to define a host (IP or DNS) and port to connect to for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Description Services define the host name or IP and port of a server that can be accessed by the Trustgrid node (or members of the cluster) where it is defined. Remote clients can then access the service via peer nodes using connectors or VPN port forwards.</description></item><item><title>Sniff Traffic Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</guid><description>The Sniff Traffic tool allows you to monitor traffic on a local network interface in realtime within the Trustgrid portal. Only the header information such as source and destination IPs, TCP flags, sequence numbers, etc. are displayed.
Using Sniff Interface Traffic Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to view traffic. Select Interfaces under the Network section. Then from the dropdown select the interface whose traffic you want to monitor.</description></item><item><title>Sniff Virtual Traffic</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-virtual-traffic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-virtual-traffic/</guid><description>Summary This tool allows you to monitor the traffic flowing over a VPN tunnel by &amp;ldquo;sniffing&amp;rdquo; inside the tunnel. This allows traffic to be viewed after NATs have been applied and confirm traffic is routed to or from the expected node.
Usage This tool is accessed on a node&amp;rsquo;s detail page under the VPN panel. Select the desired attached virtual network (note: if only on virtual network is present it will be selected by default) and click the &amp;ldquo;Tools&amp;rdquo; button in the top right.</description></item><item><title>SNMP OIDs on Trustgrid Appliances</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/snmp/oids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/snmp/oids/</guid><description>SNMP Standard OIDs Trustgrid exposes data through standard OIDs to provide information about the below resources. Most monitoring software will detect these automatically.
CPU
Memory
Disk
Network Interface
Trustgrid Custom OIDs The following custom data points are made available under Trustgrid’s Enterprise OID .1.3.6.1.4.1.53560 which will need to be used as the prefix for the below OIDs
.2.2.1 - Lists VPN Stats in a table each virtual network is a row in the table (signified with the suffix .</description></item><item><title>Agent Virtual Network Static Routes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/vpn/static-routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/agents/vpn/static-routes/</guid><description>Agents can define static routes for their virtual network to augment or override routes defined in the global virtual network route table. Field Name Description Destination The destination node or cluster where matching traffic will be routed. Destination CIDR The CIDR notation of the IP address or network traffic that this route should manage. Metric Value between 1 and 200. The available route with the lowest metric will be selected when a flow is created.</description></item><item><title>Static Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/static-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/static-routing/</guid><description>Static routing allows a node to route traffic to a remote network in addition to virtual network-defined routes(https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/). Routes defined at this level can be created for destination CIDRs outside the virtual network&amp;rsquo;s Network CIDR
Find static route definitions and change them under the Static Routing section of the VPN configuration.
Add Route dialog Field Name Description Destination The node to route traffic to. Destination CIDR The network to route traffic to.</description></item><item><title>Submit a Support Request</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/support-request/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/support-request/</guid><description>Support Request section This panel allows you to submit a request for assistance from the Trustgrid Support Team with the product or service. Please provide as much detail as possible about the issue you are experiencing so our support team can help resolve it quickly.
The support requests will be submitted with your user account email address. Field Name Description Phone number Provide the phone number you&amp;rsquo;d like to be contacted at regarding this issue.</description></item><item><title>Deploying ThousandEyes Enterprise Agent Container on Trustgrid</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/containers/thousand-eyes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/containers/thousand-eyes/</guid><description>Description Running the ThousandEyes Enterprise Agent from remote locations on Trustgrid Nodes enables organizations to monitor network latency and performance across different regions, ensuring a consistent user experience. It helps identify issues and proactively address network problems before they impact users. This monitoring can go beyond Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s native hop monitoring to perform additional tests. For organizations already using ThousandEyes this can provide a single pane of glass view of network performance.</description></item><item><title>Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/thresholds/</guid><description>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the domain level apply to all nodes in the domain, except when overridden. Events will be of type Metric Threshold Violation.
To view thresholds, a user will need domains::read permissions. To configure them, they will need domains::configure:threshold permissions.
Navigate to your domain, and click Thresholds on the left.
Load Thresholds Load thresholds measure the health of the node itself.</description></item><item><title>Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</guid><description>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the node level can override Domain Thresholds.
Example Thresholds page on a node Node Level Threshold Status Field Name Description Status Disabled (default) - Only thresholds defined at the domain level will be used for generating events. Enabled - Thresholds defined at the node level will be used for generating events, including overriding any domain-level values.</description></item><item><title>Traffic Capture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/traffic-capture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/traffic-capture/</guid><description>The Traffic Capture tool performs a traffic capture on the selected node, which can help troubleshoot connectivity issues.
Summary The Sniff Interface Traffic tool allows you to monitor traffic in realtime but there are certain instances where you need to be able to capture traffic to a file for further analysis. For example, intermittent issues may require leaving a capture running for an unknown period of time. Or, perhaps you need to review the application data within the packet payload.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Menu</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Tools on this page allow for additional troubleshooting. Troubleshooting Menu View Node Logs This utility opens the Trustgrid service logs in a text viewer in follow mode so new lines will be displayed as written to the log file.
To exit follow mode hit control + C. You can then use arrow keys to move up and down through the log file.
To return to the Troubleshooting menu hit control + C (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already) and then input :q and hit return.</description></item><item><title>Trustgrid Support's Node Access and Data Plane Security</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</guid><description>Trustgrid takes security and privacy seriously. Trustgrid teams do not have access to any data that traverses the Data Plane. All customer data moving through the Data Plane is encrypted and inaccessible to Trustgrid staff, including support and engineering teams.
For a clear understanding of the difference between the Data Plane and Control Plane, see the Basic Architecture section.
Node access is strictly limited to maintenance and troubleshooting activities, and only applies to the Control Plane.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Ubuntu VMs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/base-setup/ubuntu2204/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/base-setup/ubuntu2204/</guid><description>The trial requires users have access to two instances of Ubuntu 22.04 LTS (Jammy Jellyfish) to on which the Trustgrid agent is installed. There are numerous ways to acheive this, but below are a few methods to streamline the process.
Deploy on AWS The below methods assume you have access to an AWS account. The EC2 resources required fall under the AWS Free Tier program so costs should be minimal.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Trustgrid Agent Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/upgrade-agent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/agent-mgmt/upgrade-agent/</guid><description>How an Agent Node Upgrades The Trustgrid agent upgrade process will depend on the operating system the agent runs on. For the most part the process will include:
Gaining console access to the agent host system either via SSH or local console Running a package management tool to update the agent software package Restarting the agent service if not done automatically by the package manager Restarting the agent service is important to ensure it loads the latest configuration and starts with the updated code but will disrupt traffic across the node.</description></item><item><title>View Virtual Route Table</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</guid><description>Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.
Select VPN under the Network section.
Click the Tools button and click the View Virtual Routes button
A table will appear with routing information for the node.
Analyzing the Route Table Route Availability If a route is available, its Active column will show a green up arrow (). If a route is not available, its Active column will show a red down arrow ().</description></item><item><title>VNET</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/vnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/vnet/</guid><description>A virtual network tunnel interface can be configured on a Trustgrid node or cluster to allow the forwarding of traffic to a remote Trustgrid Node or Cluster that is attached to the same virtual network. The tunnel interface is associated with a VRF which is used to define and control what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. There is no attachment of the vnet interface to a node interface required but the virtual network does need to be attached to the node or cluster before the tunnel interface is created.</description></item><item><title>Volumes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/containers/volumes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/containers/volumes/</guid><description>Volumes allow containers to persist data between executions.
Create a Volume Volumes have the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The name of the volume. Encrypted Whether or not to encrypt the volume. Encrypted volumes The type of volume. Location Optionally, specify a location in the node data store.</description></item><item><title>VRFs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</guid><description>Overview VRFs can be used to route and/or nat and filter what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. VRFs can be associated with an interface whether it be a physical interface / virtual network interface or other tunnel interfaces such as IPSEC or GRE. VRFs are segmented on a layer 3 level from all other traffic traversing the Trustgrid node.
For standard use cases of source nat and/or destination nat creating a route and a NAT is sufficient.</description></item><item><title>WireGuard</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/wireguard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/wireguard/</guid><description>A WireGuard tunnel interface can be configured to allow a WireGuard client to connect to a Trustgrid Node running as a WireGuard server. The tunnel interface is associated with a VRF which is used to define and control what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network.
Configure WireGuard Tunnel On a Trustgrid Node navigate to Tunnels under the Network Menu, select Add Tunnel, and then select WireGuard</description></item><item><title>WireGuard ®</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/wireguard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/wireguard/</guid><description>Nodes may enable a WireGuard server to expose the virtual network to WireGuard clients.
Configuration Enabled When enabled, this node will accept WireGuard client connections Port The port clients should connect to Remote Traffic Forwarding Whether the node should forward traffic to the virtual network Key Management Clients will need the server&amp;rsquo;s public key to connect. This can be generated (using the Regenerate action) or can be derived from the private key (imported using the Import action).</description></item><item><title>ZTNA Gateway</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/ztna-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/ztna-gateway/</guid><description>Navigate to a node, then select ZTNA Gateway under the Network section.
HTTPS Endpoint Field Name Description Enabled When enabled, this node will listen for ZTNA traffic. Public FQDN The IP or FQDN of the node or the load balancer in front of the node. If using a domain name without a load balancer, be sure to select the appropriate certificate. Port The port to listen on. Users will always connect on port 443, so only change this if the node is behind a load balancer.</description></item></channel></rss>