<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trustgrid Local Console Utility on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/</link><description>Recent content in Trustgrid Local Console Utility on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Network Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/advanced-network-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/advanced-network-config/</guid><description>The setting below should be changed via the Trustgrid portal interface configuration if at all possible. These tools should only be used if the correct configuration is preventing successful communication to the control plane.. Modify Network Settings If the Trustgrid service is unreachable the normal Network Configuration will be unavailable and it may be necessary to manually edit the network settings on the device to change the IP and DNS configuration.</description></item><item><title>Remote Console Registration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/remote-registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/remote-registration/</guid><description>This feature is currently available as a preview and requires Trustgrid support to grant portal users access to activate nodes. Overview The remote console registration process allows for a Trustgrid Node running a generic image to be registered with a valid Trustgrid account.
Requirements Console access to the Trustgrid Node. This could be achieved via: For physical devices either keyboard and monitor connections or serial console For VMware or Hyper-V remote console access For Azure and AWS serial console access via each providers management portal Portal access with the appropriate permissions to activate nodes.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Menu</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Tools on this page allow for additional troubleshooting. Troubleshooting Menu View Node Logs This utility opens the Trustgrid service logs in a text viewer in follow mode so new lines will be displayed as written to the log file.
To exit follow mode hit control + C. You can then use arrow keys to move up and down through the log file.
To return to the Troubleshooting menu hit control + C (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already) and then input :q and hit return.</description></item></channel></rss>