<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node Appliance Deployments on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/</link><description>Recent content in Node Appliance Deployments on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On a Stick Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/ros-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/ros-config/</guid><description>Edge nodes can be configured in an &amp;ldquo;on a stick&amp;rdquo; configuration, in which only a single NIC is used for each node. Operating in this mode is supported only when using Layer 3 or Layer 4 configuration where hosts behind gateway nodes need access to data behind edge nodes.
In this configuration, the source IP of traffic from the edge node depends on whether Layer 3 or Layer 4 is being used, as illustrated below.</description></item><item><title>Configure HA Trustgrid Gateway Cluster in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</guid><description>Deploy a pair of Trustgrid gateways. Deployment guide includes an example Cloud Formation template that can be used directly or customized for your environment or converted to Terraform if preferred. Gateways can be deployed in the same availability zone or different ones to provide greater redundancy across AWS. Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS.
Under networking &amp;gt; clusters create a cluster using a descriptive and unique name as seen below.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</guid><description>Standing up a Trustgrid node in AWS is easy using an Amazon AMI. Trustgrid nodes in AWS use two network interfaces - a management and a data interface. The management interface communicates with Trustgrid Cloud Management systems. The data interface is used to terminate TLS tunnels from Edge Nodes.
Notes The cloudformation template below works with an AMI currently published in US-EAST-1/2 and US-WEST-1/2. Deploying in other regions requires working with Trustgrid Support Requires VPC and public subnet Does not create security groups or roles - those have to be managed separately (more below) If using a burstable performance instance types (T2, T3 and T3a) the following is advised:</description></item><item><title>AWS Requirements for HA Wireguard Cluster</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/aws-ha-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/aws-ha-cluster/</guid><description>Create EC2 Target Group and add both Trustgrid gateways with the target being wireguard server port (Default UDP 51820) The health check should be set to http with a path of /status and override traffic port to be port 80.
Only the active member of the Trustgrid Cluster will respond as healthy to the health check.
Create NLB (Network Load Balancer) with listener set to configured UDP wireguard server port (Default 51820) and forwarding to the target group created above.</description></item><item><title>AWS Requirements for HA ZTNA Gateway Cluster</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/aws-ha-ztna-gateway-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/aws-ha-ztna-gateway-cluster/</guid><description>Create EC2 target group and add both Trustgrid application gateways with the target being TCP port 80. The health check should be for http and the path should be /status
Only the active member of the Trustgrid Cluster will respond as healthy to this check.
Create an ALB (Application Load Balancer) with the listener set to HTTPS and forwarding to the target group created above. Under secure listener settings apply the SSL Certificate provided by Trustgrid for the application gateways.</description></item><item><title>Deploy to vSphere</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-vsphere/</guid><description>Requirements Hardware Resources 4 vCPU 4 GB RAM 30 GB disk space Software Requirements vSphere 6.7 or newer (with VMWare support) Configuration Best Practices Backups Trustgrid recommends against backing up virtualized Nodes. Backups that utilize VMware&amp;rsquo;s Data Protection API will initiate a VM Snapshot that will pause all traffic through the VM for a short period of time. This can cause issues such as master failover in a cluster and disruption of existing network flows.</description></item></channel></rss>