<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Management on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/</link><description>Recent content in User Management on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Access</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/api-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/api-access/</guid><description>Generating an API Key Navigate to User Management -&amp;gt; API Access, and click Regenerate API keys. This will invalidate your existing API key, if it exists. The API key is tied to your user and will have the same permissions.
The client secret key will only be available at time of generation - if it&amp;rsquo;s lost, the key will need to be regenerated
Using the API Key To use the API key in a request, pass it in as an HTTP header, like Authorization: trustgrid-token client-id:client-secret Anything that can be done in the Trustgrid Portal can be done with the API (except for generating an API token).</description></item><item><title>Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/groups/</guid><description>User Management Groups defined can be used to make Remote Access applications visible to users.
Types of Groups Trustgrid-Native Groups These groups are created in the Portal via the Add Group button. Membership is managed directly within the Portal by administrators.
Identity Provider-Synchronized Groups These groups are created based on Identity Provider (IdP) configuration for select IdPs (currently G Suite and Azure OpenID). The IdP can be configured to sync all or select groups, and the sync process will update the group membership automatically.</description></item><item><title>Policies</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/</guid><description>User Management Policies define what an authenticated user is allowed to do within the Trustgrid system. Policies either allow or explicitly deny specific actions by the user.
Types of Policies Trustgrid Managed Policies These policies start with the prefix builtin-tg and are created and managed by Trustgrid to provide a starting level of permissions based on common user types. Descriptions of the user types for each role are listed below.</description></item><item><title>Service Users</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/service-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/service-users/</guid><description>Service Users are specialized accounts designed for machine-to-machine interactions and automated integrations. Unlike standard users, Service Users cannot log in to the Trustgrid Portal UI. Instead, they are used to invoke the Trustgrid API programmatically.
Service Users can be assigned specific permissions via policies, allowing granular control over what resources an automation script or external system can access.
Service User functionality must be enabled by Trustgrid. Contact support to use this feature.</description></item></channel></rss>