<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VPN on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/</link><description>Recent content in VPN on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Network Address Translation (NATs)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/nats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/nats/</guid><description>NATs allow Trustgrid to alter the source and/or destination IP address of layer 3 traffic as it enters or leaves the VPN.
Adding an Interface NATs are scoped to an interface. Add an interface from the Actions menu.
Add Interface dialog Field Name Description Network Interface Select the desired interface from the drop-down list of those available on the node or cluster. Description User friendly description of this interface attachment.</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dns/</guid><description>Nodes can act as domain name servers (DNS) for requests ingressing the virtual network on the node if DNS is configured at the virtual network.
VPN DNS Settings page DNS Status This setting must be set to Enabled on the node to process requests targeting the configured virtual network DNS server IP.
Upstream Servers If configured, the node will use these servers to resolve DNS requests for zones not configured at the virtual network level.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dynamic-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/dynamic-routing/</guid><description>Dynamic routing allows a node to export and import routes from other nodes in the virtual network. Find dynamic route definitions and change them under the Dynamic Routing section of the VPN configuration.
Dynamic Routing table Exports Export routes for other nodes in the virtual network to import.
Add Export Route dialog Field Name Description Destination The node to route traffic to. Destination CIDR The network to route traffic to. Metric The route metric.</description></item><item><title>Port Forwarding</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/port-forwarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/port-forwarding/</guid><description>Port forwarding allows a node to expose an L4 TCP service on the virtual network.
Port Forward listing Field Name Description Virtual IP Address The IP to expose the service on the virtual network. Virtual Port The port to expose the service on the virtual network. Local Service The service to expose. Alternately, you can specify an IP and port.</description></item><item><title>Static Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/static-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/static-routing/</guid><description>Static routing allows a node to route traffic to a remote network in addition to virtual network-defined routes(https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/). Routes defined at this level can be created for destination CIDRs outside the virtual network&amp;rsquo;s Network CIDR
Find static route definitions and change them under the Static Routing section of the VPN configuration.
Add Route dialog Field Name Description Destination The node to route traffic to. Destination CIDR The network to route traffic to.</description></item><item><title>WireGuard ®</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/wireguard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vpn/wireguard/</guid><description>Nodes may enable a WireGuard server to expose the virtual network to WireGuard clients.
Configuration Enabled When enabled, this node will accept WireGuard client connections Port The port clients should connect to Remote Traffic Forwarding Whether the node should forward traffic to the virtual network Key Management Clients will need the server&amp;rsquo;s public key to connect. This can be generated (using the Regenerate action) or can be derived from the private key (imported using the Import action).</description></item></channel></rss>