<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Event Types</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</guid><description>This page lists all event types that can be generated by Trustgrid nodes. Events are alphabetized and grouped by their filter type. For events that have both trigger and resolution states, the trigger severity and resolution severity are shown.
Contents All Gateways Disconnected All Peers Disconnected BGP Peer Connectivity Certificate Expiring Cluster Failover Configuration Update Failure Connection Flapping Connection Timeout Data and Control Plane Disruption Data Plane Disruption Deregister DNS Resolution Gateway Connectivity Health Check Gateway Ingress Limit Reached Gateway UDP Tunnel Error Metric Threshold Violation Network Error Network Health Check Networking Framework Memory Management Node Connect/Disconnect Node Delete Node Stop Error Order Commented Order Created Repo Connectivity SSH Lockdown Unauthorized IP Event Types All Gateways Disconnected Trigger Severity: WARNING</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</guid><description>Events are emitted from nodes and from the Trustgrid control plane when actionable things happen. Events are the basis for alarms and notifications.
Events can be viewed for individual nodes by navigating to Events under the History section.
Events for the entire organization can be viewed by navigating to Events under the Alarms section.
Clicking the Test button will send the event through your configured alarms to help verify channels are configured as expected.</description></item></channel></rss>