<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Remote VPN Tools on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/</link><description>Recent content in Remote VPN Tools on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ping Remote Virtual Host</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</guid><description>Prerequisites Both the source and destination nodes should have a virtual management IP configured There should be a unique IP under Node &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; VPN &amp;gt; Virtual Management IP In the virtual network route configuration in your domain, a route should exist with the following settings: Destination: node name (even if part of a cluster) Destination CIDR: virtual management IP with a /32 suffix Metric: 1 Use the View Virtual Route Table tool to verify both the source and destination nodes have valid, available routes to each other&amp;rsquo;s virtual management IP Need to know the virtual IP address of the inside NAT if targeting a local IP on the destination network Need to know the virtual management IP address of the destination node if only verifying VPN network connectivity The Ping Remote Node tool allows you to verify data plane communication by node name Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Sniff Virtual Traffic</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-virtual-traffic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-virtual-traffic/</guid><description>Summary This tool allows you to monitor the traffic flowing over a VPN tunnel by &amp;ldquo;sniffing&amp;rdquo; inside the tunnel. This allows traffic to be viewed after NATs have been applied and confirm traffic is routed to or from the expected node.
Usage This tool is accessed on a node&amp;rsquo;s detail page under the VPN panel. Select the desired attached virtual network (note: if only on virtual network is present it will be selected by default) and click the &amp;ldquo;Tools&amp;rdquo; button in the top right.</description></item><item><title>View Virtual Route Table</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</guid><description>Usage Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.
Select VPN under the Network section.
Click the Tools button and click the View Virtual Routes button
A table will appear with routing information for the node.
Analyzing the Route Table Route Availability If a route is available, its Active column will show a green up arrow (). If a route is not available, its Active column will show a red down arrow ().</description></item></channel></rss>