<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Help Center on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/</link><description>Recent content in Help Center on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Support Responsibility Matrix</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</guid><description>The matrix below defines the primary responsible party for troubleshooting and resolving different types of issues. Trustgrid support can be engaged to assist in resolving issues not directly in scope of their responsibility.
Organization and Roles Trustgrid Trustgrid is a software and services provider that operates a multi-tenant cloud management system and assists customers and end-users with the deployment and management of a data transfer plane.
Customer Customers have a direct, contractual relationship with Trustgrid to utilize Trustgrid’s software and services.</description></item><item><title>Working with Trustgrid Support</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/</guid><description>Paying Trustgrid customers can contact our support team for assistance for Tier 2 support requests and assistance with Tier 1 support requests as defined by the support responsibility matrix.
Support Hours Production impacting issues (P1 Severity): 24/7/365 support All other issues: Monday-Friday 8:30am-5:30pm Central Time (excluding US holidays) To contact support: Below are the methods or requesting support from Trustgrid:
Request support via the Portal - ** This is the recommended method to request support.</description></item><item><title>Network Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</guid><description>Flow logs are a records of for network traffic that passes through a node. They can be used to troubleshoot connectivity issues, or to monitor traffic patterns.
What are flow logs? Flow logs are records containing metadata about each network traffic flow, or conversation, from the initial connection (e.g. the first SYN packet for TCP) to the closing of the connection (e.g. FIN or RST packets for TCP). Flow logs do not contain any payload data for the flow which makes them much smaller and more secure than a full packet capture of the same flow.</description></item><item><title>Check Trustgrid Services Status</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-service-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-service-status/</guid><description>View the status of all Trustgrid services on our Statuspage Account
Within the Trustgrid Portal, hover over the username in the upper right corner and then select Status.
Components Trustgrid components on the status page are broad and meant to communicate areas where there may be elevated error rates.
Node Node components affect services that nodes use to manage status, updates, and enroll.
Cloud Controller - signals nodes when to update their config and receives from nodes: events, flow logs, shadow updates Software Repository - provides both OS and Trustgrid package updates License Manager - responsible for enrolling new devices with Trustgrid Management Alerts - event collection and notification services Management Portal - the UI used to manage your devices User Management - the ability to sign in using Trustgrid native authentication Management Gateways - the ability to invoke interactive services on nodes</description></item></channel></rss>