<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in Architecture on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Architecture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</guid><description>Nodes The basic building block of a Trustgrid network is a node. Nodes are deployed on-premises or in your cloud provider and connected to each other to build a data plane on top of which additional services such as virtual networking, ztna access, and compute can be provided.
Nodes can be deployed either as an agent, a service running in an existing operating system, or as an appliance which bundles the operating system and Trustgrid software together.</description></item><item><title>Networking</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</guid><description>Trustgrid delivers a software defined wide area network (SD-WAN) that enables connectivity between cloud environments, data centers, and edge or on-premise hosts. Our robust networking feature set provides layer 3 and layer 4 network overlays with cloud management tools.
Types of Connectivity Trustgrid establishes mutual TLS tunnels between nodes using mutual authentication. These tunnels between edge nodes and gateway nodes constitute the data plane of a Trustgrid network. Over this tunnel two distinct types of connectivity are supported, Layer 3 and Layer 4.</description></item></channel></rss>