<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– architecture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in architecture on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting-Started: Basic Architecture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="nodes">Nodes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The basic building block of a Trustgrid network is a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a>. Nodes are &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/deployment/">deployed&lt;/a> on-premises or in your cloud provider and connected to each other to build a &lt;a href="%5B#data-plane%5D">data plane&lt;/a> on top of which additional services such as &lt;a href="#virtual-networks">virtual networking&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#ztna-access">ztna access&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="#edge-compute">compute&lt;/a> can be provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nodes can be &lt;a href="../deployment">deployed&lt;/a> either as an &lt;strong>agent&lt;/strong>, a service running in an existing operating system, or as an &lt;strong>appliance&lt;/strong> which bundles the operating system and Trustgrid software together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, appliance-based nodes can be &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">clustered&lt;/a> to provide high availability at a site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gateways">Gateways&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While all nodes can act as edge nodes (making only outbound connections), appliance-based nodes can also be configured to act as &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/">gateway servers&lt;/a> which listen for inbound connections from other edge nodes in the account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These connections create the &lt;a href="#data-plane">private data plane&lt;/a> which enabls the Trustgrid network services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane">Data Plane&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The data plane is built between edge nodes and their gateways nodes to allow private connectivity between sites. It provides a virtual network overlay on top of the public internet to securely connect distributed systems and applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="virtual-networks">Virtual Networks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nodes can be attached to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual networks&lt;/a>, which provide a way to share network configuration like &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">routes&lt;/a>, NATs, and &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/">ACLs&lt;/a> at scale.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="layer-4-proxy">Layer 4 Proxy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The data plane can also be used to enable Layer 4 proxy connections across two nodes. In this setup, one node will act at the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/">connector&lt;/a> listening on a specified port. When traffic is received on that port it will be forwarded to the configured &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/">service&lt;/a>. The node that hosts that service will then forward the traffic on to the configured IP and port using it&amp;rsquo;s local interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ztna-applications">ZTNA Applications&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/">ZTNA Applications&lt;/a> can be exposed through nodes or clusters. Access to an application can be restricted via &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/access-policy/">access policies&lt;/a>, for example to only allow users from a specific country.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="control-plane">Control plane&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the data plane, all Trustgrid nodes build connections to the Trustgrid control plane. This allows centralized management and monitoring of all nodes from the Trustgrid portal and api including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software updates are provided through our apt repository that ensures nodes have security updates available and only run with tested software permutations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Network, node, user, and application configuration is managed through our web portal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configuration changes are broadcast to nodes as needed, for example when adding routes or adding a gateway to your network&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All services of the control plane are contained &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/site-requirements/#trustgrid-control-plane">Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s reserved address spaces&lt;/a> to limit the required firewall rules required for an edge node to operate behind a firewall.&lt;/p>
&lt;script src="https://docs.trustgrid.io/js/fullscreen.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="basic-connectivity.png" alt="Basic connectivity diagram" onclick="toggleImageSize(this)" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-weight: lighter;">
Basic Connectivity Diagram
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Getting-Started: Networking</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Trustgrid delivers a software defined wide area network (SD-WAN) that enables connectivity between cloud environments, data centers, and edge or on-premise hosts. Our robust networking feature set provides layer 3 and layer 4 network overlays with cloud management tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="types-of-connectivity">Types of Connectivity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid establishes mutual TLS tunnels between &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> using mutual authentication. These tunnels between edge nodes and gateway nodes constitute the data plane of a Trustgrid network. Over this tunnel two distinct types of connectivity are supported, Layer 3 and Layer 4. Layer 3 supports &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">routed&lt;/a> traffic and Network Address Translation (NAT) to replicate traditional WAN connections. Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s Layer 4 networking uses reverse proxies to map local IP-port number combinations to remote hosts. Each connectivity type has distinct advantages and may be used for either gateway nodes or edge nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="layer-3-overview">Layer 3 Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Trustgrid VPN feature provides the capability to securely route IP packets between networks. In this configuration, Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> can operate as a distributed mesh virtual private network (VPN) that can allow applications to access remote data and services at layer 3 (L3) of the network OSI model. This is done by defining a virtual L3 network (similar to an Amazon VPC) and then selecting how edge node networks are exposed and translated into the the virtual address space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 3 configuration is required for all Trustgrid networking deployments on the Gateway (data center / cloud) side. This allows the use of L3 or Layer 4 configurations for edge node deployments. Layer 3 connectivity enables easy support of many hosts at each side of the connection. This allows the replication of existing &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">routes&lt;/a> and subnets to minimize reconfiguration of any remote or local networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 3 edge configuration is ideal in situations where there is an incomplete understanding of all traffic (source and destination hosts/ports) as it supports more permissive ACLs. It is required when using stateful protocols (except FTP) and other protocols such as SIP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All gateway nodes must be deployed using L3 networking in a two interface (management/data NIC) configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="layer-4-overview">Layer 4 Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid Layer 4 (L4) is only supported in edge configurations. Layer 4 networking enables a reverse proxy connection between the Gateway Node IP address:port number that maps directly to an on-premise host:port. Specific network plug-ins support stateful features like FTP using L4 connectivity. With Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s L4 networks there is no concern of overlapping local IP subnets on either end of the tunnel because Trustgrid proxies the traffic. The source of all TCP/UDP traffic is the edge node interface, not the originating host. This is transparent to the hosts on either side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 4 connectivity offers slightly better performance than L3 in specific types of traffic and is ideal when there is a single or few remote/edge hosts that are being accessed with deterministic traffic. Layer 4 edge nodes are usually easier to deploy at an edge site as they can avoid the configuration of a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a> overlay (NATs, ACLs, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">Routes&lt;/a>, etc). Remote sites that desire to view the actual source of traffic should use Layer 3 for edge configurations as the source IP for all traffic in a Layer 4 connection is the edge node&amp;rsquo;s data IP address.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>