<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Connectors</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</guid><description>Connectors are configured in conjunction with services to define a local listening port for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Configuration Connectors are configured under the Networking &amp;gt; Connectors tab of the node or cluster configuration section in the Trustgrid Portal.
Add Connector dialogue Field Name Description Protocol The protocol that the listener for the connector will use. Options are TCP, UDP, FTP, and TFTP.
FTP must operate in passive mode when using L4 services and connectors.</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</guid><description>Services are configured in conjunction with connectors or port forwards to define a host (IP or DNS) and port to connect to for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Description Services define the host name or IP and port of a server that can be accessed by the Trustgrid node (or members of the cluster) where it is defined. Remote clients can then access the service via peer nodes using connectors or VPN port forwards.</description></item><item><title>Tunnels</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/</guid><description>Tunnels Overview Trustgrid Supports configuring various tunneling protocols to establish secure connectivity between any appliance that supports the underlying protocol. The supported tunnels are listed below.
IPsec - Internet Protocol Security supporting IKEv1 and IKEv2 tunnels GRE - Generic Routing Encapsulation used for setting up a direct point to point network connection Vnet - The virtual network tunnel is the Trustgrid Proprietary VPN tunneling protocol and therefore can only be used to establish connectivity to other Trustgrid nodes in the organization Wireguard - The latest open source tunneling protocol aiming to provide better performance than the traditional ipsec or openvpn protocols &amp;ldquo;Wireguard&amp;rdquo; is a registered trademark of Jason A.</description></item><item><title>VRFs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</guid><description>Overview VRFs can be used to route and/or nat and filter what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. VRFs can be associated with an interface whether it be a physical interface / virtual network interface or other tunnel interfaces such as IPSEC or GRE. VRFs are segmented on a layer 3 level from all other traffic traversing the Trustgrid node.
For standard use cases of source nat and/or destination nat creating a route and a NAT is sufficient.</description></item><item><title>GRE</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/gre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/gre/</guid><description>Trustgrid supports configuring GRE tunnels that can be used to establish connectivity to any appliance that supports the GRE protocol. A GRE tunnel interface is created which can then be attached to an interface on a node. VRFs can then be used to control the flow of traffic and how it should appear on the network.
Configure GRE Tunnel On a Trustgrid Node navigate to Tunnels under the Network Menu, select Add Tunnel, and then select GRE</description></item><item><title>IPSec</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/ipsec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/ipsec/</guid><description>Trustgrid supports configuring traditional IPSec tunnels that can be used to establish connectivity to any appliance that supports the IPSec protocol. Once an IPSec tunnel is configured an IPSec virtual interface is created that can be attached to a node interface. VRFs can be used in conjunction to explicitly control what traffic is allowed (VRF ACLs) to pass and how it should look on the network (VRF NATs or Traffic Rules).</description></item><item><title>VNET</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/vnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/vnet/</guid><description>A virtual network tunnel interface can be configured on a Trustgrid node or cluster to allow the forwarding of traffic to a remote Trustgrid Node or Cluster that is attached to the same virtual network. The tunnel interface is associated with a VRF which is used to define and control what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. There is no attachment of the vnet interface to a node interface required but the virtual network does need to be attached to the node or cluster before the tunnel interface is created.</description></item><item><title>WireGuard</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/wireguard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/tunnels/wireguard/</guid><description>A WireGuard tunnel interface can be configured to allow a WireGuard client to connect to a Trustgrid Node running as a WireGuard server. The tunnel interface is associated with a VRF which is used to define and control what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network.
Configure WireGuard Tunnel On a Trustgrid Node navigate to Tunnels under the Network Menu, select Add Tunnel, and then select WireGuard</description></item></channel></rss>