<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Domain on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/domain/</link><description>Recent content in Domain on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/domain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</guid><description>An access policy is a list of rules that each allow, reject, or drop traffic at the VPN level.
If no rules are defined, traffic will not pass through the virtual network.
A rule can match traffic based on the following fields:
Field Name Description Action Whether to ALLOW, DROP, or REJECT the traffic. Protocol You can choose ANY, UDP, ICMP, or TCP. Source The source of the traffic. You can select a network object, a network group, or provide a CIDR.</description></item><item><title>Domain</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/</guid><description>A domain is the logical grouping of nodes inside an organization.
Domains are a logical grouping of nodes, allowing configuration of virtual networks and node thresholds. Each Trustgrid deployment has a single domain.</description></item><item><title>Network Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</guid><description>A network group is a list of network objects that allows for easier rule management.
A network group requires a name to be set. This will be used to reference the group in access policy rules.
Navigating into a network group allows management of the group’s member objects.</description></item><item><title>Network Objects</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</guid><description>A network object allows naming a CIDR inside a VPN for easier rule management.
A network object requires the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The label to use when referencing this object. CIDR Specifically an IPv4 CIDR. Multiple network objects may be clustered into a network group.</description></item><item><title>Review Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</guid><description>Because changes to a domain virtual network affect all nodes, domain configuration changes must be reviewed before applied, and are applied all at once.
After making changes to a virtual network, you can review outstanding changes. A list of changes will show who made each change, with a before/after table if appropriate.
Individual changes can be rejected by clicking the delete icon at the top.
Once changes are applied, outstanding changes will disappear from the review page, and nodes will receive the configuration updates.</description></item><item><title>Routes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</guid><description>Routes configured under Domains determine to which node or cluster the Trustgrid virtual network should route traffic for a specific subnet.
Virtual Network Routes Routes defined a the virtual network level allow creating a global route table shared with all nodes and clusters attached to the virtual network. This table is then used to evaluate where to send VPN traffic for a specified destination CIDR.
Route Fields A Route has the following fields:</description></item><item><title>Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/thresholds/</guid><description>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the domain level apply to all nodes in the domain, except when overridden. Events will be of type Metric Threshold Violation.
To view thresholds, a user will need domains::read permissions. To configure them, they will need domains::configure:threshold permissions.
Navigate to your domain, and click Thresholds on the left.
Load Thresholds Load thresholds measure the health of the node itself.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Networks</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/</guid><description>Virtual networks define an overlay network and routes for layer 3 connectivity. Trustgrid nodes are then assigned to networks. Virtual network overlays work similarly to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s VPCs but can span between clouds, data centers, and the edge.
Virtual Networks Concepts Overlay Example Virtual Networks - Layer 3 Trustgrid uses a virtual network to traffic between nodes. This avoids common challenges like conflicting subnets in large, non-centralized networks.
Inside and outside NATs are used to expose hosts for traffic</description></item></channel></rss>