<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guides on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Node Agent Deployments</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/agent-deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/agent-deploy/</guid><description>Supported Operating Systems Linux Ubuntu 22.04 LTS x86-64/AMD64 At this time only x86-64/AMD64 based operating systems are supported. Container The Trustgrid agent can be deployed as a container on Linux systems. This provides an isolated environment for the agent without requiring a full operating system instance.
Trustgrid provides a Docker image that contains the agent pre-configured and optimized to run in Docker or similar container hosting environments like Kubernetes.
Agent Installation Installation instructions are also shown in the portal after adding an agent.</description></item><item><title>Configure FTP and FTPS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/ftp-and-ftps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/ftp-and-ftps/</guid><description>FTPS &amp;amp; FTPS Using Layer 3 FTP &amp;amp; FTPS are supported in passive mode when using layer 3. This configuration requires the FTP server to be configured with the external IP address in the passive settings set to the Trustgrid virtual IP that corresponds to the FTP server.
FileZilla passive mode settings:
FTP Using Layer 4 FTP is supported in passive mode when using L4 Proxy, however FTPS is not. To configure FTP access through L4 Proxy, the Outbound L4 Service and/or L4 Connector need to be configured with FTP set as the protocol as shown below:</description></item><item><title>Configure Layer 3 VPN</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/config-l3-vpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/config-l3-vpn/</guid><description>The VPN feature enables routing of IP packets by utilizing a virtual IP space that is configured on the nodes. In this configuration, the node can be used as the next hop for route destined for the virtual IP space, or the node can be used as the default gateway for a network. The virtual IP space is used as a transit network with NAT being utilized to translate IP addresses on to/from the virtual IP space on either side.</description></item><item><title>Enable SAML with Okta</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/saml-okta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/saml-okta/</guid><description>In Okta, switch to the Classic UI to be able to configure SAML applications.
Further Information on configuring SAML Application in Okta Classic UI: https://developer.okta.com/standards/SAML/setting_up_a_saml_application_in_okta/
Create an Application, then select Web and SAML 2.0.
When configuring SAML, enter the Trustgrid Portal and select EmailAddress for Name ID format and Email for Application username.
Complete the following survey questions and then download the IDP Metadata XML File by clicking on Identity Provider Metadata link.</description></item><item><title>Find the Public IP Address of a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/find-ip-node/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/find-ip-node/</guid><description>The public IP address refers to the source IP address observed by the Trustgrid cloud when the control plane connections are established. This is the IP address after any NATs are applied to outbound internet traffic on the node&amp;rsquo;s WAN interface.
Nodes Table The public IP address is a default column in the Nodes table list. You can use search to filter the list to see the public IP of the desired node.</description></item><item><title>Changing the WAN Interface IP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/wan-interface-ip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/wan-interface-ip/</guid><description>The WAN interface of a Trustgrid node is used to build connections to both the Control Plane and any Data Plane connectivity. Any change to this IP address is disruptive and presents a risk that the device will go offline if incorrect information is provided. This could potentially require a technical resource to go onsite to reconnect physical devices.
To make the below changes via the Trustgrid portal the user must have the Node Administrator or Administrator role.</description></item></channel></rss>