<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Control Plane Release Notes on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Control Plane Release Notes on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>June 2025 Major Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-06/</guid><description>VLAN Sub-Interface Improvements Adds SNMP support for VLAN interfaces, enhancing monitoring capabilities. Removes the node-level restriction on VLAN interface assignments. Infovisor Redesign This release includes a significant redesign of the Infovisor, providing a more intuitive and user-friendly interface. Some key improvements include:
Info is now grouped into multiple panels that can be collapsed or expanded, and even added/removed for easier navigation. All info fields now include a copy button when hovered over, allowing for easy copying of information.</description></item><item><title>April 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-04/</guid><description>New Hop Monitoring Options This cloud release when combined with the April 2025 major appliance release, adds the following new Hop Monitoring options in the Gateway &amp;gt; Client panel.
Other Improvements and Fixes Fixes an issue preventing setting the cluster heartbeat IP on Google Cloud Platform appliances.</description></item><item><title>March 2025 Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-03/</guid><description>Other Improvements and Fixes Takes additional steps to prevent issues that lead to control plane outages in February 2025. Fixes an issue that prevented some models from saving their Gateway configuration changes.</description></item><item><title>February 2025 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2025-02/</guid><description>Permissions and Policies Condition Scoped Policies With this release we expand our permissions model to allow for using tags to scope the policy. This allows for more granular control of permissions, or as an alternative to specifying TGRNs in the policy.
For example, if you wanted to limit a group of users to only see the nodes and cluster for a specific client, you could create a policy that looks like this: Tag Scoped Policy based on ClientID tag Any cluster or node with this tag would have the permissions granted by this policy.</description></item><item><title>November 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-11/</guid><description>Upgrade Manager This release makes available the Upgrade Manager to orchestrate upgrades across large numbers of devices. The Upgrade Manager can target specific nodes and clusters based on tags and provides a single pane of glass for monitoring the upgrade process.
Upgrade Manager also automates Cluster upgrades by starting with the standby node in the cluster, triggering a failover once it that node has completed the upgrade, and then upgrading the other member of the cluster.</description></item><item><title>September 2024 2nd Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09-2/</guid><description>Removal of Select All Option As part of the July backend library a &amp;ldquo;Select All&amp;rdquo; option was introduced on tables, such as the nodes table. Trustgrid has determined this option creates risks of large changes with insufficient controls to prevent mistakes so we are removing it from all tables.</description></item><item><title>September 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-09/</guid><description>Data Plane Status for Gateways A recent change to the data plane panel to display disconnected peers had the unintended side-effect that appliances acting as gateways would show a Degraded status if any of their clients wasn&amp;rsquo;t connected, even if that client was offline. As this is a pretty normal state the status was confusing for users. The data plane status indicator has been changed to only count the connections the node is responsible for initiating and does not count any inbound connections.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-07/</guid><description>Portal Backend Library Update With this release, we are updating the React library used in the Portal to a more recent version. This change should be mostly invisible to users there are a few notable improvements including:
Resizable columns: In most tables including the Nodes and Flow Logs tables. This will make it easier to read the data in the tables. Notifications are improved: Node actions show in-progress status and node alerts appear as stackable bottom-right alerts expanding on hover.</description></item><item><title>May 2024 2nd Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05-2/</guid><description>Issues Resolved Nodes or Clusters with upper case letters were impacted by a number of UI bugs that prevented: Viewing the VPN configuration Creating modifying routes with upper case named nodes/clusters as the destination</description></item><item><title>May 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-05/</guid><description>Introducing Alert Center A new Alert Center has been added to the node page to centralize alert messages and simplify resolving multiple alerts. This removes the alerts from the Infovisor menu and makes resolving multiple alerts easier. Example alert center with 3 open alerts Other Improvements and Fixes Further improvements in flow log query performance for faster results and resolved an issue that caused exports to not be complete. Detaching Policies now prompts for confirmation.</description></item><item><title>March 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-03/</guid><description>Portal Notification Improvements This release makes several changes to how a portal user is notified of new events and commands (such as Restart and Reboot) related to the node being viewed. The toast pop-up notifications have a new look as shown below: Example notifications of a restart request and the resulting events The notifications will automatically close or can be dismissed by clicking the X at the top corner.
This release also will notify if a Restart request fails to complete successfully by showing a Failed status toast and a message in the center of the screen.</description></item><item><title>February 2024 Release Notes - Minor</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/2024-02/</guid><description>Flow Log Performance Improvements This release further increases the performance of flow log search using our new database.
Other Improvements The MTR interface in the portal now supports selecting a source IP from your interface and cluster IPs. The Reboot and Restart buttons in the portal will now be disabled if a node is offline. This is to make clear you cannot perform these actions on an offline node. Other Fixes Resolves issue preventing adding Azure AD as an identity provider.</description></item><item><title>January 2024 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/january-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/january-2024/</guid><description>Default Authentication Provider Change Trustgrid has previously utilized Auth0 as the authentication provider for customers who do not use a custom identity provider (IdP). With this release, Trustgrid has migrated to utilizing an internally managed authentication service to provide more control and stability.
This change will have no impact on customers using their own Identity Providers (IdPs) for portal authentication User Migration Process As part of this process users will be prompted to migrate their accounts from the previous Auth0 provider to the new internally managed authentication service.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Third Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-3/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issues:
Issues Fixed Fixes an issue that caused virtual network access policies to fail to respect configured line numbers.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023-2/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issue:
Issues Fixed A function was deprecated in the last release as it was believed to be no longer needed but it was discovered that some methods of registration, such as the AWS CloudFormation template, still relied on it. This release removes the deprecation and restores the function.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/november-2023/</guid><description>Statistics Improvements Long Term Statistics Starting with this release the Overview graphs for nodes running the July 2023 release or newer will display 1 week and 1 month statistic views. Previously only 24 hours was visible in the portal. This allows viewing historical usage trends over longer periods of time directly from the node detail page.
1 week stats are aggregated into hourly data points 1 months stats are aggregated into 6 hour data points JVM Heap Metrics A new section called Metrics with a new statistic called JVM Heap to help make clear if the load on a node requires more memory than is currently allocated to the node process.</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/august-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/august-2023/</guid><description>Cluster Site Health Improvements Since introducing our cluster site health state feature there have been several instances where the state was being reported incorrectly. This release has taken steps to prevent that and has also introduced a new tool to force validating the health state in the event the state does appear incorrect. Validate Health action Data Plane Panel Improvements This release includes two improvements to the Data Plane panel:</description></item><item><title>July 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/july-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/july-2023/</guid><description>Network Interface Panel Changes Interface Details Copy All Button Frequently Trustgrid users need to share the interface configuration information with people who do not have access to the Trustgrid portal. There is now a Copy All button that will load all of these details into your clipboard.
Copy All button Example WAN interface output:
IP: 172.16.11.31/24 Hardware Address: 00:50:56:8e:03:54 Gateway: 172.16.11.1 DNS1: 172.16.11.4 DNS2: 4.2.2.2 Public IP Removed from WAN Interface The WAN interface used to include a field labeled &amp;ldquo;Public IP&amp;rdquo; that was the IP address the Trustgrid control plane saw as the source IP for traffic from the node.</description></item><item><title>May 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023-2/</guid><description>This minor release fixes the following issues:
Issues Fixed The Overview graphs on a Node Detail page showing &amp;ldquo;invalid date&amp;rdquo; when you hover over a VPN data point. The Flow Logs Advanced Search did not display the correct flows when the &amp;ldquo;Newest First&amp;rdquo; flow log order was used.</description></item><item><title>May 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/may-2023/</guid><description>Accessibility Improvements Prior to this release we used only the color red to indicate if the control or data plane was disconnected. We now use different icons to indicate there is an issue with connectivity.
Control Plane Disconnected Control Plane Disconnect icon Data Plane Disconnected Data Plane Disconnected icon Change Audit Improvements Several improvements where made around our change auditing system including:
Tag changes are now audited. Change records can now be replicated into a customer&amp;rsquo;s AWS S3 bucket.</description></item><item><title>April 2023 Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023-2/</guid><description>Issues Fixed This minor release fixes the following issues:
Network Maps displayed peer nodes as disconnected New Orders could not be created if left open too long before the first save</description></item><item><title>April 2023 Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/april-2023/</guid><description>Documentation Trustgrid is moving away from our documentation previously hosted on Confluence to docs-as-code system at https://docs.trustgrid.io. This should enable us to more tightly integrate the portal UI with related documentation.
As a start, we&amp;rsquo;ve created a link called Documentation under the Management section of the main navigation bar that will open the docs in a new tab.
Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve created a section for release notes that will allow you to monitor release for Control Plane and Node releases via RSS feeds going forward.</description></item></channel></rss>