<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Agent and Appliance Shared Configuration on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/</link><description>Recent content in Agent and Appliance Shared Configuration on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alert Center</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/alert-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/alert-center/</guid><description>The Alert Center provides a centralized view of open alerts for a node. Alerts can be resolved from this screen individually, or all can be resolved using the &amp;ldquo;Mark all as resolved&amp;rdquo; button. Example alert center with 3 open alerts</description></item><item><title>Audits</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</guid><description>Node audits provide records when services on a node are invoked, or when upgrades are applied. This can be helpful to see the historical maintenance of a node.
Node audits can be viewed for a specific node by navigating to Audits under the History section on the node view.
Users will need audits::read:node permissions to view node audits.
Node audits can also be found for the entire organization by navigating to Operations-&amp;gt;Node Audits.</description></item><item><title>Connectors</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/connectors/</guid><description>Connectors are configured in conjunction with services to define a local listening port for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Configuration Connectors are configured under the Networking &amp;gt; Connectors tab of the node or cluster configuration section in the Trustgrid Portal.
Add Connector dialogue Field Name Description Protocol The protocol that the listener for the connector will use. Options are TCP, UDP, FTP, and TFTP.
FTP must operate in passive mode when using L4 services and connectors.</description></item><item><title>Node Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/flow-logs/</guid><description>This page will show the most recent flow logs for the specific node being viewed and allow for advanced searches scoped to the current node.
See this page for more info on Flow Logs</description></item><item><title>Infovisor</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/infovisor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/infovisor/</guid><description>The infovisor displays details about the Trustgrid node and can be displayed by clicking the Info button in the top right or hitting the backtick ` key. Button to open Infovisor It displays the following information in a card layout: Example infovisor It contains the below information but can vary between appliance and agent-based nodes. The table below lists the fields and if they are displayed depending on node type.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/location/</guid><description>Trustgrid uses each node&amp;rsquo;s public IP address to derive location information. If it&amp;rsquo;s incorrect, the fields can be set manually. If set manually, IP changes will not update the node&amp;rsquo;s location when viewed from the nodes table or the network map.
To change the Node Location: Change the details to desired settings then click Save when done.</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/services/</guid><description>Services are configured in conjunction with connectors or port forwards to define a host (IP or DNS) and port to connect to for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.
Description Services define the host name or IP and port of a server that can be accessed by the Trustgrid node (or members of the cluster) where it is defined. Remote clients can then access the service via peer nodes using connectors or VPN port forwards.</description></item></channel></rss>