<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/node/</link><description>Recent content in Node on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audits</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/shared/audits/</guid><description>Node audits provide records when services on a node are invoked, or when upgrades are applied. This can be helpful to see the historical maintenance of a node.
Node audits can be viewed for a specific node by navigating to Audits under the History section on the node view.
Users will need audits::read:node permissions to view node audits.
Node audits can also be found for the entire organization by navigating to Operations-&amp;gt;Node Audits.</description></item><item><title>Data Plane</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</guid><description>The Data Plane panel shows a list of all statistics known peers, their connection status, provides tools for testing connectivity and can display statistics for the connection between the node and the peer.
Export List of Peers You can export a CSV formatted list of all peers by clicking Actions -&amp;gt; Export Export button The CSV file will include columns for:
Connection status (true/false) Peer name Peer IP Path (if applicable) RTT - Return Trip Time or latency observed when the panel was opened or refreshed Mode - TLS or TLS/UDP Type - The role of the node to peer.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</guid><description>Network Interfaces Navigate to a node, then select Interfaces under the Network section.
Interfaces panel The Interface dropdown at the top allows you to select which interface to manage.
ETH0 - WAN Interface This interface is always used to build the outbound TLS tunnels for control and data plane connectivity. If the node is deployed in a single interface configuration, this interface will also be used for local network connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/</guid><description>A node is an instance of software used for building connections, managing compute resources, and deploying software.
Node Types A node can be installed on a hardware appliance, as a virtual appliance (Vsphere and Hyper-V), and deployed in a public cloud (Amazon AMI, Google, Microsoft). There are three main types of nodes - Edge, Gateway, and Management.
All Trustgrid nodes run on a hardened Ubuntu operating system. Nodes are managed through the Trustgrid portal or via the API (requires authentication token).</description></item><item><title>Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</guid><description>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the node level can override Domain Thresholds.
Example Thresholds page on a node Node Level Threshold Status Field Name Description Status Disabled (default) - Only thresholds defined at the domain level will be used for generating events. Enabled - Thresholds defined at the node level will be used for generating events, including overriding any domain-level values.</description></item><item><title>Node Down Response</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/operations-runbook/node-down-response/</guid><description>This process is intended to help customer support personnel quickly identify the scope of a node down problem and get services back online as quickly as possible.
Node Down Triage Triage Checklist Determine Production Status of the Trustgrid Node
Confirm High Availability or Disaster Recover is Functioning
If clustered, is the partner active and working
If there is a second site, confirm if it is active
Determine the type of outage (Control Plane, Data Plane or Both)</description></item></channel></rss>