<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node Appliance Release Notes on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/</link><description>Recent content in Node Appliance Release Notes on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January 2026 Third Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01-3/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20260116-2361 20260116-153629.64ac9d4 n-2.23.6 It was discovered that upgrading appliances via the Local Console Utility caused some systems to fail to boot. This issue resolves that problem and allows appliances to be upgraded successfully using the Local Console Utility.
Additionally, this release changes how OS packages are upgraded so that future upgrades should apply faster.
Like version n-2.23.4, this release updates the APT repository to a mirror from December 15, 2025, which includes packages available on that date.</description></item><item><title>January 2026 Second Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01-2/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20260108-2356 20260108-162524.eeaec95 n-2.23.5 This release resolves an issue seen when upgrading appliances using the NCA-1210 and Dell R250 platforms running Ubuntu 22.04 to version n-2.23.4, which caused the upgrade of a particular OS package to fail due to an artifact left over from the imaging process. Appliances using these platforms can now successfully upgrade to this release.
Like version n-2.23.4, this release updates the APT repository to a mirror from December 15, 2025, which includes packages available on that date.</description></item><item><title>January 2026 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2026-01/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251216-2350 20251216-211950.61a1833 n-2.23.4 Shortly after publishing we discovered that appliances using the NCA-1210 and Dell R250 platforms running Ubuntu 22.04 hit a significant package conflict that caused the upgrade to fail. Because of the failure mode, this release has been effectively revoked until the conflict can be resolved; please do not upgrade devices at this time. This release updates the APT repository to a mirror from December 15, 2025, which includes packages available on that date.</description></item><item><title>December 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-12/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251124-2340 20251124-234159.0f29e39 n-2.23.3 This is a minor release that fixes the following issues:
There was a situation where a bad certificate for the control plane could cause a device to stop attempting to connect. Simultaneous disconnections of the cluster heartbeat connections could cause a device to enter a deadlock state where it would not attempt to reconnect to its cluster peers. Resolves an issue where non-cluster appliance nodes would log an error about looking for a cluster IP address.</description></item><item><title>November 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-11/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251105-2319 20251105-135239.a7de5ae n-2.23.2 Cluster Fixes and Improvements Fixed an issue where, after the configured active cluster member was changed while the original active node was offline, the returning node could incorrectly claim the active role. This occurred because the returning node was unaware of the change and briefly assumed the active role before releasing it, but the newly configured active node did not reclaim the role.</description></item><item><title>October 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-10/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20251006-2299 20251006-145121.01eb7c5 n-2.23.1 Resolve Inaccurate UDP Events and Debug Logs This release will fix an issue that caused some nodes with UDP enabled to generate a large number of events indicating:
UDP Tunnel has timed out for node &amp;lt;nodename&amp;gt; and endpoint &amp;lt;endpoint&amp;gt; UDP Tunnel connection has been re-established for node &amp;lt;nodename&amp;gt; and endpoint &amp;lt;endpoint&amp;gt; These events were inaccurate and could be safely ignored. UDP tunnel traffic was NOT disrupted.</description></item><item><title>August 2025 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-08/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250813-2291 20250813-201825.ef18f9a n-2.23.0 DNS Health Appliances being able to successfully resolve DNS is important for their overall functionality and reliability. Ensuring that DNS queries are properly handled can prevent a range of issues, especially regarding connections to the Trustgrid control plane.
To ensure newly provisioned nodes can connect, even if their provided DNS servers are not immediately reachable, the node has a DNS cache for critical control plane services.</description></item><item><title>April 2025 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-04/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250415-2266 20250415-213243.4a224c3 n-2.22.0 Hop Monitoring Improvements This release makes some significant improvements to Hop Monitoring. Previously the Hop Monitoring ran every 20 seconds providing only 3 samples per minute. This was not enough to provide accurate data for some applications. This release increases the sample rate to every 5 seconds. This allows the Hop Monitoring to provide accurate data for applications that require a high sample rate.</description></item><item><title>January 2025 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2025-01/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20250109-2213 20250109-221438.4c724ae n-2.21.1 Other Improvements and Fixes Fixes an issue where connections to the Trustgrid control plane could get stuck in a CLOSE_WAIT state. This could cause the node to show as disconnect despite a working data plane connection. Adds an early release feature to allow clustered Azure-based appliances to manage a floating, local cluster IP address similar to on-premises appliances. Currently there is no UI support for this feature.</description></item><item><title>October 2024 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-10/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20241010-2172 20241010-161952.c6810b2 n-2.21.0 Force Node Health Check Refresh In the July 2024 cloud release Trustgrid exposed warnings in the portal if a node was unable to connect to its configured DNS server, the Trustgrid update repository (repo), or if SSH had been reconfigured to listen on an IP other than localhost. These health checks run automatically at the following times:
Repo Connectivity is checked every 24 hours DNS Resolution runs hourly SSH Lockdown is checked when the node service first starts With this release, rather than waiting for the health checks to rerun and update the state of each check you can now force the node to rerun each check.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Major Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07-2/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240719-2112 20240719-202719.9cf7134 n-2.20.0 Configuration Retrieval Improvements Appliances retrieve their configuration from the control plane services. Before this release, it was not obvious if a node was unable to pull down its configuration which could lead to unexpected behavior. Two improvements have been made:
A new event called Configuration Update Failure has been created that the appliance will send if it is unable to connect to the configuration control plane API endpoint.</description></item><item><title>July 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-07/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240704-2096 20240704-010918.2.b2a86bf n-2.19.3 Dynamic Routing Issue A recent release broke the ability of a node to announce a VPN Dynamic route to a peer. This release resolves that issue.</description></item><item><title>June 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-06/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240514-2064 20240514-213500.a967cd2 n-2.19.2 Issues Resolved Flow logs related to port forwards were not showing on the receiving device An issue was preventing some security packages from being updated Updated the AWS library being utilized in the AWS dependency package</description></item><item><title>April 2024 Minor Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-04/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240422-2039 20240422-165737.3d6b62c n-2.19.1 Abnormal Disconnect Messages limited to Clients Before this release, both the appliances that are acting as the gateway server and the edge node client would send abnormal disconnect events. This change limits abnormal disconnect messages to only be sent from the client to avoid excessive alert notifications on the gateway server.
VPN Communication with Out-of-date Peers A recently release version of the appliance introduced an unexpected change that caused out-of-date clients, running versions from early 2021 or older, to receive VPN packets they could not process.</description></item><item><title>March 2024 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-03/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240306-1999 20240306-161006.62ba5a5 n-2.19.0 Dynamic Access Policy Evaluation Previously Access Policies were only evaluated at the time a flow was created. With this release, access policies will be re-evaluated in realtime for active flows. This allows dynamically changing policies to immediately take effect without requiring existing flows to timeout or reset.
System Resources Overview Appliances running this release will now share with the control plane the number of CPU cores, total system memory (RAM), and total disk size.</description></item><item><title>February 2024 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/2024-02/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20240203-1968 20240203-071412.8f765f6 n-2.18.0 Removal of Local UI System The local UI functionality allowed users with direct physical access to an appliance network port to connect to a lightweight web server on the appliance to change the WAN interface IP and see the connectivity status. Several years ago, this solution was augmented with the Console Utility which has proved easier to use and has been expanded to provide much more functionality.</description></item><item><title>December 2023 Appliance Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/dec-2023-minor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/dec-2023-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231206-1914 20231206-183238.65d2bde n-2.17.3 Disable UDP Rekeying A customer had a misconfiguration that led to the UDP rekeying messages being lost. This compounded the performance impact as the UDP tunnels had to be rebuilt frequently.
This release adds the ability for Trustgrid support to disable UDP rekeying on a gateway if needed. Trustgrid will make the UDP rekeying process more resilient and better able to handle lost key exchanges in the future.</description></item><item><title>November 2023 Appliance Minor Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/nov-2023-minor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/nov-2023-minor/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231122-1901 20231122-215335.d942235 n-2.17.2 Resolved Issues Fixes an issue introduced in the October 2023 release that caused the end time of flow logs to be incorrect Fixes an issue that prevented registering nodes in newer AWS regions</description></item><item><title>October 2023 Appliance Second Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023-1-minor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023-1-minor/</guid><description> Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231017-1855 20231017-165331.5772aac n-2.17.1 Resolved Issues Fixed an issue where the appliance would stop responding to SNMP traffic on the virtual management IP if virtual network port forwards were configured.</description></item><item><title>October 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20231003-1842 20231003-145438.e8103a2 n-2.17.0 Support for running Ubuntu 22.04 LTS This release adds support for running the Trustgrid node appliance on Ubuntu 22.04 LTS for new deployments on AWS, Azure and vSphere. The 18.04 appliances will continue to be supported and security updates made available via the Trustgrid repository.
There are no plans to support upgrading OS on deployed devices at this time due to the risks involved.</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Second Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230824-1797 20230824-150008.3c2d422 n-2.16.2 Update Fix This minor release resolves several issues:
Fixed an issue where client devices could experience increased CPU utilization if their peer gateways were offline or unreachable. Resolved issues with ARP on VLAN interface cluster IPs that could cause both active and standby members to respond to ARP requests. This prevented proper failover behavior. Resolved SNMP issues for VMware VM8 nodes that didn&amp;rsquo;t have all 8 virtual network interfaces attached to the virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>August 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230731-1784 20230731-222839.d3f2205 n-2.16.1 Update Fix This minor release resolves an issue that prevented a security package from upgrading.</description></item><item><title>July 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</guid><description>Package Version Core Version Release 1.5.20230712-1762 20230712-200223.7cced96 n-2.16.0 New Event Types Several new event types are generated with this version of the node appliance software.
DNS Failure If the node is unable to resolve DNS via its configured DNS servers it will generate a DNS Resolution error event. Example DNS resolution events Interface Down Notification This event is triggered when any configured interface&amp;rsquo;s link state goes from UP to DOWN.</description></item></channel></rss>