<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Node Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/</link><description>Recent content in Node Appliance Release Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release-Notes: October 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/oct-2023/</guid><description>
&lt;table style="margin: 0 auto;">
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Package Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Core Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Release&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>TBD&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TBD&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n-2.17.0&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="support-for-running-ubuntu-2204-lts">Support for running Ubuntu 22.04 LTS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This release adds support for running the Trustgrid node appliance on Ubuntu 22.04 LTS for new deployments on AWS, Azure and vSphere. The 18.04 appliances will continue to be supported and security updates made available via the Trustgrid repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
There are no plans to support upgrading OS on deployed devices at this time due to the risks involved.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="preview-feature-node-registration-from-the-trustgrid-console">(Preview Feature) Node Registration from the Trustgrid Console&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This release includes a new feature that allows you to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/remote-registration/">register a node from the Trustgrid console&lt;/a>. This will allow a Trustgrid node running the a standard image to be registered with a Trustgrid account without needing to share a complete license token.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The high-level process is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>A user with console access to a Trustgrid node logs in and initiates the registration process. This triggers a process that generates unique certificates for the node and generates a short activation code. The node will then begin checking with the Trustgrid control plane to see if it has been activated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This code can then be shared with a user with access to the Trustgrid portal. That user can then enter the code in the Trustgrid portal via the &lt;strong>Activate Node&lt;/strong> action. After entering the code they are prompted to provide a name for the node and click &lt;strong>License Node&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the node detects its code has been activated it finalizes registration and then reboots. The node is then available for use and configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This release also allows the user at the console to deregister a node. This will remove the node from the Trustgrid account and deactivate the license.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
This feature is currently in preview and requires Trustgrid support to enable the feature for specific users.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="other-trustgrid-console-improvements">Other Trustgrid Console Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The ability to run &lt;code>traceroute&lt;/code>, &lt;code>mtr&lt;/code>, &lt;code>ip&lt;/code>, &lt;code>curl&lt;/code>, &lt;code>openssl&lt;/code> from the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/troubleshooting/#network-tools-shell">Troubleshooting &amp;gt; Network Tools Shell&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The ability to modify an interface&amp;rsquo;s MTU settings from the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/local-console-utility/advanced-network-config/#change-interface-mtu">Advanced Network Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-tool-for-monitoring-connectors">New Tool for Monitoring Connectors&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This release includes a new service that will allow you to see active &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/">L4 Connector&lt;/a> sessions. This gives visibility into the active usage of any connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-improvements-and-fixes">Other Improvements and Fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Audit messages for actions related to containers will now include the container name for improved visibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IPSEC Tunnels will now display their up/down status on the Tunnels page for easier monitoring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolves an issue preventing AWS nodes from detecting their region correctly if they were set to require IMDSv2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved issues that lead to false events for &amp;ldquo;packet(s) too large for UDP&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Interface Down&amp;rdquo; notices during restart/reboot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved an issue impacting proxy ARP responses on VLAN subinterfaces for outside NAT.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: August 2023 Second Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-2-minor/</guid><description>
&lt;table style="margin: 0 auto;">
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Package Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Core Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Release&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.5.20230824-1797&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20230824-150008.3c2d422&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n-2.16.2&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="update-fix">Update Fix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This minor release resolves several issues:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed an issue where client devices could experience increased CPU utilization if their peer gateways were offline or unreachable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved issues with ARP on VLAN interface cluster IPs that could cause both active and standby members to respond to ARP requests. This prevented proper failover behavior.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved SNMP issues for VMware VM8 nodes that didn&amp;rsquo;t have all 8 virtual network interfaces attached to the virtual machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: August 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/august-2023-1-minor/</guid><description>
&lt;table style="margin: 0 auto;">
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Package Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Core Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Release&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.5.20230731-1784&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20230731-222839.d3f2205&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n-2.16.1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="update-fix">Update Fix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This minor release resolves an issue that prevented a security package from upgrading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: July 2023 Appliance Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/node/july-2023/</guid><description>
&lt;table style="margin: 0 auto;">
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Package Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Core Version&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Release&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.5.20230712-1762&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20230712-200223.7cced96&lt;/td>
&lt;td>n-2.16.0&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="new-event-types">New Event Types&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Several new &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/">event types&lt;/a> are generated with this version of the node appliance software.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dns-failure">DNS Failure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the node is unable to resolve DNS via its configured DNS servers it will generate a DNS Resolution error event.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="dns-event.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 70%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example DNS resolution events
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="interface-down-notification">Interface Down Notification&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This event is triggered when any configured interface&amp;rsquo;s link state goes from UP to DOWN.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="interface-event.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 70%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example Interface health events
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="trustgrid-unhealthy-stop-notification">Trustgrid Unhealthy Stop Notification&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This event is triggered if the Trustgrid service fails to stop completely prior to the most recent start. This could indicate a hard power cycle event or something caused the Trustgrid service to halt unexpectedly.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="trustgrid-crash.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 70%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example Node Stop Error
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="cluster-health-events">Cluster Health Events&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The following cluster health related events are now available and will now resolve themselves once the triggering condition clears.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Network Health Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data and Control Plane Disruption&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="virtual-network-port-forwards">Virtual Network Port Forwards&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Port forwards allow mapping a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">layer 4 service&lt;/a> to a virtual IP address in a Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">layer 3 virtual network&lt;/a>. Prior to this release, port forwards could only be defined at the node or cluster level and this required an additional virtual network route to be defined to send the virtual IP traffic to the correct node or cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/">Virtual Network Port Forward&lt;/a> feature combines the route and port forward configuration and consolidates the definition to the virtual network level.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="layer-4-health-checks-deprecated">Layer 4 Health Checks Deprecated&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">layer 4 service&lt;/a> historically had an option to perform a health check where a connection attempt was made once per minute to the configured IP and port. If this was configured on a cluster, the member nodes would mark themselves unhealthy if the connection failed. Since this was usually caused by an issue with the local network or target server, this frequently led to both nodes being marked as unhealthy and taking the cluster offline. As this feature was rarely used and caused more issues than it solved we have removed this it from this version of the node software. If this was previously configured on a service the setting will be ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support-for-requiring-imdsv2-on-aws-ec2-instances">Support for requiring IMDSv2 on AWS EC2 Instances.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The AWS Instance Metadata Service (IMDS) provides information about the EC2 instance that the Trustgrid service queries to enable certain features. Some potential security issues were identified in the IMDSv1 version of this service and AWS recommends &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/configuring-IMDS-existing-instances.html#modify-require-IMDSv2">requiring IMDSv2&lt;/a> going forward. This version of the Trustgrid node software is confirmed to be fully compatible with IMDSv2-only instances.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>