<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started with a Trial Account on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started with a Trial Account on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Request Trustgrid Trial Account</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/request-trial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/request-trial/</guid><description>The process below will guide you through requesting a free trial account.
High-Level Steps Sign up for a Trustgrid trial account Verify email Sign in Prerequisites Email address Chrome-based browser Step 1 - Create a Trustgrid account Using Chrome or a similar browser navigate to https://portal.trustgrid.io/signup Provide the requested information. Note that the account will be created based on the provided Company Name. A verification email will be sent to the provided address.</description></item><item><title>Implement Access Policy Restrictions</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/access-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/access-policies/</guid><description>When designing a network from a zero-trust, least-privilege mindset, all agents and appliances should restrict access as much as possible both to each other and their adjacent network resources. Trustgrid allows for granular control over what traffic is permitted across the virtual network using access policies. The default virtual network was created with an &amp;ldquo;Allow All&amp;rdquo; policy to facilitate initial connectivity during the trial period.
In this section, we will update the policy to restrict traffic between the two agents.</description></item><item><title>Configure Subnet Routing</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/subnet-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/trial/subnet-routing/</guid><description>The tutorial up to this point only demonstrated the ability to send traffic between the IP addresses assigned to the trustgrid0 interfaces on each agent. However, it&amp;rsquo;s quite likely that security and operational constraints will prevent the Trustgrid agent from being installed directly on the target server. Instead, the agent will need to route traffic destined for the target server&amp;rsquo;s local network.
In this section, we will configure an agent to route traffic destined for another network through the Trustgrid virtual network.</description></item></channel></rss>