<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Identity Providers on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/</link><description>Recent content in Identity Providers on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure AD</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/azure-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/azure-idp-fields/</guid><description>Setup Setting up the Azure AD integration requires the configuration of an Azure App registration. See Azure App registration configuration.
Field Name Description Issuer Specifies the Azure App OpenID metadata endpoint. Client ID Specifies the Azure App client ID. Secret Specifies the Azure App secret. Before being able to save the configuration, validation of the Issuer needs to be performed by pressing the Test button. Once the validation has been performed and the configuration saved, the sync section will be available.</description></item><item><title>G Suite</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/gsuite-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/gsuite-idp-fields/</guid><description>Setup Setting up the G Suite integration requires a G Suite administrator to perform the configuration.
Once the integration has been successful, the user sync selection will be presented:
Sync all users - Syncs all available users along with all the groups associated to the users. Sync users from specific groups - Syncs all users from the selected groups. Disconnect G Suite - Deletes all users and groups and removes the G Suite integration.</description></item><item><title>OpenID</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/open-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/open-idp-fields/</guid><description>
Field Name Description Issuer The OpenID issuer URL. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider. Client ID The OpenID application client ID. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider. Client Secret The OpenID application client secret. This will be provided to you by your OpenID Identity Provider.</description></item><item><title>SAML</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/saml-idp-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/idps/saml-idp-fields/</guid><description>When configuring a SAML IDP, the provider will often provide a metadata XML file to simplify configuration. If provided, you can upload that on the SAML configuration page, which will automatically populate the fields necessary for SAML authentication.
Field Name Description Issuer A URL that will point to the IDP, typically with some identifying information so the IDP can determine the source of the request. This will be provided by your SAML identity provider.</description></item></channel></rss>