<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Networks on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Networks on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</guid><description>An access policy is a list of rules that each allow, reject, or drop traffic at the VPN level.
If no rules are defined, traffic will not pass through the virtual network.
A rule can match traffic based on the following fields:
Field Name Description Action Whether to ALLOW, DROP, or REJECT the traffic. Protocol You can choose ANY, UDP, ICMP, or TCP. Source The source of the traffic. You can select a network object, a network group, or provide a CIDR.</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</guid><description>The DNS feature allows nodes in the virtual network to act as DNS servers for ingress VPN traffic. The node can resolve queries custom defines DNS zones and records, or forward queries to upstream DNS servers.
DNS Settings Field Name Description Enable/Disable DNS This field enables or disables the DNS feature on the virtual network. DNS Server IP This is the IP address that should be used as the resolver. There is no need to create a VPN route for this IP.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network IP Pools</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/ip-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/ip-pool/</guid><description>Virtual Network IP Pools are used for automatically assigning virtual management to nodes. This is optional but makes configuration and management easier.
At this time only agent-based nodes support automatic IP assignment Address Assignment Addresses are assigned sequentially from the pool by Trustgrid. When a node is attached to a virtual network with an IP pool configured, it will automatically be assigned the next available IP from the pool. When a node is detached its IP is returned to the pool for reuse.</description></item><item><title>Network Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</guid><description>A network group is a list of network objects that allows for easier rule management.
A network group requires a name to be set. This will be used to reference the group in access policy rules.
Navigating into a network group allows management of the group’s member objects.</description></item><item><title>Network Objects</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</guid><description>A network object allows naming a CIDR inside a VPN for easier rule management.
A network object requires the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The label to use when referencing this object. CIDR Specifically an IPv4 CIDR. Multiple network objects may be clustered into a network group.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network Port Forwards</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</guid><description>Virtual Network Port Forwards allow a virtual IP address to be associated with a TCP Layer 4 service on a remote node or cluster without the need to specify a route for that virtual IP address. Example Virtual Network Port Forward Description As noted above, a Virtual Network Port Forward (or remote port forward) associates a service defined on a node or cluster with a virtual IP address within the virtual network without needing to specifically route that IP to the node/cluster.</description></item><item><title>Review Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/</guid><description>Because changes to a domain virtual network affect all nodes, domain configuration changes must be reviewed before applied, and are applied all at once.
After making changes to a virtual network, you can review outstanding changes. A list of changes will show who made each change, with a before/after table if appropriate.
Individual changes can be rejected by clicking the delete icon at the top.
Once changes are applied, outstanding changes will disappear from the review page, and nodes will receive the configuration updates.</description></item><item><title>Routes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</guid><description>Routes configured under Domains determine to which node or cluster the Trustgrid virtual network should route traffic for a specific subnet.
Virtual Network Routes Routes defined a the virtual network level allow creating a global route table shared with all nodes and clusters attached to the virtual network. This table is then used to evaluate where to send VPN traffic for a specified destination CIDR.
Route Fields A Route has the following fields:</description></item></channel></rss>