<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alarms on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/</link><description>Recent content in Alarms on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alarm Filters</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/</guid><description>Alarm Filters are used to determine which events trigger notifications and to define which channels should receive those notifications.
Alarm filters have the following fields:
Field Name Description Name The name should be unique. Description The description is displayed in the alarm filters table. Enabled An alarm filter must be enabled for matching event to be sent to the selected channel. Deselecting the check box can be handy if you wish to suppress a specific type of alarm.</description></item><item><title>Alert Suppression</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alert-suppression/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alert-suppression/</guid><description>Maintenance and other planned disruptive activity can generate a large amount of alerts and notifications for no value. The Trustgrid system allows you to define alert suppression windows during which no alerts are triggered.
Define Alert Suppression Window Navigate to Alarms -&amp;gt; Alert Suppression.
Enter a message to users. During the window this will be displayed on the dashboard when users first log in.
Select a duration between 1 and 4 hours for your window.</description></item><item><title>Channels</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/</guid><description>A channel defines one or more method of delivering alert notifications to external systems.
Notification Delivery Channels Email Channel One or more email address (comma separated) that will receive messages from alerts@trustgrid.io
PagerDuty Channel Trustgrid will generate an incident via the PagerDuty API if provided a valid API routing key. To procure a routing key, create a service in PagerDuty and add an Events API V2 integration. After adding the integration, the Integration Key is your API routing key.</description></item><item><title>Event Types</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/</guid><description>This page lists all event types that can be generated by Trustgrid nodes. Events are alphabetized and grouped by their filter type. For events that have both trigger and resolution states, the trigger severity and resolution severity are shown.
Contents All Gateways Disconnected All Peers Disconnected BGP Peer Connectivity Certificate Expiring Cluster Failover Configuration Update Failure Connection Flapping Connection Timeout Data and Control Plane Disruption Data Plane Disruption Deregister DNS Resolution Gateway Connectivity Health Check Gateway Ingress Limit Reached Gateway UDP Tunnel Error Metric Threshold Violation Network Error Network Health Check Networking Framework Memory Management Node Connect/Disconnect Node Delete Node Stop Error Order Commented Order Created Repo Connectivity SSH Lockdown Unauthorized IP Event Types All Gateways Disconnected Trigger Severity: WARNING</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/</guid><description>Events are emitted from nodes and from the Trustgrid control plane when actionable things happen. Events are the basis for alarms and notifications.
Events can be viewed for individual nodes by navigating to Events under the History section.
Events for the entire organization can be viewed by navigating to Events under the Alarms section.
Clicking the Test button will send the event through your configured alarms to help verify channels are configured as expected.</description></item></channel></rss>