<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operations on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/</link><description>Recent content in Operations on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration Changes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/changes/</guid><description>Trustgrid records information about changes users make to all configuration. This can be helpful when troubleshooting recent changes.
Changes can be viewed for a specific node and for the entire organization. To view changes for a specific node, navigate to a node and select Changes under the History section. To view changes for the entire organization, navigate to Operations-&amp;gt;Changes.
The following information is shown for each change:
Field Name Description Date When the change was made IP The IP address from which the change originated Event The type of change (delete/create/change/action).</description></item><item><title>Authentication Audits</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/authentication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/authentication/</guid><description>Trustgrid records information for authentication attempts into the control plane. This information can be used to troubleshoot authentication issues, or to monitor for suspicious activity.
Authentication audits are available by navigating to Operations-&amp;gt;Authentication Audits. Only the most recent 25 records are shown, but the last 30 days of audits can be downloaded by clicking the link at the bottom of the page.
Successful logins from external identity providers are logged, but failed attempts are not.</description></item><item><title>Organization Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/flow-logs/</guid><description>This page shows Flow Logs from all nodes in an organization. See this page for more info on Flow Logs
Flow Log Export Trustgrid can export flow logs to any S3 bucket. Set your bucket name and apply the policy provided, and then Trustgrid will configure replication for your flow logs into your bucket.
Fields for configuring S3 replication Field Name Description AWS Account ID This is the AWS Account ID that contains the bucket you wish to have Flow Logs replicated to.</description></item></channel></rss>