<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Appliance Nodes on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/</link><description>Recent content in Appliance Nodes on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Options</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/advanced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/advanced/</guid><description>The Advance section provides additional configuration options for customizing the node behavior from the default settings. Default settings work in most environments and should only be changed if needed based on your specific requirements. Config Options Advanced Config Options The Config Options panel allows customizing various advanced settings for the node such as network flow defaults. Each setting provides a description of what it controls and the value field. Additionally, the button on the far right allows resetting a setting back to the default value.</description></item><item><title>BGP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/bgp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/bgp/</guid><description>Summary Trustgrid nodes can be configured to connect to an external BGP router to advertise and receive routes. This allows Trustgrid networks to be integrated into an existing routing fabric.
The BGP panel is listed under the Network panel group.
Configuration Router Configuration These are the settings used by the local BGP router.
Field Name Description Status Enabled/Disabled - Whether the BGP server is running on the node. ID The IP addressed used to identify the BGP router.</description></item><item><title>Cluster Heartbeat Configuration</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/cluster/</guid><description>Cluster configuration is only available for nodes that are members of a cluster. Heartbeat The cluster heartbeat defines a persistent connection between cluster members. The heartbeat is used to determine the health of the cluster and to determine which member is the active member. This configuration is required on cluster members.
Field Name Description Heartbeat Host The IP (bound to an interface) on which heartbeat communication will occur Heartbeat Port The port on which heartbeat communication will occur The same interface should be selected for all cluster members Status Endpoint (Optional) The Status Endpoint allows you to start an HTTP REST endpoint on a port on the WAN interface IP that will return a 200 response if the member is healthy and the active cluster member.</description></item><item><title>Data Plane</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/data-plane/</guid><description>The Data Plane panel shows a list of all statistics known peers, their connection status, provides tools for testing connectivity and can display statistics for the connection between the node and the peer.
Export List of Peers You can export a CSV formatted list of all peers by clicking Actions -&amp;gt; Export Export button The CSV file will include columns for:
Connection status (true/false) Peer name Peer IP Path (if applicable) RTT - Return Trip Time or latency observed when the panel was opened or refreshed Mode - TLS or TLS/UDP Type - The role of the node to peer.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/interfaces/</guid><description>Network Interfaces Navigate to a node, then select Interfaces under the Network section.
Interfaces panel The Interface dropdown at the top allows you to select which interface to manage.
ETH0 - WAN Interface This interface is always used to build the outbound TLS tunnels for control and data plane connectivity. If the node is deployed in a single interface configuration, this interface will also be used for local network connectivity.</description></item><item><title>Additional Metrics</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/metrics/</guid><description>The Metrics page will be used to display additional available statistics that are not displayed on the overview page. Similar to the overview page these stats are viewable in 1, 2, 6, 12, and 24-hour views, and 1 week and 1 month views.
JVM Heap The Trustgrid service on appliance-based nodes runs via the Java Virtual Machine (JVM). When launched the java process claims a minimum amount of memory from the operating system.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/overview/</guid><description>Stats The Node overview page shows performance and network traffic data.
Supported time windows are selectable at the top. VPN and network statistics can be targeted to specific virtual networks and interfaces.
Field Name Description Node Performance shows CPU, disk, and memory usage percentages VPN Traffic Volume shows data usage sent and received, across all VPNs and for the selected virtual network Traffic Volume shows data sent and receives, across all interfaces and for the selected interface Connected Peers shows the number of other nodes connected.</description></item><item><title>Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/thresholds/</guid><description>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the node level can override Domain Thresholds.
Example Thresholds page on a node Node Level Threshold Status Field Name Description Status Disabled (default) - Only thresholds defined at the domain level will be used for generating events. Enabled - Thresholds defined at the node level will be used for generating events, including overriding any domain-level values.</description></item><item><title>VRFs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/vrfs/</guid><description>Overview VRFs can be used to route and/or nat and filter what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. VRFs can be associated with an interface whether it be a physical interface / virtual network interface or other tunnel interfaces such as IPSEC or GRE. VRFs are segmented on a layer 3 level from all other traffic traversing the Trustgrid node.
For standard use cases of source nat and/or destination nat creating a route and a NAT is sufficient.</description></item><item><title>ZTNA Gateway</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/ztna-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/ztna-gateway/</guid><description>Navigate to a node, then select ZTNA Gateway under the Network section.
HTTPS Endpoint The HTTPS endpoint is used to provide connectivity for non-WireGuard ZTNA applications.
Field Name Description Enabled When enabled, this node will listen for ZTNA traffic. Public FQDN The IP or FQDN of the node or the load balancer in front of the node. If using a domain name without a load balancer, be sure to select the appropriate certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>