<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Documentation</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting-Started: Customer Responsibilities</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/customer-responsibilities/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Trustgrid and our customers share the responsibilities of securing the Trustgrid network. Trustgrid assumes and automates a significant part of the overall security challenges. These challenges range from the cloud to the firmware on hardware appliances. Our customers are responsible for securing physical environments, identity and access management, and all security aspects of the environments where Trustgrid is installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="trustgrid-secures-the-cloud">Trustgrid Secures the Cloud&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>All cloud management components are secured and monitored by Trustgrid. This includes the hardware, software, and network for all cloud components including the Portal/Management API and other management tools. Customers are responsible for issuing credentials to the Portal for each authorized user and maintaining the security of those accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="network-security-is-a-shared-responsibility">Network Security is a Shared Responsibility&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid is responsible for the security of all data plane traffic from the time it enters a Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> until the time it exits a Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a>. Customers are responsible for the security of all network traffic eggressing from any Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="trustgrid-teams-with-customers-for-edge-security">Trustgrid Teams with Customers for Edge Security&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>All virtual or hardware appliances are secured by Trustgrid. Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s ability to secure hardware is restricted to supported hardware appliances with specific exceptions. Customers are responsible for the security of the physical and logical environments into which Trustgrid is integrated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="secure-gateway-nodes">Secure Gateway Nodes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid customer&amp;rsquo;s should apply access controls to ingress traffic for gateway nodes. By restricting ingress access to edge nodes IP ranges the system security is improved and many common attacks easily avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="encrypt-traffic-with-customer-certificates">Encrypt Traffic with Customer Certificates&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By default, Trustgrid encrypts all traffic on the data and control planes with privately issued certificates from our PKI. Customers may elect to provide their own certificates for data plane encryption ensuring Trustgrid maintains a zero-knowledge security posture of all data plane traffic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting-Started: Basic Architecture</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/basic-architecture/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="cloud-components">Cloud Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Portal - The cloud management UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gatekeeper - Provides configuration updates to edge nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zuul - Maintains persistent connection with &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> for reporting, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/events/">events&lt;/a>, and updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API - The management API that exposes 100% of UI elements to automation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repo - The APT repository that stores all firmware, OS, and &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="edge-components">Edge Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Node - The software that provides core functionality in the edge including &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/">networking&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a>, compute, and management features. Edge nodes build outbound connections to gateway nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="use-cases">Use Cases&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software Defined Networking - Create a mesh &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/networking/">network&lt;/a> that connects cloud applications to edge data with load balancing, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">clustering&lt;/a>, and failover managed through a portal or API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edge Compute - Deploy applications to the edge to access datasets not appropriate for replication to the cloud due to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a> or compliance concerns, latency, or cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device Management - Manage thousands of &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> with advanced tools to reduce the burden of operations at enterprise scale.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edge API - Integrate thousands of edge datasets with a single API interface and ETL functions executing at the edge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security - Leverage Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s advanced &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a> to protect against a wide range of threats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Audits</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/audits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/audits/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Node audits provide records when services on a node are invoked, or when upgrades are applied. This can be helpful to see historical maintenance of a node.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Node audits can be viewed for a specific node by navigating to &lt;code>Audits&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>History&lt;/code> section on the node view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users will need &lt;code>audits::read:node&lt;/code> permissions to view node audits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-list.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Node audits can also be found for the entire organization by navigating to &lt;code>Operations&lt;/code>-&amp;gt;&lt;code>Node Audits&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: BGP</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/bgp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/bgp/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid nodes can be configured to connect to an external BGP router to advertise and receive routes. This allows Trustgrid networks to be integrated into an existing routing fabric.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The BGP panel is listed under the Network panel group.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="router-configuration">Router Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>These are the settings used by the local BGP router.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="status">
&lt;th>Status&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Enabled/Disabled - Whether the BGP server is running on the node.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="id">
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP addressed used to identify the BGP router. This is usually the IP on the interface used for BGP communication.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="asn">
&lt;th>ASN&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The Autonomous System Number that identifies the router.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="client">
&lt;th>Client&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Determines if the BGP router is in client mode&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="bgp-config.png" alt="table with BGP router settings" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
BGP router settings
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="peer-group-configuration">Peer Group Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This page is used to configure BGP peers that this router will establish connections with. All peers associated with the group share the same Export and Import settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add a new group:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>+Add Peer Group&lt;/strong> and provide a name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click Add.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="add-peer-group.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Add Peer Group button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>After your group is created you will need to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add peers - these are the other BGP routers your node will connect to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define import policies - these limit what routes are accepted from peers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define export policies - these limit what routes are advertised to peers&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="add-peers">Add Peers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;strong>+Add Peer&lt;/strong> button to add a BGP peer to the group. Provide:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>User friendly name for the peer&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="asn">
&lt;th>ASN&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The Autonomous System Number that identifies the peer identifies itself with&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="secret">
&lt;th>Secret&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(Optional) Secret passphrase used to authenticate with the peer&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ip">
&lt;th>IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>IP address that the peer can be reached at&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="add-peer.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example Add Peer Dialog
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h4 id="define-import-policies">Define Import Policies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The BGP server on the node will only accept routes advertised by peers if they match an import policy prefix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the Imports panel use the &lt;strong>+Add Import Policy&lt;/strong> button to add a new policy.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The user friendly name of the policy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="action">
&lt;th>Action&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Allow - advertised routes matching the defined prefixes will be added to the local routing table&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deny - advertised routes matching the defined prefixes prefixes will be rejected&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(optional) Additional information describing the policy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Click on the newly created policy to &lt;strong>+Add Prefix&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="prefix">
&lt;th>Prefix&lt;/th>
&lt;td>CIDR notation of a network used to match with advertised routes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="exact">
&lt;th>Exact&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Yes - Requires the advertised route to match the subnet length of the prefix defined above&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No - Allows routes with the same network but have different prefix lengths to match&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(optional) Additional information describing the prefix&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="define-export-policies">Define Export Policies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A BGP export policy controls which routes are advertised and sent to external BGP peers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One the Exports panel use the &lt;strong>+Add Export Policy&lt;/strong> to create a new policy&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The user friendly name of the policy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="cluster">
&lt;th>Cluster&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(Yes/No) If the node is a member of a cluster this setting will determine if it should only advertise the configured prefixes when it is the active member of the cluster.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="action">
&lt;th>Action&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Determines if matching route prefixes will be advertised or not:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Allow - Configured prefixes will be advertised to the peer group members&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deny - Explicitly prevent prefixes from being advertised&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Click the newly created policy and then click &lt;strong>+Add Prefix&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="prefix">
&lt;th>Prefix&lt;/th>
&lt;td>CIDR notation of a network to be advertised&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(optional) Additional information describing the prefix&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="management-tools">Management Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="restart-bgp-server">Restart BGP Server&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="restart-bgp.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Restart BGP button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
It is sometimes necessary to completely restart the BGP server to clear any issues or force new settings to go into effect immediately. The &lt;strong>Restart BGP&lt;/strong> button is available in the tools section of the BGP panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once issued you should see the confirmation message: Restart request sent.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="restart-bgp-output.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 30%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
BGP Restart Confirmation
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bgp-status">BGP Status&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="bgp-status.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
BGP Status button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The BGP Status tool allows you to see information about the state of BGP peering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="bgp-status-output.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
BGP Status Output
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="status">
&lt;th>Status&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Shows if the peer is actively connected or not&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="connected">
&lt;th>Connected&lt;/th>
&lt;td>If connected, shows how long the peering has been established&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="asn">
&lt;th>ASN&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The Autonomous System Number that identifies the router&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="peer-ip">
&lt;th>Peer IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP address of the peer router&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="advertised-routes">
&lt;th>Advertised Routes&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Lists the routes being advertised to the peer router&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="recieved-routes">
&lt;th>Recieved Routes&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Hovering over the view button displays the routes received from the peer and their associated metrics&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting-Started: Trustgrid's Access to Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/getting-started/security/trustgrid-node-access/</guid><description>
&lt;p>By default, Trustgrid support has access to all &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> via the Control Plane, subject to Trustgrid policies and procedures. Trustgrid customers may opt to disallow Trustgrid support access to their &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a>. Disabling support access does not interfere with automated management features such as patching, updating, logging, or authentication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Changes to the support flag are audited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: February</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-status-panel">Data Plane Status Panel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The previous release added a pop-up table that displayed statistics about a node’s connections to other node such as gateways. We’ve now moved most of this information to a new panel dedicated for this purpose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hovering over the Data Plane status indicator next to the node name still includes basic details about the number of gateways known and connected. And it includes a link to the new panel for more detail:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="data-plane-hover.png" alt="Data Plane Hover">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking that link or just selecting the Data Plane panel from the left navigation bar will bring you to a new page showing much of the same detail as the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/">previous pop-up table&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="data-plane-historical-stats">Data Plane Historical Stats&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now load historical latency data about a connection between this node and a connected gateway. Simply select the gateway from the table by clicking it, choose a start and end time and click &lt;code>Load&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="data-plane-view.png" alt="Data Plane View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="portal-tool-improvements">Portal Tool Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="tool-setting-history">Tool Setting History&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A common pain point when using the tools within the Trustgrid Portal was that if you had to rerun a tool you had to reenter the values into the prompt. With this release Trustgrid is introducing an execution history that will make rerunning a tool much simpler for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, if I run the Interface &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/tcp-port-test/">TCP Port Test&lt;/a> tool for the first time, the target IP and port will be the defaults 192.168.1.1 and port 80&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tcp-port-test.png" alt="TCP Port Test">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I change these to a new IP and port and run (e.g. 172.16.22.199 and port 22) and run the tool. The next time I run the tool these settings will be populated automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tcp-port-test-2.png" alt="TCP Port Test">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, I can click the History tab on the right to see the last few execution settings. I simply need to click apply to rerun one of the configurations listed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="history.png" alt="History">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mtr-tool">MTR Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>MTR (or my trace route) is an alternative to the traditional traceroute tool that expands on the data gathered and reported in a number of ways. It can be run interactively to run continuously until stopped, gather additional statistics, report multiple paths more clearly and more. While this tool has been available from within the Terminal for some time, Trustgrid has now made this accessible directly from the portal user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To use this new feature, the node must be running the latest Trustgrid package version (&lt;code>1.5.20220215-1159&lt;/code>) or newer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>To run the tool, navigate to the Network → Interfaces section of a node and select the desired interface. Then click the MTR button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="mtr-button.png" alt="MTR Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default settings are to target the local loopback interface IP (&lt;code>127.0.0.1&lt;/code>) and run 10 times (&lt;code>-c 10&lt;/code>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="mtr-modal.png" alt="MTR Modal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Change the target to the desired IP or host name and update the options. Some useful options include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>-T&lt;/code> to use TCP instead of ICMP and can be combined with &lt;code>-P XXXX&lt;/code> to target a specific known listening port. This can be useful when targeting a Trustgrid gateway from and edge node. (e.g. &lt;code>-T -P 8443&lt;/code>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>-w&lt;/code> runs MTR in wide screen reporting mode. You will not see output on the screen until the &lt;code>-c&lt;/code> count has completed but the output will persist, unlike when run interactively where it is cleared from the screen at completion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>See the &lt;a href="https://manpages.ubuntu.com/manpages/bionic/man8/mtr.8.html">mtr man page&lt;/a> for additional options.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="interface-flows-tool">Interface Flows Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Under the Network → Interface section you will see a new “Flows” tool listed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flows-button.png" alt="Flows Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To use this new feature, the node must be running the latest Trustgrid package version (&lt;code>1.5.20220215-1159&lt;/code>) or newer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This tool provides information about flows traversing an interface, similar to who the VPN “View Virtual Translations Table” tool shows flows traversing the VPN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Launching the tool you have a number of options to filter the results. Or you can run without filters to return all flows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flows-modal.png" alt="Flows Filter Options">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resulting table lists the flow found on the interface. This can be sorted by column.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="terminate-flow.png" alt="Flows Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, any active flow can be Terminated (disconnected) from within the tool. You will be prompted to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="terminate-flow-confirm.png" alt="Terminate Confirmation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="network-interface-improvements">Network Interface Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="interface-speed-and-duplex">Interface Speed and Duplex&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Trustgrid portal now displays the negotiated speed and duplex values:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="eth0.png" alt="Interface Speed">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it now allows you to change from the default Auto negotiation setting to a manual setting. This is frequently necessary when the connected port is hard set to a speed and duplex value, which breaks auto negotiation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="speed.png" alt="Interface Speed">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alert-improvements">Alert Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="alert-suppression-window-events">Alert Suppression Window Events&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An Alert Suppression Window prevents the Trustgrid system from sending notification to alarm channels for a scheduled period of time. This is useful for preventing noisy alerts during planned maintenance. Historically, correlating events to this time period required remembering when the maintenance occurred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the suppression window is closed, either by cancelling or allowing it to expire, two events are created. One for the scheduled start:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="alarm-suppression.png" alt="Alarm Suppression Begin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And another for the actual end time:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="alarm-suppression-end.png" alt="Alarm Suppression End">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These events are viewable at both the node and organization level to make it easy to correlate events to the maintenance window.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="override-domain-level-threshold-alerts">Override Domain Level Threshold Alerts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Threshold alerts, such as CPU % or latency, can be configured to apply to all nodes within a domain. But sometimes it is necessary for a specific node to have different thresholds defined. With this release, the domain thresholds can be overridden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you navigate to the Alerts panel of a node, you will see a section at the bottom titled Global Alerts. It will list all threshold alerts defined at the higher, domain level. Click the Override button to set a node specific value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="threshold-override.png" alt="Override">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Define a new threshold value or duration&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="threshold.png" alt="Threshold Configuration">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you click &lt;code>Save&lt;/code>, the value will have a yellow square to indicate it is an override.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="overridden-threshold.png" alt="Threshold Override">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="threshold-alerts-included-data-points">Threshold Alerts Included Data Points&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously it wasn’t always clear why a threshold alert, such as an alarm regarding latency, exceeded the configured threshold. Even if you connected immediate to the device and checked the latency might have returned to normal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the JSON payload sent to alarm &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/">channels&lt;/a> (email, Slack, PagerDuty, etc.) can include the data points used to calculate the average that exceeded the threshold. This is in a new section called &lt;code>details&lt;/code> and the values are in pairs of the timestamp &lt;code>t&lt;/code> (unix time) and value &lt;code>v&lt;/code> (in milliseconds in the example below).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="td-card card">
&lt;div class="card-header bg-white">Alert Payload&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body code p-l0 m-0">
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-JSON" data-lang="JSON">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">...&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;details&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;values&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">[&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664460&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1310&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664520&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1310&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664580&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">31&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664640&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">31&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664700&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">890&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">],&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">...&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Cluster</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/cluster/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Cluster configuration is only available for nodes that are members of a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="heartbeat">Heartbeat&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The cluster heartbeat defines a persistent connection between cluster members. The heartbeat is used to determine the health of the cluster and to determine which member is the active member. This configuration is required on cluster members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="heartbeat.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="heartbeat-host">
&lt;th>Heartbeat Host&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP (bound to an interface) on which heartbeat communication will occur&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="heartbeat-port">
&lt;th>Heartbeat Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port on which heartbeat communication will occur&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
The same interface should be selected for all cluster members
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="status-endpoint">Status Endpoint&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>(Optional) The Status Endpoint allows you to start an HTTP REST endpoint on a port on the WAN interface IP that will return a 200 response if the member is healthy and the active cluster member. This is commonly needed if a load balancer is being placed in front a cluster to provide high-availability for ZTNA or Wireguard gateway traffic.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="endpoint-ip">
&lt;th>Endpoint IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Hard set to the WAN interface IP address&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="endpoint-port">
&lt;th>Endpoint Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Defines the port that the HTTP server will listen on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If blank the HTTP server will be disabled.&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: Connectors</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Connectors are configured in conjunction with &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">services&lt;/a> to define a local listening port for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Connectors are configured under the Networking &amp;gt; Connectors tab of the node or cluster configuration section in the Trustgrid Portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="add-connector.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 45%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Add Connector dialogue
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="protocol">
&lt;th>Protocol&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>The protocol that the listener for the connector will use. Options are TCP, UDP, FTP, and TFTP.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>FTP must operate in passive mode when using L4 services and connectors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="listen-interface">
&lt;th>Listen Interface&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The interface that you want the connector to listen on. If set to &amp;ldquo;All&amp;rdquo;, the connector will listen on 0.0.0.0.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="listen-port">
&lt;th>Listen Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port that you want the connector to listen on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="remote-node">
&lt;th>Remote Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The remote node or cluster that traffic will be proxied to.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="remote-service">
&lt;th>Remote Service&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Either the friendly name of &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">service&lt;/a> that is defined on the remote node, or the IP:Port of the remote service to connect to.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="rate-limit-mb/s">
&lt;th>Rate Limit (Mb/s)&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The maximum amount of throughput that will be allowed to traverse the tunnel when connecting to the connector. This can be used to prevent saturating the connection at either the local or remote sites.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="sniff-traffic">
&lt;th>Sniff Traffic&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Listed only on the Connectors table, this will automatically launch a Sniff Traffic tool for the &lt;a href="#listen-port">listening port&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="connector-sniff-traffic.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="improved-identity-provider-integration">Improved Identity Provider Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid has supported SAML integration to manage portal access for some time. As we began supporting additional services, such as Remote Access applications, more flexibility was needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="openid-support">OpenID Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OpenID is a newer standard for managing communication between an application and an Identity Provider (IdP). It offers additional functionality compared to SAML including the ability to simplify integration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, Trustgrid supports simplified integration with Google G Suite and Microsoft AzureAD which includes the ability to synchronize groups and group members. Trustgrid will expand this functionality to other IdPs in the future but for now, other OpenID compatible IdPs can be integrated using a more generic OpenID setup process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="saml-self-service">SAML Self-Service&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid will continue to support SAML integration. Previously the setup process required the Trustgrid Support Team to complete the configuration, but now this is available to Administrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="add-users-instead-of-inviting-them">Add Users Instead of Inviting Them&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Previously&lt;/strong>, adding new users to the Trustgrid portal was a bit clunky when using the SAML integration. To add a user you would:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Invite the user. This would generate an email which the user didn’t really need.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The user would then need to successfully authenticate via the configured IdP.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You could then adjust the user&amp;rsquo;s role to reflect the appropriate permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Now&lt;/strong>, when an IdP is configured there is a simplified process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the User Management panel click “Add User”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From a single prompt, you can enter the user’s email address (matching what is configured in the Identify Provider), set their Role, and select the correct Identity Provider (if there is more than one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="add-user-modal.png" alt="Add User Modal">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The option to Invite Users is still available under Actions if you need to create users in the Trustgrid native IdP.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="domain-improvements">Domain Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the changes outlined below, it is worth noting that Domains have been moved under the Management section of the navigation bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="review-changes">Review Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid Domains encompass configuration settings that impact many nodes and clusters, such as Virtual Network Routes. The impacts of changes here can have a wide effect and it is not uncommon for multiple members of a team to be working in this context at the same time without knowing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address this Trustgrid has updated the user interface to reduce the risk of improper or conflicting changes. After a change is made within a domain it is not immediately applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Instead, a warning icon will be added to the Review Changes panel. Navigating to this panel will display all changes that are waiting to be applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The changes will include the user making the change. If more than one user has made changes they can confirm with that user if they are ready for that change to go into effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Optionally, if they determine one of the changes should not be applied it can be removed by clicking the red X. Be aware that if this is done the change would have to be recreated and reviewed to add later.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once the user has confirmed the changes look correct they can click Apply Changes. You will be prompted to confirm and then the changes will be pushed out to nodes in the domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="review-changes.png" alt="Review Changes Screen">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="improved-virtual-network-routes-table">Improved Virtual Network Routes Table&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Virtual Network Routes table has been significantly reworked in this release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest improvement is in the Destination selection method. The old interface required selecting from a long list of all nodes and clusters in the domains which became unmanageable as the number of these increased. Additionally, there was no distinguishing between nodes and clusters beyond the name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now when the Destination field is selected you are given a list (typeahead filtered) that now has a prefix of Cluster or Node to clearly identify the destination type.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, the Save and Add Routes buttons have been moved to the top of the table to reduce the need to scroll down as you work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-nat-virtual-networks">No-NAT Virtual Networks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Making Network Address Translation (NAT) easier to manage and scale has been a primary use case for Trustgrid. However, there are some situations where altering the IP addresses is unnecessary and even undesirable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address this we have added the ability to create a Virtual Network that will perform no address translation by default. This should greatly increase the ease of configuring such networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When adding a new Virtual Network set the “No NAT Mode” to Yes. For a Network CIDR just enter 0.0.0.0/0, this field will be made optional in a later release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="add-network-modal.png" alt="Add Network Modal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After creation, you will see that NO-NAT Mode is enabled in the table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="networks-table.png" alt="Networks Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever this network is attached to a Node or Cluster interface you will see a notice like the below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="no-nat-notice.png" alt="No NAT Notice">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vpn-improvements">VPN Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The VPN interface in the portal has been reworked in ways we hope will simplify the experience when configuring and managing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="feature-navigation-panels">Feature Navigation Panels&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The legacy VPN page frequently required significant scrolling to get to the most relevant section. The new interface breaks these sections into multiple panels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since Address Translation is the most commonly used section it is automatically selected when you navigate into the VPN context.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="improved-multiple-virtual-network-support">Improved Multiple Virtual Network Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid has supported Nodes and Clusters being attached to multiple Virtual Networks but the user experience interacting with them was cumbersome. For example, in a number of places, you had to select from a list of all the available virtual networks, even if they weren’t attached. This experience has been greatly improved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vpn-virtual-networks-table">VPN Virtual Networks Table&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the Node or Cluster is already attached to a single Virtual Network this will be selected automatically when you select the VPN navigation link. However, if you have multiple networks you will be presented with a table of only the attached Virtual Networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="virtual-networks-table.png" alt="Virtual Networks Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Actions dropdown of this table will enable you to Attach additional Virtual Networks or Detach the current Virtual Networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="overview-virtual-network-graph">Overview Virtual Network Graph&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously the Overview Virtual Network graph listed all Virtual Networks within a domain. Now it will only show attached networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vpn-toolbar">VPN Toolbar&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have navigated to the VPN context of a node and selected a Virtual Network you will see a bar like the below at the top of the page. The bar provides important data about the Virtual Network including the node’s Virtual Management IP (and the ability to edit it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="vpn-toolbar.png" alt="VPN Toolbar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking the Tools button on the right of the bar brings up a menu of both Virtual Network and Interface tools. Users no longer have to switch between tabs to access these different toolsets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="vpn-tools.png" alt="VPN Tools">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-virtual-translation-table-interface">New Virtual Translation Table Interface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The View Virtual Translation Table shows active NATs similar to a &lt;code>show connections&lt;/code> command from legacy solutions. Previously running this tool produced raw console output that could be challenging to work with when there were large numbers of active connections.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new version of the tools creates a paginated table that is easily searchable and can be refreshed without needing to return to the Tools section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="virtual-nats-table.png" alt="Virtual NATs Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="proxyarp-option-for-outside-nats">ProxyARP Option for Outside NATs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Previously the Trustgrid node would ARP on the local network for any IP contained in the Local CIDR of an outside NAT. For example, if your Outside NAT Local CIDR was for 192.168.1.0/24, the node would respond to ARP requests for any IP in that network (192.168.1.1 - .254).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is still the default behavior, but there is now an option to disable this functionality when configuring Outside NATs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="proxy-arp-option.png" alt="Proxy ARP Option">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-panel-improvements">Data Plane Panel Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the February 2022 release we introduced the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/">Data Plane status panel&lt;/a> for investigating connections between edge and gateway nodes. With this release we’ve added some tools to this panel. The new Ping and Test Performance tools are linked in the far right column of each gateway’s row.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="ping-test-performance.png" width="400px" />
&lt;h3 id="gateway-ping">Gateway Ping&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="gateway-ping-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>The gateway ping tool will launch a ping inside the data plane tunnel between the node and the gateway, similar to ICMP ping. This can provide a more realtime view of latency between node and gateway compared to the RTT column (only loaded on refresh) and the historical data which provides a minute by minute view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ping-output.png" alt="Ping Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gateway-performance-tool">Gateway Performance Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The gateway performance tool attempts to estimate the available upload bandwidth between a node and gateway.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="gateway-performance-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>By default this tool will attempt to send 10MB of data to the destination device. This then used to calculate the available bandwidth. Sending more data provides a more accurate estimate but be aware that other devices using the same internet circuit may experience degraded performance while the test is running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="performance-output.png" alt="Gateway Performance Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The periods are posted for about every 1MB of data sent. If you see exclamation marks this can indicate lost packets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tool-improvements">Tool Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="mtr-improvements">MTR Improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>MTR, which was &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/">recently added to the portal&lt;/a>, can be powerful troubleshooting tool, but it has many options which can be tricky for newer users. To simplify the use we’ve added a new user interface that provides graphical options for selecting common parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="mtr-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;h2 id="aws-instances-metadata">AWS Instances Metadata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When the Trustgrid software is deployed in AWS we can gather additional metadata about the underlying instance. With this release we have added the availability zone, instances type and instance ID to the Info panel available on every node.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-visor.png" alt="AWS Metadata">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timestamps-for-virtual-network-changes">Timestamps for Virtual Network Changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before changes are committed to a virtual network setting, such as the virtual network route table, they are listed in the Changes panel for approval. This made it easier to see if other users had outstanding changes that might be in conflict. However, it wasn’t clear if the other user just made that change or if it had been left accidentally. With this release we’ve added a timestamp that shows when the user saved the change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="modified-route.png" alt="Change Example">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data Plane</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/data-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/data-plane/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>The Data Plane panel shows a list of all statistics known peers, their connection status, provides tools for testing connectivity and can display statistics for the connection between the node and the peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="export-list-of-peers">Export List of Peers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can export a CSV formatted list of all peers by clicking Actions -&amp;gt; Export
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="data-plane-export.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 25%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Export button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CSV file will include columns for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Connection status (true/false)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peer name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peer IP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Path (if applicable)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RTT - Return Trip Time or latency observed when the panel was opened or refreshed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mode - TLS or TLS/UDP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type - The role of the node to peer. SERVER = gateway, CLIENT = edge device&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ports - The ports used to establish the connection&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="tools">Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The far right column as links to launch the following tools:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gateway-ping">Gateway Ping&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="gateway-ping-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>The gateway ping tool will launch a ping inside the data plane tunnel between the node and the gateway, similar to ICMP ping. This can provide a more realtime view of latency between node and gateway compared to the RTT column (only loaded on refresh) and the historical data which provides a minute by minute view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ping-output.png" alt="Ping Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gateway-performance-tool">Gateway Performance Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The gateway performance tool attempts to estimate the available &lt;strong>upload bandwidth&lt;/strong> between current node and the selected peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="gateway-performance-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>By default this tool will attempt to send 10MB of data to the destination device. This then used to calculate the available bandwidth. Sending more data provides a more accurate estimate but be aware that other devices using the same internet circuit may experience degraded performance while the test is running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="performance-output.png" alt="Gateway Performance Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The periods are posted for about every 1MB of data sent. If you see exclamation marks this can indicate lost packets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="trace-route-and-mtr">Trace Route and MTR&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Both of the links here will populate the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/interfaces/">interface tool of the same name&lt;/a> with the selected peer&amp;rsquo;s IP address and TCP port. This allows you to trace the route or run MTR diagnostics directly between the current node and the selected peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
This is most effective if run from the client/edge node to a gateway since the gateway is the only one actually listening on that port. If run in the other direction (gateway -&amp;gt; client) it is likely any firewall between will drop the connections and the client will definitely not respond on that port.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="view-latency-to-peers">View Latency to Peers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To view latency data between two nodes, select either the edge or gateway node, and then from the peers table, select the node to view.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Gateway nodes will list edge nodes in their peers table
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="peer-list.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a peer is selected, the monitoring section will populate with relevant data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="monitoring.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hop data is only available for nodes that have hop monitoring enabled. See &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/">Monitoring Network Hops to Peers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Documents</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/support/documents/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Trustgrid and customers can share documents securely in the Documents section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="documents.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adding or deleting documents requires &lt;code>documents::modify&lt;/code> permissions. Downloading and viewing documents requires &lt;code>documents::read&lt;/code> permissions.
(show how to add and delete and download a document).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: May</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="trustgrid-permissions-restructuring">Trustgrid Permissions Restructuring&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid’s portal and API have used Role based permissions to manage access within the Trustgrid system. As Trustgrid has expanded our feature set, adding features like containers, and our user base have grown the predefined role structure has become a poor fit. Many times these new features required Trustgrid Support to grant access to users. Additionally, what each role could and could not do was opaque to customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this release will be migrating to a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/">policy-based&lt;/a> approach that will allow customers to independently tailor permissions to meet their own use cases. Customers will also be able to see exactly what rights policies allow and what policy is granting a user access &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/users/#view-effective-permissions">directly in the portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This migration will also allow future enhancements such as automatic policy assignment based on group membership, resource based policies limiting users to specific nodes/clusters, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-it-works">How it Works&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The new policy permission works as such:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Users can be attached to one or more policy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Policies are defined that either allow or explicitly deny permissions or actions
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Permission are grouped according to the related feature/objects set
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Read allows a user to view that group of related objects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modify will allow users to add, change or delete those objects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Additional actions such as running tools on a node can be allowed/denied&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A denied permission will override any allowed permission in another policy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="migration-of-role-permissions-to-policies">Migration of Role Permissions to Policies&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid previously had 4 predefined roles. With this release these will be migrated into 5 new builtin policies, and an additional policy will be created. As part of this migration Trustgrid is also making sure these policies only include the “least-privileges” required to perform the intent of each of the previously defined roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the release process users previously assigned a role will be automatically assigned the corresponding policy or policies listed below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below is a list of our historic roles and the policies that replace them plus any known changes. If users previously assigned a role lose a tool or function they need, they can either be attached to a higher level builtin policy with the appropriate permissions or a custom policy can be created and attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="monitor-now-tg-builtin-monitorhahahugoshortcode-s2-hbhb-policy">Monitor (now &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-monitor">tg-builtin-monitor&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Monitor no longer has access to troubleshooting tools. These were removed because some of these seemed to exceed the privileges required for the user types expected to have this role.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="operator-now-tg-builtin-operatorhahahugoshortcode-s3-hbhb-policy">Operator (now &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-operator">tg-builtin-operator&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>No changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="node-administrator-now-tg-builtin-node-adminhahahugoshortcode-s4-hbhb-policy">Node-Administrator (now &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-node-admin">tg-builtin-node-admin&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>No changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="administrator-now-tg-builtin-adminhahahugoshortcode-s5-hbhb-and-tg-builtin-access-adminhahahugoshortcode-s6-hbhb-policy">Administrator (now &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-admin">tg-builtin-admin&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-access-admin">tg-builtin-access-admin&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The administrator role previously included both the ability to make almost all technical changes and the ability to control access and permission to the portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trustgrid determined that these functions are separate and many companies may want to further restrict the access administration to a subset of users. The functions have been split into two policies:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>builtin-tg-admin - Full access to make technical changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>builtin-tg-access-admin - Ability to add or invite users, change and attach policies, and configure Identity Providers&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, Trustgrid cannot determine who within an organization should and should not have each of these functions so during this migration any user that was previously assigned the Administrator role will be attached to both policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is highly recommended customers review which users are attached to the builtin-tg-access-admin policy and remove from those that do not require it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="provisioning-order-improvements">Provisioning Order Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="contacts-and-stakeholders">Contacts and Stakeholders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Orders historically only had fields for a general order contact and a technical contact. With this release additional stakeholders can be listed (such as a project manager associated with the project or other executive contacts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="stakeholders.png" alt="Stakeholders List">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is to eventually provide a method to send status updates to all contacts in a more automated fashion as order progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-provisioning-contacts-for-your-organization">Add Provisioning Contacts for your Organization&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you have stakeholders that will frequently be used on orders, you can add them as Contacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="contacts.png" alt="Add Contact">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These will then be available to select in the stakeholders section of an order and will auto-polulate the fields&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="add-stakeholder.png" alt="Add Stakeholder">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="activity-report">Activity Report&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="activity-report.png" alt="Activity Report">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new Activity Report will list all orders that transitioned to the selected Status during the selected Time Range and the results can be exported as a CSV. This can be useful for tracking progress of provisioning projects over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rack-mount-field-added">Rack Mount Field Added&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Some Trustgrid hardware has the option of including rack mounts. Previously this was documented in notes, but with this release a field has been added. If an appliance type does not have a rack mount option this will show as “unavailable”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="rack-mounts.png" alt="Rack Mount">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Access to the Provisioning section of the portal is not a part of a builtin policy at this time. Access admins should create policies to grant users orders permissions and attach to the appropriate users.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Docs: Node Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/flow-logs/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This page will show the most recent 1000 flow logs for the specific node being viewed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>See this page for more info on &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/">Flow Logs&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: June</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="faster-node-overview-graphs">Faster Node Overview Graphs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With this release we have reduced the time it takes for the initial Overview graphs to load when you first navigate to the node.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-time-range-selector">New Time Range Selector&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Previously the Trustgrid portal used a few different time range selectors on different pages, none of which were the most user friendly. Trustgrid is standardizing on a new selector shown below which some key new abilities:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Change from Local (browser) time zone to UTC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch from an Absolute (e.g June 1 at 10am to Jun 1 at 11am) to a Relative time (last X hours)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="time-picker.png" alt="Time Range Selector">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new selector is in use at:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Flow Logs - Advanced Search&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Plane - Gateway monitoring statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-panel-improvements">Data Plane Panel Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="data-plane-monitor-graph">Data Plane Monitor Graph&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously the statistics for latency (visible after clicking on the name of a connected gateway) were shown in three separate graphs: min, max, and mean. This sometimes made it hard to compare as they had different scales. Now these data points are visible on a single graph. They can also be deselected with the graph scale adjusting automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tunnel-latency.png" alt="Tunnel Latency Graph">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sort-peers-by-connected-status">Sort Peers by Connected Status&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously the connected status column didn’t allow you to sort. If you had a lot of connected peers and wanted to focus on disconnected ones it was a challenge. Now you can sort by clicking on the column header.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="node-location-tab">Node Location Tab&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a new Location panel under History on the node detail page. This page allows you to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Specify the Latitude and Longitude of used to display the location of the node on the network map. You can utilize a map such as Google Maps to determine these coordinates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specify the City, State, Country and Zip where the node is deployed. Currently this is for informational purposes only and does not update the Lat/Long coordinates.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="location-form.png" alt="Location View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flow-log-improvements">Flow Log Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the new time range selector, we have also improved how advanced searches return results. Previously, if your search included a long time range or was run on a node with a lot of flows the system could return partial results. Now we’ve added a “Load More” button and additional results will be returned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="load-more-button.png" alt="Load More Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="access-policy-improvements">Access Policy Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We’ve added several improvements to the Access Policy table for a virtual network.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can now select and bulk delete rules&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New special destination object options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>private&lt;/code> - all IP v4 blocks defined as private by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Private_network#Private_IPv4_addresses">RFC 1918&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>public&lt;/code> - public will cover all other IP v4 addresses&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Gateway</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/gateway/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Gateway nodes accept TLS tunnel connections from other nodes in the domain. They are responsible for routing traffic between nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Gateways are only configurable at the node level. Configuring a gateway requires &lt;code>nodes::configure:gateway&lt;/code> permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gateway-types">Gateway Types&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A gateway can be one of three types:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>public&lt;/code> - allows all connections from edge nodes in the domain&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>private&lt;/code> - allows only allow-listed clients to connect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>hub&lt;/code> - allows connections from edge nodes and other gateway nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A public gateway should be secured with a firewall to prevent unauthorized access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Navigate to a node and select &lt;code>Gateway&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>System&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="server-settings">Server Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="public-config.png" alt="input table with all Trustgrid gateway server options" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 90%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Gateway Server settings
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="status">
&lt;th>Status&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Either &lt;code>Enabled&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Disabled&lt;/code> - when enabled, the node will listen and accept connections from other nodes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="udp-enabled">
&lt;th>UDP Enabled&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Whether to allow UDP tunnels to be established through this gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="public-ip-or-dns">
&lt;th>Public IP or DNS&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The public IP or DNS name of the gateway. This is the address that other nodes will use to connect to this gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="port">
&lt;th>Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port that the gateway will listen on. This is the port that other nodes will use to connect to this gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="udp-port">
&lt;th>UDP Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port that the gateway will listen on for UDP tunnels. This is the port that other nodes will use to connect to this gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="max-ingress-mbps">
&lt;th>Max Ingress Mbps&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The ingress bandwidth limit for the gateway. Connections will be throttled when this limit is reached.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="certificate">
&lt;th>Certificate&lt;/th>
&lt;td>When using DNS for gateway connections, you may specify an uploaded [certificate]({{ ref &amp;ldquo;/docs/certificate&amp;rdquo; }}) to use for TLS connections.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="gateway-type">
&lt;th>Gateway Type&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The type of gateway. See &lt;a href="#gateway-types">Gateway Types&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="monitor-network-hops-to-peers">
&lt;th>Monitor Network Hops to Peers&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Whether to monitor latency to peers through this gateway. This can have a performance impact and is not recommended for high-traffic gateways.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="gateway-clients">Gateway Clients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Private gateways only allow connectivity from listed and enabled clients. To add a client, use the typeahead textbox at the bottom of the clients table and select the desired node.
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="client">
&lt;th>Client&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Name of a node that should connect to this private gateway&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="enabled">
&lt;th>Enabled&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Values are Enabled &lt;em>(default)&lt;/em> or Disabled. If set to Enabled the client node will attempt to connect.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="client-settings">Client Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Settings in this section define how the node connects to gateway servers as a client&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="clients.png" alt="table of gateway client settings" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 90%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Gateway client settings
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="max-egress-mbps">
&lt;th>Max Egress Mbps&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The egress bandwidth limit for the gateway. Connections will be throttled when this limit is reached.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="gateway-paths">Gateway Paths&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Allows you to define alternate paths to a gateway server&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>A name for the path.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="gateway-node">
&lt;th>Gateway Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Gateway for which the path is applicable.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="host-ip">
&lt;th>Host IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Destination IP address for the path.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="host-port">
&lt;th>Host Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Destination port for the path.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="local-ip">
&lt;th>Local IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Use this local IP as the source IP for the connection to the gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="use-as-default">
&lt;th>Use as Default&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>True - Will not attempt to connect to the configured Gateway Node using the WAN interface IP and Default Gateway path.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>False - Will attempt to connect to the Gateway node using both this defined path &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> the WAN Interface IP and Default Gateway path.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="gateway-tools">Gateway Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To see detailed messages about gateway traffic, select the &lt;code>Troubleshoot Gateway Traffic&lt;/code> option from the services menu under &lt;code>Gateway Tools&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="launch-troubleshoot-gateway-traffic.png" alt="Troubleshoot gateway Traffic dialog with options of Local, Peer and Service" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Troubleshoot Gateway Traffic dialog
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This will open a new window with live diagnostic messages about traffic&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="troubleshoot-gateway-traffic.png" alt="terminal output showing gateway log messages between two Trustgrid nodes" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Output of Troubleshoot Gateway tool
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="tag-improvements">Tag Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two major improvements regarding tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cluster-members-inherit-tags">Cluster Members Inherit Tags&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously you had to set tags at the node and cluster level which required a lot of duplicate effort. Now when you configure tags at the cluster level the member nodes inherit this tag.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tags-searchable-in-the-nodes-table">Tags Searchable in the Nodes Table&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With this release if you add a tag as a column to the nodes table, you can then search the table for matching values.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nodes-table-improvements">Nodes Table Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two new columns can be added to the nodes table:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="virtual-management-ip-column">Virtual Management IP Column&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now see from the table the virtual management IP assigned to each node. If you have multiple virtual networks you will have the option to select each network as a column. These columns have the prefix &lt;code>MGMT IP:&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="available-columns.png" alt="Available Columns">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="device-type-column">Device Type Column&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now see what type of device, physical or virtual, is running the node software.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="generic-webhook-support-as-an-alert-channel">Generic Webhook Support as an Alert Channel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This version adds the ability to publish alerts to a channel utilizing a generic webhook. This should allow integration with additional systems beyond the built-in channels Trustgrid supports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To utilize either edit an existing channel or create a new one and populate the Generic Webhook section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="generic-webhook.png" alt="Generic Webhook">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="provisioning-improvements">Provisioning Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There have been several changes to the Provisioning (formerly Orders) section of the Portal including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Due Dates for Orders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for specific device models (as opposed to just hardware vs virtual)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/august/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="resource-scoped-permission-policies">Resource-Scoped Permission Policies&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/">May 2022 release&lt;/a> enabled the creation of more granular permissions policies. With this release we’ve added the ability to grant permissions to specific &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> resources. This enables you to limit a user to only see specific devices with very limited permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Polices now have a &lt;code>Resources&lt;/code> section. This can be populated with a list of Trustgrid Resource Names (TGRN) to limit where the defined permissions are applied. See the documentation on &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#resource-scoped-policies">Resource-Scoped Polices&lt;/a> for more info.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="monitor-network-hops">Monitor Network Hops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid has add a troubleshooting feature to collect traceroute like data on a regular basis. When enabled a node will collect 3 samples a minute and store the data in the cloud. This data will assist in determining the source of packet loss or high latency between devices. See &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/">Monitoring Network Hops to Peers&lt;/a> to learn more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-hops.png" alt="Network Hops">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="show-isp-and-asn-for-public-ip">Show ISP and ASN for Public IP&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid now uses our IP geolocation database provider to supply the internet service provider (ISP) and autonomous system number (ASN) associated with the public IP of nodes. This info is visible under History → Location, listed under the IP-Derived Info panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="asn-isp.png" alt="ISP and ASN">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It should be noted the accuracy of this information varies between ISPs&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="identity-provider-idp-logins-in-authentication-audits">Identity Provider (IdP) Logins in Authentication Audits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Previously, the logs under the Operations → Authentication Audits only displayed logins using the Trustgrid native authentication provider. If you were using an IdP you would need to review the providers logs to see when users logged in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this release we now display IdP portal logins the same way native logins are reported.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Infovisor</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/infovisor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/infovisor/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The infovisor displays details about the Trustgrid node and can be displayed by clicking the Info button in the top right or hitting the backtick &lt;code>`&lt;/code> key.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="info-button.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 25%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Button to open Infovisor
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It contains information such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Control and Data Plane Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public IP - This is the IP observed by the Trustgrid Control plane as the source IP by traffic from the node&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Version and Package Version - The Trustgrid software version running on the node&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/">Enabled / Disabled Status&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device Type&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Operating System (OS) Version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/#trustgrid-resource-names-or-tgrn">TGRN or Trustgrid Resource Name&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/tags/">Tags&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On AWS Nodes additional information is reported based on the metadata service
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Availability Zone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Instance ID&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Instance type&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="infovisor.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example infovisor
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Docs: Interfaces</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/interfaces/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="network-interfaces">Network Interfaces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Navigate to a node, then select &lt;code>Interfaces&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="interfaces.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 90%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Interfaces panel
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>Interface&lt;/code> dropdown at the top allows you to select which interface to manage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="select-interface.png" alt="Interface Dropdown">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="eth0---wan-interface">ETH0 - WAN Interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This interface is always used to build the outbound TLS tunnels for control and data plane connectivity. If the node is deployed in a single interface configuration, this interface will also be used for local network connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="eth---lan-interface">ETH# - LAN Interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Used in configurations with more than one interface for local network connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vlan-subinterface">VLAN Subinterface&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Virtual under a physical LAN interface that will apply a VLAN tag to traffic&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="hardware-address">
&lt;th>Hardware Address&lt;/th>
&lt;td>MAC address of the interface.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="interface-name">
&lt;th>Interface Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Name assigned to the interface by the operating system. This varies between hardware models and is sometimes needed when using tools such as Sniff Interface or reviewing logs.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="interface-vrf">
&lt;th>Interface VRF&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Selects to which &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vrfs/">VRF&lt;/a> the interface is attached.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="vlan-id-subinterfaces-only">
&lt;th>VLAN ID (Subinterfaces Only)&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Sets the VLAN ID/tag for the subinterface.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ip-assignment-eth0-only">
&lt;th>IP Assignment (ETH0 only)&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>DHCP - requires a DHCP server or relay in the same broadcast domain as the interface connection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Static - configured using the fields below&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ipv4-address-cidr">
&lt;th>IPv4 Address CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>IP address using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classless_Inter-Domain_Routing">classless inter-domain routing (CIDR) notation&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="gateway-ip">
&lt;th>Gateway IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ETH0 - The IP address of the default gateway for this device. All traffic not in the same network as an interface IP or with a specified route will use this gateway.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ETH1 - This is only used in a 2-interface setup to access local resources outside the interface&amp;rsquo;s configured network. Routes must be defined.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dns-server-1/2-ip-eth0-only">
&lt;th>DNS Server 1/2 IP (ETH0 only)&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Used to resolve DNS names to connect to the Trustgrid control plane.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="cluster-virtual-ip">
&lt;th>Cluster Virtual IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Used in &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">clusters&lt;/a>, this IP address is moved between member nodes based on the active cluster member. It can be used to route traffic between the virtual and local networks. This IP address can only be changed within the cluster interfaces page.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="auto-negotiation">
&lt;th>Auto-Negotiation&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Sets if the interface will use auto-negotiation to determine the speed and duplex settings. Values can be AUTO &lt;em>(default)&lt;/em> or MANUAL.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="duplex">
&lt;th>Duplex&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Locked unless Auto-Negotiation set to MANUAL. Sets the interface to either FULL &lt;em>(default)&lt;/em> or HALF duplex&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="speed">
&lt;th>Speed&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Locked unless Auto-Negotiation set to MANUAL. Sets the interface to 10, 100, 1000 Mbps.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ignore-health-check">
&lt;th>Ignore Health Check&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Value can be Disable &lt;em>(default)&lt;/em> or Enable. If set to Enable, the interface&amp;rsquo;s link status will no longer be used by the node to determine its &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/#cluster-member-health-conditions">cluster member health state&lt;/a>. Useful if a single node has a network connection it&amp;rsquo;s peer does not such as an alternate WAN path.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="interface-routes">Interface Routes&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If the node is part of a cluster, these must be configured at the cluster level&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These routes are used to access networks that are not in the same network as a configured interface &lt;strong>and that are not accessed using the default gateway IP configured for ETH0 - WAN Interface&lt;/strong>. It is rare to need to define these on the ETH0 interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the interface from the Network Interface dropdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;code>+ Add Entry&lt;/code> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enter the route information There are three fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="destination-cidr">
&lt;th>Destination CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>This is the CIDR notation of the network or host that needs to be routed. For a single host, use /32 as the CIDR suffix.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="next-hop">
&lt;th>Next Hop&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP address to which traffic destined for the above defined network will be sent. No CIDR suffix is needed.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Optional field to provide additional information about the route.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the green check &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check" style="color: green;">&lt;/i> to confirm the route.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Repeat steps 2-4 with any additional routes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;code>Save&lt;/code> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="additional-ips">Additional IPs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IP address entries added to the list below will be bound to the current interface.
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Only visible on LAN interfaces and Subinterfaces
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advanced-network-settings">Advanced Network Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="dark-mode">
&lt;th>Dark Mode&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Value can be Disable &lt;em>(default)&lt;/em> or Enable. When set to Enable the node will restrict ICMP responses so that it will not respond to ICMP (Ping) echo requests or respond to failed TCP/UDP connection attempts with reset or ICMP Destination Port Unreachable&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: September</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="container--improvements">Container Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid has greatly enhanced the container features we support and this release makes these features available to all users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="container-management">Container Management&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now stop and start individual containers running as a service from within the portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="stop-start-buttons.png" alt="Stop Start Buttons">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="container-volumes-and-mounts">Container Volumes and Mounts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Containers on Trustgrid now support creating persistent volumes and mounting them within the container. These volumes can even be encrypted using Trustgrid managed, software-based encryption.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="container-privileges">Container Privileges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is now possible to run containers as a privileged user or specify the user/group the container should execute as. Additionally, you can add or drop Linux capabilities that the container has enabled on execution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="import-container-configuration">Import Container Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Container configurations can end up complex. Recreating on many nodes is tedious and error prone. Trustgrid now supports importing the configuration from an existing node or cluster that has the container defined as desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interactive-tools-improvements">Interactive Tools Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="terminate-running-tools-without-closing-window">Terminate Running Tools without Closing Window&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Interactive tools such as Terminal and Sniff Traffic now support terminating the session without closing the window. This can be useful in situations, such as if sniffing traffic on a very active node, where you want to be able to stop the tool but still be able to analyze the output.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="traffic-capture-tool-improvements">Traffic Capture Tool Improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Traffic Capture tool now displays the settings used while running. This includes the interface and filter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="capture-settings.png" alt="Capture Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="provisioning-and-order-management-improvements">Provisioning and Order Management Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Provisioning section of the Trustgrid portal has been extensively overhauled to improve the order management experience and make future improvements easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-look">New Look&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The first change you’ll notice is that clicking Provisioning opens a new tab. The orders table now makes it easier to search and filter the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The individual order screen is now a single page view to reduce the need to switch between tabs. And orders now support attaching files such as legacy device configurations or diagrams that might be useful for configuring the new devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="order-notifications">Order Notifications&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now configure &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/">Alarm Filters&lt;/a> for four new order based events:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Order Created&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Order Commented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Order Status Change&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Order Customer Update&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These events can then be sent to existing or newly defined &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/channels/">channels&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Changing Node Status (Enabling / Disabling)</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Trustgrid nodes can be in two states:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Enabled - In this state the node will connected to the Trustgrid Control Plane and any Data Plane gateways the node is configured to use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled - This is a reduced functionality state that cause the node to only attempt to connect to the Trustgrid control plane. It can be managed to a limited extent but many other Trustgrid features will not function in this state&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Disabling a node allows for additional security if a device is in transport and can also be used as an easily reversible way of verifying a node is no longer in use before fully deleting the node.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Changing the node status will trigger a restart of the Trustgrid node service.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="disablingenabling-from-info-tab">Disabling/Enabling from Info Tab&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If disabling or enabling a single node you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to that node in the Trustgrid portal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Info&lt;/strong> tab by clicking the dropdown in the top-right, or hitting the &lt;code>`&lt;/code> key.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the Status dropdown change to Disable or Enable
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="info-tab-status.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 70%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Info tab with Status dropdown
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="disablingenabling-from-nodes-table">Disabling/Enabling from Nodes Table&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If disabling or enabling multiple nodes it is easier to do so from the Nodes table&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to the nodes table.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Use the search box to filter the displayed nodes.
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Note that if you change this any selected nodes will be de-selected.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the checkbox on the left to select the nodes you wish to disable or enable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the Actions dropdown select either &lt;strong>Enable&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Disable&lt;/strong>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="nodes-table-status.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Status actions on Nodes table
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="disablingenabling-via-terraform">Disabling/Enabling via Terraform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nodes can be enabled or disabled via the Trustgrid published Terraform provider using the &lt;a href="https://registry.terraform.io/providers/trustgrid/tg/latest/docs/resources/node_state/" target="_blank">tg_node_state&lt;/a> resource.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The Trustgrid API refers to this state via the &lt;code>status&lt;/code> attribute. The value &lt;code>ACTIVE&lt;/code> means the node is &lt;strong>enabled&lt;/strong> and the value &lt;code>INACTIVE&lt;/code> indicates the node is currently &lt;strong>disabled&lt;/strong>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Network Objects</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>A network object allows naming a CIDR inside a VPN for easier rule management.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A network object requires the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The label to use when referencing this object.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="cidr">
&lt;th>CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Specifically an IPv4 CIDR.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-objects.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple network objects may be clustered into a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/">network group&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: October</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="cluster-improvements">Cluster Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="cluster-site-health-state">Cluster Site Health State&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With this release we introduce the concept of &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/cluster-health/">Cluster Site Health State&lt;/a>. This addition makes it more obvious when there is an issue with a cluster at a site and possible to configure &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alarm-filters/">alarm filters&lt;/a> to notify your team when changes occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We display the cluster health on the list view:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="cluster-list.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>And on the cluster overview:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="td-card-deck card-deck mb-4">
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Unhealthy notice on cluster overview
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="cluster-unhealthy-notice.png" alt="cluster unhealthy notice">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Offline notice on cluster overview
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="cluster-offline-notice.png" alt="cluster offline notice">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="cluster-status-endpoint">Cluster Status Endpoint&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When placing a load balancer in front of a Trustgrid cluster it is necessary to give the load balancer a way to determine which node is active so that it can send the traffic appropriately. We’ve added an optional HTTP endpoint that will listen on cluster members but will only return a 200 code on the active member of the cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is now a new section under System → Cluster for cluster members where you can define the port on which the node will listen. This endpoint will always listen on the WAN interface IP.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="status-endpoint.png" width="600px" />
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Requires node version 20220808 or newer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="enable-different-interface-routes-for-cluster-members">Enable Different Interface Routes for Cluster Members&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Traditionally, cluster members share the interface routes configured at the cluster level. This is usually desirable, but certain situations can require each member to have a different route defined. For example, If you have deployed your cluster members in different AWS Availability Zones for redundancy and you have the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/#cluster-heartbeat-communication">heartbeat communication&lt;/a> on a LAN interface each would need a different route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this release you will see the ability to “Add Entry” for additional routes under the LAN interface section of cluster members. You will also see a read-only entry with a blue square for any cluster-defined route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="interface-routes.png" alt="interface routes">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-panel-improvements">Data Plane Panel Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="easier-peer-selection">Easier Peer Selection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously, to select a node in the data plane peers table you had to click exactly on the node’s name. Now, you can click anywhere in the name box.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="display-data-plane-stats-for-gateways">Display Data Plane Stats for Gateways&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Prior to this release we only displayed Tunnel Latency and &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/">Network Hops&lt;/a> (when enabled) on edge node devices. With this release you can now navigate to a gateway’s data plane panel and select a client edge node. The data displayed is based on the edge node’s perspective but can still provide useful information on the state of the connection between devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-improvements">Other Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="flow-log-advanced-search-by-tcp-flags">Flow Log Advanced Search by TCP Flags&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Flow Log Advanced Search now has the ability to search for TCP flows with specified TCP flags. In the TCP Flag section just click the flags that you want to search for and the matching flows will be returned. If multiple flags are selected, only flows with all matching flags will be returned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flow-logs-search.png" alt="advanced search">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="node-audits-shows-node-version-changes">Node Audits Shows Node Version Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When a node is upgraded and successfully reconnects, the Node Audits section will display the new and previous versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="audits.png" alt="audits">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="swagger-api-improvements">Swagger API Improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A number of new areas are now documented in our public swagger documentation: &lt;a href="https://portal.trustgrid.io/api-docs/">https://portal.trustgrid.io/api-docs/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new sections include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Additional Audit endpoints&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Container and VM configuration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ZTNA Gateway&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: October Second Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="order-management-improvements">Order Management Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This release is primarily focused on making improvements to our order management system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="notification-of-changes-in-open-orders">Notification of Changes in Open Orders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously if more than one user was making changes to the same order it was possible the second user to save would overwrite the changes of the first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the system will notify you if someone has changed an order while you have it open. You would then need to refresh the page to see the changes made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="priority-field">Priority Field&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Orders can now be assigned a priority of Normal, High or Urgent. This will be reflected in the Orders table by changing the color of the summary to yellow for High priority and red for Urgent.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="td-card-deck card-deck mb-4">
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Order priority menu
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="priority-field.png" alt="priority field">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Example &lt;code>High&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Urgent&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>Normal&lt;/code> priority order summaries
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="priority-list.png" alt="priority summaries">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="support-for-hyperlinks">Support for Hyperlinks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now add Hyperlinks within an order to provide support documentation on the configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Hyperlink Form
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="hyperlinks.png" alt="hyperlink form">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="in-production-orders-moved-to-closed">“In Production” Orders moved to Closed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now when an order’s status is changed to &lt;code>In Production&lt;/code>, it will appear in the &lt;code>Closed&lt;/code> page of orders. This will make is easier to see how many open orders are in process.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="orders-search.png" width="200px"/>
&lt;h2 id="other-improvements">Other Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="advanced-flow-log-search-history">Advanced Flow Log Search History&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now load a history of your previous Advanced Flow Log searches by clicking the history tab to the right. You can then choose to reload a prior search’s parameters by clicking the apply button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flow-log-history.png" alt="Flow Log Search">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="events-table-search">Events Table Search&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Events table now has a search field that will filter the events shown. This has been added both at the Node Detail Events page and under Operation to see events across all nodes in the org.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="events.png" alt="Events Table Search">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: October Third Release</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/october-3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="repository-performance-improvements">Repository Performance Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This release includes a significant overhaul of the the repository control plane service. This service is responsible for providing upgrade packages and pushing/pulling container images.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-stats-for-private-and-hub-gateways">Data Plane Stats for Private and Hub Gateways&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prior to this release, viewing the Data Plane stats such as tunnel latency and [network hops](https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/gateway-tools/monitoring-network-hops-to-peers/ would not display. These stats will now be displayed the just like edge and public gateway stats.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="changing-configured-master-active-logging">Changing Configured Master (Active) Logging&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With this release, if a user changes which node is configured as the master (active) member of the cluster it will be logged on &lt;code>Changes&lt;/code> for the cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row;">
&lt;div style="width: 25%;">
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Changing the configured master (active) node
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="set-active.png" alt="set active">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div style="width: 75%;">
&lt;div class="td-card card mb-4">
&lt;div class="card-header">
Change entry for active member change
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;img src="changes.png" alt="change list">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Review Node Events</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/review-node-events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/review-node-events/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When troubleshooting a problem on edge or gateway nodes, reviewing node events can provide critical information about the nature of the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Choose the node that may be causing the problem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to &lt;code>Events&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Look for any critical problems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-alerts.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more issues involving multiple nodes, review [Domain Node Events](need link for this).&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Choose the &lt;code>Operations&lt;/code> tab&lt;/li>
&lt;li>View &lt;code>Events&lt;/code> across the organization&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="alerts-page.png" alt="img">
Types]](https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/event-types/)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: December</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-status-table">Data Plane Status Table&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Previously Trustgrid had a visual indicator on the Node detail page to show the Data Plane health of a node, but it only showed the state as &lt;code>Connected&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Degraded&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Disconnected&lt;/code>. While connected and disconnected were clear, there was little information on why the status was Degraded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this release hovering over the Data Plane status icon will bring up a pop-up screen showing all the peers and and their connection status. Additionally, if the peer is connected it will show:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The public IP of the peer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The mode used to connect to with the peer (TLS or UDP)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The route trip time (RTT) between the devices when the tool was last run.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This data can be searched and refreshed. In a future release we will make historical RTT time viewable for each peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="data-plane-hover.png" alt="Data Plane Status">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flow-log-improvements">Flow Log Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flow logs provide valuable metadata about traffic across Trustgrid networks but our search had performance and reliability issues that made it difficult to use. With this release we’ve rearchitected how search these logs to allow for a significant performance improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improved-ip-geolocation-data">Improved IP Geolocation Data&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid has changed our public IP geolocation data providers to improve the accuracy of the information we use to place nodes on our Network Maps. This new provider will also allow us to present additional information such as ISP and ASN in the future, which could be handy for identifying when multiple devices from the same ISP or ASN start having issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="custom-portal-roles">Custom Portal Roles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid is working on moving our permission structure beyond the four default roles (Monitor, Operator, Node-Administrator and Administrator) to allow customers to tailor roles to just the permissions their users need. For example, you could allow a user Monitor (read-only) permissions to most of the Trustgrid environment but grant them the ability to stop and start containers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently this requires working with Trustgrid Support to define these new roles but once defined they can be assigned by Node Administrators and Administrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-improvements">Other Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can now search the Nodes table for Management IPs and Device types&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed a broken link in the new user invite email for customers without IDP integration&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Location</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/location/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Trustgrid uses each node&amp;rsquo;s public IP address to derive location information. If it&amp;rsquo;s incorrect, the fields can be set manually. If set manually, IP changes will not update the node&amp;rsquo;s location when viewed from the nodes table or the network map.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-location.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="to-change-the-node-location">To change the Node Location:&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>Change the details to desired settings then click &lt;code>Save&lt;/code> when done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Submit a Support Request</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/submit-support-request/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/submit-support-request/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Trustgrid support is available 24/7/365 with a commitment to respond to any Emergency Support request within 30 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="to-contact-support">To contact support:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Email: &lt;a href="mailto:support@trustgrid.io">support@trustgrid.io&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Phone: 888-308-8995 x2&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="authorized-support">Authorized Support&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid can only provide support to customers with a Trustgrid Portal account commensurate with the account&amp;rsquo;s permission level in the portal. To receive support the user must be able to respond to an email at the account&amp;rsquo;s email address in the portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="enable-support-for-trustgrid">Enable Support for Trustgrid&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid customers can prohibit Support access to Nodes in the Portal. It may be required to enable this support to resolve certain issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Overview</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/overview/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="stats">Stats&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Node overview page shows performance and network traffic data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Supported time windows are selectable at the top. VPN and network statistics can be targeted to specific virtual networks and interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-overview.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-overview2.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="node-performance">
&lt;th>Node Performance&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows CPU, disk, and memory usage percentages&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="vpn-traffic-volume">
&lt;th>VPN Traffic Volume&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows data usage sent and received, across all VPNs and for the selected virtual network&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="traffic-volume">
&lt;th>Traffic Volume&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows data sent and receives, across all interfaces and for the selected interface&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="connected-peers">
&lt;th>Connected Peers&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows the number of other nodes connected. This will change based on the node type - gateways connect to all edge nodes, while edge nodes only connect to gateways.(LINK HUB GATEWAY PAGE WHEN DOCUMENTED)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="vpn-flows">
&lt;th>VPN Flows&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows new and active flows, across all VPNs and for the selected virtual network&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="tcp-errors">
&lt;th>TCP Errors&lt;/th>
&lt;td>shows TCP errors across all interfaces&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Support Responsibility Matrix</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/support-responsibility-matrix/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>The matrix below defines the primary responsible party for troubleshooting and resolving different types of issues. Trustgrid support can be engaged to assist in resolving issues not directly in scope of their responsibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="organization-and-roles">Organization and Roles&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="trustgrid">Trustgrid&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid is a software and services provider that operates a multi-tenant cloud management system and assists customers and end-users with the deployment and management of a data transfer plane.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="customer">Customer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Customers have a direct, contractual relationship with Trustgrid to utilize Trustgrid’s software and services. Depending on the contractual relationship with Trustgrid, Customers may also assume the role and responsibilities of End Users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="end-user">End-User&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>End Users own and operate a physical, virtual or cloud environment in which the Trustgrid software may be installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="terminology">Terminology&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="trustgrid-management-portal">
&lt;th>Trustgrid Management Portal&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Cloud-based system used to remotely manage, monitor, and configure Trustgrid Nodes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="trustgrid-node">
&lt;th>Trustgrid Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Appliance running Trustgrid’s software to facilitate Trustgrid Connect, EdgeCompute, and RemoteAccess services. These appliances could be deployed on physical devices or as virtual machines. The appliance consists of the Trustgrid software and the underlying operating system (OS).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="customer-site">
&lt;th>Customer Site&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Site with Trustgrid node(s) deployed and managed by the Customer.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="end-user-site">
&lt;th>End-User Site&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Site with Trustgrid node(s) deployed and managed by the End-User.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="support-matrix">Support Matrix&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Issue Type&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Trustgrid&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Customer&lt;/th>
&lt;th>End-User&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Trustgrid software or operating system issues&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Control Plane Connectivity&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared - Customer Site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared - End-User Site&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Data Plane Connectivity&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Limited&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Data Plane Performance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shared&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Power and physical network connectivity for Trustgrid Appliance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - Customer Site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - End-User Site&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Internet Service&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - Customer Site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - End-User Site&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Internet Side Firewall&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - Customer Site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - End-User Site&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Local networking including switching and firewall&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - Customer Site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Full - End-User Site&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>Trustgrid can work with the Customer and End-User to confirm that the Trustgrid system is working as expected and provide additional information to aid in troubleshooting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tier-one-support">Tier One Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The customer’s support team should be the end-user’s first point of contact. Trustgrid’s standard support contract makes the customer responsible for performing tier one support tasks prior to escalating Trustgrid Support. This includes contacting end-user technical resources as needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example tasks include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Troubleshooting offline Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changing Trustgrid node IP addresses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adding, modifying and testing NATs on Edge devices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modifying interface and domain routes, including facilitating failover between sites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabling and removing nodes, clusters and related configuration (e.g. routes) when no longer needed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Note: Some of the above services are managed by Trustgrid Professional Services during initial deployment
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Repositories</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/repositories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/repositories/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="list-view">List View&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid provides a fully managed private container registry. Uploaded container images may be viewed by navigating to Repositories in the portal:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="list-view.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users can push and pull containers from the repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="docker-login">Docker Login&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To authenticate with the registry, use the command provided at the bottom of the repositories view. Authentication lasts approximately 24 hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="container-namespace">Container Namespace&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Each customer is isolated to their own container namespace. To upload or download a container, it must be named with your namespace as a prefix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="name-space.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, to push a tomcat container to your registry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>docker tag tomcat:latest docker.trustgrid.io/namespace.trustgrid.io/tomcat:latest docker push docker.trustgrid.io/namespace.trustgrid.io/tomcat:latest&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="container-repo-view">Container Repo View&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Each repository can be managed. Clicking into a container will show its uploaded tags and digests, as well as the URI that can be used to pull the container.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="node-container-auth">Node Container Auth&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trustgrid nodes authenticate automatically with the Trustgrid container registry and can pull any image uploaded to the registry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Services</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Services are configured in conjunction with &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/">connectors&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vpn/port-forwarding/">port forwards&lt;/a> to define a host (IP or DNS) and port to connect to for layer 4 (L4) connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Services define the host name or IP and port of a server that can be accessed by the Trustgrid node (or members of the cluster) where it is defined. Remote clients can then access the service via peer nodes using &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/">connectors&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vpn/port-forwarding/">VPN port forwards&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="functionality">Functionality&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the local network, a connection&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>source IP&lt;/strong> will be the node&amp;rsquo;s interface IP.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If the service is defined on a cluster, the active cluster members IP will be used.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the node has multiple interfaces, the source will be the interface that has a matching &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/interfaces/#interface-routes">interface route&lt;/a> for the target IP.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If the service&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="#host">host field&lt;/a> is set to a DNS name, the node will use its WAN interface DNS servers to resolve the address.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Services are configured under the Networking &amp;gt; Services panel of the node or cluster configuration section in the Trustgrid Portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="service.png" alt="Dialogue to add a service with fields for enabled" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Add Service dialogue
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="enabled">
&lt;th>Enabled&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Values: Yes or No. Allows each service to be individually disabled if desired&amp;quot;&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="protocol">
&lt;th>Protocol&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>The protocol of the service to connect to. Options are TCP, UDP, FTP, and TFTP, along with pre-defined default ports for RDP, SSH, and VNC.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>FTP must operate in passive mode when using L4 services and connectors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="service-name">
&lt;th>Service Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>A friendly name for the service that will be used in the Remote Service field of a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/connectors/">connector&lt;/a>. Can only contain letters, numbers, and the &lt;code>-&lt;/code> character.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="host">
&lt;th>Host&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP or DNS address of the host to connect to.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="port">
&lt;th>Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port to connect to on the host.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(Optional) User friendly description of the service.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="test-connectivity">
&lt;th>Test Connectivity&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Show only on the Services table for TCP Protocol services. When clicked, the client node will attempt a TCP port connection to the configured host and port and display success or failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="service-test-connectivity.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: Thresholds</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/thresholds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/thresholds/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Thresholds provide a way to trigger events when different measurements exceed a given value. Thresholds configured at the node level can override &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/thresholds/">Domain Thresholds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To view and configure thresholds, a user will need &lt;code>nodes::configure::thresholds&lt;/code> permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigate to a node, and click &lt;code>Thresholds&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>System&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="list.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that overridden thresholds have a yellow square icon next to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="load-thresholds">Load Thresholds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Load thresholds measure the health of the node itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The name of the threshold. This will be available in generated events.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="telemetry">
&lt;th>Telemetry&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The metric to monitor. Options are CPU usage (%), memory usage (%), disk usage (%), and embryonic flows (absolute count).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="threshold">
&lt;th>Threshold&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The value that must be exceeded for an event to be generated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="duration">
&lt;th>Duration&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The time period to measure. If the threshold is exceeded for this duration, an event will be generated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="network-thresholds">Network Thresholds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Network thresholds measure the health of the network from the node&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The name of the threshold. This will be available in generated events.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="telemetry">
&lt;th>Telemetry&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The metric to monitor. Options are latency (ms), bandwidth in (Mbps), and bandwidth out (Mbps).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="threshold">
&lt;th>Threshold&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The value that must be exceeded for an event to be generated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="duration">
&lt;th>Duration&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The time period to measure. If the threshold is exceeded for this duration, an event will be generated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="target">
&lt;th>Target&lt;/th>
&lt;td>For latency, target node to measure the latency to. For bandwidth measurements, the interface to measure the bandwidth on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Debug Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/debug-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/ops-logs/debug-logs/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-debug-logs">What are debug logs?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Debug log files contain detailed technical information about the operation of a Trustgrid node. They are useful for Trustgrid support engineers to troubleshoot issues. If your node is experiencing problems, generating logs at that time may help identify the root cause.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="generating-log-files">Generating Log Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Debug Log button is located in the top right of a Node Details page.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="debug-logs-button.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 30%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Debug Logs button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Debug Log dialogue will show any previously generated log files. Clicking the Fetch Newest Logs
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="debug-logs-fetch.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Debug Logs dialogue and fetch button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
A node must be online and connected to the Trustgrid control plane to generate and publish new logs.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the node has completed compressing and uploading the logs a new entry will appear. Clicking the Download button will pull down the zip filed to your local system.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="debug-logs-new.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Download button next to newly generated file
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Trustgrid support will have access to the same files, it is not necessary to download and send the file to the support team. Just note the time it was generated.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
At this time the zip file generated by the node is incompatible with the decompress utility built into Windows operating systems. Use of a 3rd party compression utility such as 7zip is required to decompress.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="log-files">Log Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There a multiple types of logs that are included in the generated zip file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="node-appliance-log-files">Node Appliance Log Files&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Files are gathered from the following directories:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>/var/log/trustgrid - These logs are generated by the node service as part of normal operations and upgrades. These are the most commonly used by Trustgrid support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>/var/log/unattended-upgrades - These logs are generated by the operating system during upgrades and can be useful when troubleshooting failed upgrades.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>/var/lib/trustgrid/config - These aren&amp;rsquo;t actually logs but contain the node configuration files which may be needed by support to verify the configuration has been successfully retrieved by the node from the control plane.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Authorization to Request Support</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/request-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/trustgrid-support/request-support/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To prevent unauthorized users from potentially compromising the control plane, Trustgrid has implemented a policy to approve customers&amp;rsquo; staff for access to technical support services. Trustgrid will not refuse support completely in cases when unauthorized staff request it, but will limit the disclosure of confidential information and will refuse to make configuration changes without approval from an authorized support contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>All staff who request support must have a portal login.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Trustgrid support staff will not execute any change requested by staff that exceeds that staff members access to portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a. Monitor Access: Staff can alert of issues and request remote assistance but no change in the portal can be requested or made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. Operator Access: Staff can alert of issues and request remote assistance but only changes limited to the Operator role can be requested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. Administrator Access: Staff can request any system change.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Site Requirements</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/site-requirements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/site-requirements/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Trustgrid’s architecture consists of Nodes deployed at the Edge (on-premise) and management infrastructure built in AWS. Nodes create tunnels to other nodes for data transfer, and to the management infrastructure for control. All tunnels are TLS connections and must be permitted by any firewall between&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="network-requirements-for-all-nodes">Network Requirements for All Nodes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In order to connect to the Trustgrid Control Plane, the following outbound traffic must be allowed from the node’s configured primary interface IP address&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>TCP Port 443 and TCP/UDP 8443 to:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>35.171.100.16/28&lt;/li>
&lt;li>34.223.12.192/28&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TCP/UDP Port 53 to the configured DNS servers. These DNS servers must be accessible from the WAN/outside interface IP and be able to resolve DNS requests for the trustgrid.io domain&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Trustgrid nodes will attempt connect to 169.254.169.254 on port 80. This is a standard instance metadata server in public clouds such as AWS and Azure. This connectivity is not required outside these providers.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="recommendations">Recommendations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At least 10 Mbps download speed is recommended for reasonable performance during upgrades. Actual bandwidth requirement will be specific to the workloads running across the device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hardware devices are recommended to be connected to ports configured for 1000 Mbps and full duplex with auto negotiation on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gateway-node-network-requirements">Gateway Node Network Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to being able to connect to the Control Plane resource outlined above, Gateway Nodes must be allowed to receive inbound traffic on their configured public IP and port (typically TCP/UDP port 8443). Both the advertised public IP and port are configurable when enabling a node as a gateway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Network Groups</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>A network group is a list of &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/">network objects&lt;/a> that allows for easier rule management.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A network group requires a name to be set. This will be used to reference the group in &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/">access policy&lt;/a> rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-groups2.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigating into a network group allows management of the group’s member objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="member-network-objects.png" alt="img">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Restart the Trustgrid Service on a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/restart-node/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Restarting the Trustgrid service is faster than a full node reboot and resolves many non-recurring problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the &lt;code>Node&lt;/code> detail page for the node affected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;code>Restart&lt;/code> located in the top right corner of the page&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="restart1.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>After clicking, type in the name of the node and click &lt;code>Confirm&lt;/code> to execute the action&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="execute2.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>the node agent will restart (Node host will not restart)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Expect the node to alert for disconnection and connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Reboot a Node</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/reboot-node/</guid><description>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the Node from the node page you wish to reboot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;code>Reboot&lt;/code> from the top right corner of the page&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="reboot.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Type in the name of the node in the text box, and click the confirmation button&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="execute.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>The node will reboot within 60 seconds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Node agent will start automatically on reboot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expect the node to alert for disconnect/connect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does not require a cloud gateway&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: VRFs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vrfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vrfs/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>VRFs can be used route / nat and filter what traffic is allowed to pass and how it should appear on the network. VRFs can be associated to an interface whether it be a physical interface / virtual network interface or other tunnel interfaces such as ipsec or gre. VRFs are segmented on a layer 3 level from all other traffic traversing the Trustgrid node.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For standard use cases of source nat and/or destination nat creating a route and a NAT is sufficient. Traffic rules can be used for more advanced controls. An applicable ACL is required for any traffic to pass as a zero trust methodology is applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="address-translation">Address Translation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is where NATs are created in order to translate the traffic to appear as desired on the network.
NATs support translating both source and destination CIDRs as well as masquerading as the egress interface address.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="snat--dnat-example">SNAT / DNAT Example&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>Using the example NAT below if a source packet was initiated from 10.10.10.100 destined for 10.10.20.100 the source address would be translated to 192.168.10.100 and the destination address would be translated to 192.168.20.100.
It is important to note that nat translations occur before routing decisions are made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="nat1.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="maquerade-example">Maquerade Example&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>Using the example below if a source packet is initiated from within 10.10.10.0/24 destined for anything in 192.168.10.0/24 the source would be translated to the interface address the packet is egressing on. If it was a single interface Trustgrid node it would be sourced as the wan facing interface address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="masquerade1.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="routes">Routes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Note that NAT translations happen before routing so routes should be created for the destination NAT CIDR if applicable.
Routes require a destination CIDR, interface and metric.
A next hop is optional and only applicable for non-tunnel interfaces such as physical interfaces or vlan subinterfaces.
The gateway of the applicable interface will be used if no next hop is defined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The example below would be used for example to offload all internet bound traffic directly out the WAN facing interface&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="offload.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="traffic-rules">Traffic Rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Traffic rules can be used for more advanced granular traffic manipulation beyond standard source and destination nat.
There are many more parameters that can be applied to the traffic depending on the specific use case.
When creating a traffic rule an ACL is required for traffic to pass. The available parameters are defined below.
Rules are evaluated based on the line number. The first matching rule is the one that will be applied to the packet.
More specific rules should always be implemented above less specific rules. Eg a rule for a /24 network should be above a /16 network the /24 is included in.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="number">
&lt;th>Number&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The line number the rule is applied to. Rules are matched in numerical order.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="action">
&lt;th>Action&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>All traffic rules have an action that is applied to the associated packet.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accept - The packet is allowed to be processed locally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drop - The packet is dropped and not responded to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reject - A TCP Reset is sent in response&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forward - The packet is forwarded to its defined destination such as an interface or another VRF&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mirror - Packets are not manipulated but can be mirrored for inspection purposes.
For example passing through an IDS container such as Snort.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Log - The packet is not manipulated but is marked for logging&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ingress-interface">
&lt;th>Ingress Interface&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The traffic rule is applied to packets that ingress on this interface&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="forward-interface">
&lt;th>Forward Interface&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Packets are forwarded out this interface once the rule is applied&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="protcol">
&lt;th>Protcol&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The protocol that the rule should apply to. All, ICMP, TCP or UDP&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="forward-vrf">
&lt;th>Forward VRF&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Packets are forwarded into another VRF that is associated on the node. Only configureable when a forward action is selected.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="source-cidr">
&lt;th>Source CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The source network the rule should apply to&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination-cidr">
&lt;th>Destination CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The destination network the rule should apply to&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="masquerade">
&lt;th>Masquerade&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Translate and source all packets from the nodes interface address when enabled&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dnat-destination">
&lt;th>DNAT Destination&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Forward all traffic to the DNAT destination IP/Port. For example in order to forward all http traffic through a proxy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination-mac">
&lt;th>Destination Mac&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The destination mac address defined overwrites the source mac address of the packet. Necessary only for some container deployments such as Snort inpsecting traffic.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ports">
&lt;th>Ports&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Used to define a port range when creating a traffic rule&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h6 id="traffic-rule-example">Traffic Rule Example&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>In the below example the first rule on line number 1 is forwarding all traffic destined to 10.0.20.0/24 to a virtual network tunnel interface. Any NATs configured under Address Translation will be applied before the packet is forwarded to its destination. The rule on line number 10 will forward all traffic that does not match the first rule out to the internet masquerading as the WAN interfaces address.
If the line numbers were reversed the virtual network rule would never be matched as all traffic would match the internet offload rule which is configured for all source and destination traffic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="trafficrule1.png" alt="img">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: ZTNA Gateway</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/ztna-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/ztna-gateway/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Navigate to a node, then select &lt;code>ZTNA Gateway&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ztna-gateway.png" alt="ztna-gateway">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="https-endpoint">HTTPS Endpoint&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The HTTPS endpoint is used to provide connectivity for non-WireGuard ZTNA &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/">applications&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="enabled">
&lt;th>Enabled&lt;/th>
&lt;td>When enabled, this node will listen for ZTNA traffic.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="public-fqdn">
&lt;th>Public FQDN&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP or FQDN of the node or the load balancer in front of the node. If using a domain name without a load balancer, be sure to select the appropriate &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/certificates/">certificate&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="port">
&lt;th>Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port to listen on. Users will always connect on port 443, so only change this if the node is behind a load balancer.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="certificate">
&lt;th>Certificate&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The certificate to use for TLS traffic. Only needed if the node is to be directly accessed by users (i.e., without a load balancer) and the FQDN is a domain name.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="wireguard-endpoint">WireGuard Endpoint&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The WireGuard endpoint is used to provide connectivity for WireGuard ZTNA &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/">applications&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="enabled">
&lt;th>Enabled&lt;/th>
&lt;td>When enabled, this node will listen for WireGuard traffic.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="public-fqdn">
&lt;th>Public FQDN&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP or FQDN of the node or the load balancer in front of the node.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="port">
&lt;th>Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port to listen on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="public-key">
&lt;th>Public Key&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The node&amp;rsquo;s WireGuard public key. This can be generated or imported using the actions dropdown. Note that regenerated the key will disconnect existing clients and require users to reconfigure their WireGuard connection.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>“WireGuard” is a registered trademark of Jason A. Donenfeld.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Routes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Routes configured under &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/">Domains&lt;/a> determine to which &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">Trustgrid virtual network&lt;/a> should route traffic for a specific subnet.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="virtual-network-routes">Virtual Network Routes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Routes defined a the virtual network level allow creating a global route table shared with all nodes and clusters attached to the virtual network. This table is then used to evaluate where to send VPN traffic for a specified destination CIDR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="routes-list.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="route-fields">Route Fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Route has the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="destination">
&lt;th>Destination&lt;/th>
&lt;td>This will be the name of the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> that traffic will be routed to. This list is auto-populated based on the nodes and clusters in the selected &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/">domain&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination-cidr">
&lt;th>Destination CIDR&lt;/th>
&lt;td>This is the CIDR notation of the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a> that should be routed to the above destination &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="metric">
&lt;th>Metric&lt;/th>
&lt;td>If there are multiple routes for the same &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a> the metric will determine which route will be used. The lowest number is the highest priority. See the &amp;ldquo;Automatic Failover&amp;rdquo; text below.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="description">
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;td>(Optional) This field can be used to provide additional information about the purpose of the route. e.g. it could label a route as a DR route indicating that in normal circumstances it would have a higher metric than a primary route.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="managing-virtual-network-routes">Managing Virtual Network Routes&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="adding-virtual-network-routes">Adding Virtual Network Routes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to Domain &amp;gt; Virtual Networks and select the desired Virtual Network.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Routes table is selected by default
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-route-table.png" alt="Virtual Network named vNet1 with the Routes option selected in the navigation menu" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Virtual Network &amp;gt; Routes
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Tip: Use the search field to filter the list of routes so you can see the routes you are adding. You could filter by the CIDR address or part of the destination node/cluster names. This will show any existing matching routes, and will make it easy to see the new routes you are adding.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the add route button.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="add-route-button.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Add route button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide the desired route information in the &lt;a href="#route-fields">fields&lt;/a> &lt;ol type="A">&lt;li>Select the destination cluster or node&lt;/li>&lt;li>Enter the destination network in CIDR notation. For a single IP use /32.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Enter a metric between 1 and 200.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Optionally, provide a description.&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="new-route-entry.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat the above two steps for any additional routes you wish to add.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the Save button.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="save-button.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 20%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Save route button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There should be a notification saying &amp;ldquo;Routes Updated&amp;rdquo; but you will need to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">review and apply changes&lt;/a> before the changes are actually be published to nodes in your environment.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="saved-route.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example of a saved route
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
As stated above, the route changes are not actually implemented until you click the Apply button the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">Review Changes&lt;/a> panel.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="deleting-virtual-network-routes">Deleting Virtual Network Routes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to Domain &amp;gt; Virtual Networks and select the desired Virtual Network.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Routes table is selected by default
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-route-table.png" alt="Virtual Network named vNet1 with the Routes option selected in the navigation menu" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Virtual Network &amp;gt; Routes
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the search field to filter the list of routes.
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
You could filter by the CIDR address or part of the destination node/cluster names. This will show any existing matching routes, and will make it easy to see the new routes so you can delete them.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the red X on the far right of the route being removed.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="delete-route.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; ">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat the above two steps for any additional routes you wish to add.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the Save button.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="save-button.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 20%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Save route button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There should be a notification saying &amp;ldquo;Routes Updated&amp;rdquo; but you will need to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">review and apply changes&lt;/a> before the changes are actually be published to nodes in your environment.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="saved-route.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example of a saved route
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="route-failover">Route Failover &lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Route failover allows a subnet to be routed to an alternate &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> in the event of a failure.  This can be automatic or performed manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites &lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In either configuration, the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a> settings under VPN settings for the primary and backup destination &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">clusters&lt;/a> must match. Including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Network Virtual Route&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="virtual-network-route.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Network Group under Outside NAT Table&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="outside-nat-table.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Virtual CIDR under Inside NAT Table&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="inside-nat-table.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="automatic-failover">Automatic Failover&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To have the route failover without manual intervention you must define two routes for the same subnet (Destination CIDR) with different metrics.  The lowest numerical metric will take precedence unless the destination &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> is offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the below example configuration we want traffic for the 10.20.0.0/24 network to the &lt;code>edge&lt;/code> &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a> first, and failover to the &lt;code>edge-dr&lt;/code> &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="automatic-failover.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preventing-automated-failback-or-forcing-a-failover">Preventing Automated Failback or Forcing a Failover&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As mentioned above if multiple routes are configured traffic will route to destination with the lowest metric number. So if the primary destination fails but then comes back online traffic will be routed back automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there are some circumstances where this is not desirable. For example, if the primary site is unstable you may wish to keep traffic at the backup site until the primary is stabilized. Alternately, you may wish to preemptively reroute traffic to the backup site in advance of planned maintenance at the primary site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To preemptively reroute traffic to the backup site, update the backup route to have a lower metric than the primary route.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="manual-failover">Manual Failover&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In some circumstances, it may be preferable for failover to only occur with manual intervention. In this situation, you will have a single route under the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/">domain&lt;/a>.  To initiate a failover you&amp;rsquo;ll need to update the destination &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/">cluster&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Login to the Portal and select your domain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the link to the desired &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/">domain&lt;/a> under the &amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; column.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">&amp;ldquo;Virtual Networks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> section and select the &amp;ldquo;Routes&amp;rdquo; tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the route you wish to failover.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update the destination device. (e.g. in the below you would switch from edge to edge-dr).
&lt;img src="update-destination.png" alt="Update Destination">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click save.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Virtual Network Port Forwards</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/remote-port-forward/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
Virtual Network Port Forwards allow a virtual IP address to be associated with a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">Layer 4 service&lt;/a> on a remote node or cluster without the need to specify a route for that virtual IP address.
&lt;/div>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="remote-port-forward.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example Virtual Network Port Forward
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As noted above, a Virtual Network Port Forward (or remote port forward) associates a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">service&lt;/a> defined on a node or cluster with a virtual IP address within the virtual network without needing to specifically &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">route&lt;/a> that IP to the node/cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any node attached to the virtual network that receives VPN traffic destined for the configure IP and port will proxy the connection and send the traffic to the target node which will then send the traffic to the IP and port configured for the target service.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="virtual-ip-address">
&lt;th>Virtual IP Address&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Virtual IP address assigned to the port forward.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="virtual-port">
&lt;th>Virtual Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>TCP port on which the port forward will listen for connections.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination-node">
&lt;th>Destination Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Node or Cluster where the target &lt;strong>service&lt;/strong> is defined.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination-service">
&lt;th>Destination Service&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Service that traffic for the &lt;strong>virtual IP&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>virtual port&lt;/strong> will be forwarded to.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/access-policy/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>An access policy is a list of rules that each allow, reject, or drop traffic at the VPN level.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>If no rules are defined, traffic will not pass through the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A rule can match traffic based on the following fields:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="action">
&lt;th>Action&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Whether to ALLOW, DROP, or REJECT the traffic.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="protocol">
&lt;th>Protocol&lt;/th>
&lt;td>You can choose ANY, UDP, ICMP, or TCP.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="source">
&lt;th>Source&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The source of the traffic. You can select a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/">network object&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/">network group&lt;/a>, or provide a CIDR.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="destination">
&lt;th>Destination&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The destination of the traffic. You can select a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-objects/">network object&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/network-groups/">network group&lt;/a>, or provide a CIDR.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="line-number">
&lt;th>Line Number&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Rules are evaluated starting with the lowest numbered rule. Once a rule matches, later rules are ignored even if they might also match the traffic.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="port-range">
&lt;th>Port Range&lt;/th>
&lt;td>For TCP and UDP traffic, you can specify a port (e.g., 80) or a range (e.g., 8000-9000).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="access-policy.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note that &lt;em>all specified&lt;/em> fields must be matched for the rule to match.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help-Center: Network Flow Logs</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/flow-logs/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Flow logs are a records of for network traffic that passes through a node. They can be used to troubleshoot connectivity issues, or to monitor traffic patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-flow-logs">What are flow logs?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flow logs are records containing metadata about each network traffic flow, or conversation, from the initial connection (e.g. the first SYN packet for TCP) to the closing of the connection (e.g. FIN or RST packets for TCP). Flow logs &lt;strong>do not contain any payload data&lt;/strong> for the flow which makes them much smaller and more secure than a full packet capture of the same flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flow logs can be used for troubleshooting by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Verifying that both the expected source and destination node have the appropriate logs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>That any &lt;a href="#nat-impact-on-source-and-destination-fields">NATs&lt;/a> are applying as expected.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>That the expected number of flows or sent/received byte are being passed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TCP Flags can be used to confirm a successful connection is being made. For example:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A TCP Flow with only a SYN flag is never completing the TCP Handshake process indicating an issue, such as a firewall or routing configuration problem, preventing the destination IP from either receiving packets or replying successfully&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A TCP Flow with only a SYN &amp;amp; RST flag indicates something in the path is actively resetting the connection attempt. This could be a firewall or an application IP restriction.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="flow-log-data">Flow Log Data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Below are the potential fields of a single flow log.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="start-time">
&lt;th>Start Time&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The time the flow started&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="end-time">
&lt;th>End Time&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The time the flow ended&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="protocol">
&lt;th>Protocol&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The protocol of the traffic TCP, UDP, ICMP&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="source-node">
&lt;th>Source Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The node that initiated the flow&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="source-ip">
&lt;th>Source IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP address through which the node initiated the flow&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="source-port">
&lt;th>Source Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port through which the node initiated the flow&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dest-node">
&lt;th>Dest Node&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The node that received the flow&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dest-ip">
&lt;th>Dest IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP address to which traffic was sent&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dest-port">
&lt;th>Dest Port&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The port to which traffic was sent&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="recv-bytes">
&lt;th>Recv Bytes&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Bytes received at the source node&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="sent-bytes">
&lt;th>Sent Bytes&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Bytes sent from the source node&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="tcp-flags">
&lt;th>TCP Flags&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>All TCP Flags set on any packets seen over the duration of the flow:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>SYN - sync packet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PSH - push packet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ACK - ack packet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>URG - urgent packet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FIN - finish packet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RST - reset packet&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>TCP Flags are only available for &lt;strong>TCP&lt;/strong> flows that traverse the layer 3 VPN function. ICMP and UDP traffic, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/services/">Layer 4 services&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vpn/port-forwarding/">VPN Port Forwards&lt;/a> will not have this data.&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="nat-impact-on-source-and-destination-fields">NAT Impact on Source and Destination Fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vpn/nats/">NATs&lt;/a> are applied to a flow they will influence the source/destination IP and port values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consider this flow:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="mermaid">graph LR
client(HTTP Client\n192.168.100.1) -- src: 192.168.100.1\ndest: 10.100.1.1--> Node1
subgraph Virtual Network
Node1 -- src: 10.100.2.1\ndest: 10.100.1.1 --> Node2[Node2 \n Local IP\n172.16.1.100]
end
Node2 --src: 172.16.1.100 \n dest:172.16.1.20 --> server(HTTP Server\n172.16.1.20)
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Node1 would report the flow before any NATs were applied&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Source IP&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Destination IP&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>192.168.100.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>10.100.1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Node2 would report the flow after the NATs on Node1 were applied (changing the source 10.100.2.1) and the NATs on Node2 were applied (changing the source to 172.16.1.100 and the destination to 172.16.1.20)&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Source IP&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Destination IP&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>192.168.100.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>10.100.1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note:&lt;/h4>
For simplicity sake ports were excluded. Destination ports will not be changed by NATs. Source ports would also be maintained for any 1:1 NAT, but would change if a many:1 (or overload) NAT was applied to the flow.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="viewing-flow-logs">Viewing Flow Logs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flow logs are visible at an organization level by navigating to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/operations/flow-logs/">Operations &amp;gt; Flow Logs&lt;/a>. This will show you the most recent 1000 flows over the last two hours for the &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> nodes in the organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view Flow Logs only for traffic through a specific node, navigate to that node and go to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/flow-logs/">History &amp;gt; Flow Logs&lt;/a>. This will show you the most recent 1000 flows over the last two hours for the &lt;strong>currently selected&lt;/strong> node.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="flow-logs-node.png" alt="table showing flow log entries for a node" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example flow log table for a node
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="advanced-search">Advanced Search&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Flow logs can be filtered by any of the fields listed above. To filter by a field, click the &lt;code>Advanced Search&lt;/code> button at the top right of the flow logs table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, the ordering can be changed so that oldest flows (or flows closest to the time range specified) can be shown first. There is a limit of 10,000 flows returned per search.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="advanced-search.png" alt="Dialog showing the various search filter parameters available in advanced search." style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Advanced Search dialog
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="exporting-flow-logs-to-csv">Exporting Flow Logs to CSV&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>From the Flow logs table you can export the current filtered logs to a CSV file for further analysis or reporting. Several fields are exported differently in the CSV file:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are the potential fields of a single flow log.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="start-and-end-time">
&lt;th>Start and End Time&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Both of these fields exported two different ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Human friendly in the format: MM/DD/YYYY HH:MM:SS AM/PM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Timestamp in milliseconds since epoch for machine parsing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="tcp-flags">
&lt;th>TCP Flags&lt;/th>
&lt;td>TCP Flags are exported in hexadeximal format (e.g. 0x02 for SYN flag set) rather than the human friendly names. See the below section for more info on converting these values.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="understanding-tcp-flag-hex-values">Understanding TCP Flag Hex Values&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When exporting TCP flags to CSV, the values will be shown as hexadecimal numbers rather than the human readable names (e.g. SYN, ACK). The below table shows how each flag would be prepresented as a hex value or binary value.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Hex Value&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Binary Representation&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Flag Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x01&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00000001&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FIN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Finish (end of data communication)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x02&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00000010&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SYN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Synchronize sequence numbers&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x04&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00000100&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>RST&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reset the connection&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x08&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00001000&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>PSH&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Push function&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x10&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00010000&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>ACK&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Acknowledgment&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x20&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>00100000&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>URG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Urgent pointer field significant&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x40&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>01000000&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>ECE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Explicit Congestion Notification Echo&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x80&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>10000000&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CWR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Congestion Window Reduced&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>The CSV export will show the hex value that represents the combination of set flags. For example, a flow with SYN and ACK flags set would show the hex value &lt;code>0x12&lt;/code> in the CSV, representing the binary value &lt;code>00010010&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note:&lt;/h4>
The value shown is the total of ALL flags seen on all packets that are part of the flow. If you are only used to looking at the flags of individual packets you will see combinations not normal in regular TCP traffic. For example a complete flow might have a SYN, ACK, RST and FIN.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To convert hax flags to human readable format first convert to binary then check each bit position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To convert hex to binary you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>an online tool like &lt;a href="https://www.binaryhexconverter.com/hex-to-binary-converter">Binary to Hexadecimal Converter&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>searching google.com using the prompt &lt;code>0x## to binary&lt;/code> (replacing the ## with the hex value)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the &lt;code>=HEX2BIN(hex_value)&lt;/code> function in Excel or Google sheets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then you can use the resulting bit map with a table like below to convert to human readable flags:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Example Hex&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Binary Equivalent&lt;/th>
&lt;th>CWR&lt;/th>
&lt;th>ECE&lt;/th>
&lt;th>URG&lt;/th>
&lt;th>ACK&lt;/th>
&lt;th>PSH&lt;/th>
&lt;th>RST&lt;/th>
&lt;th>SYN&lt;/th>
&lt;th>FIN&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0xd6&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>1101 0110&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0x1b&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>0001 1011&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Upgrading Trustgrid Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/upgrade-nodes/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="how-a-node-appliance-upgrades">How a Node Appliance Upgrades&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The upgrade process will:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Upgrade the Trustgrid application package. As part of this process the node will backup the current running version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Apply security updates to install operating system packages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reboot the Trustgrid node appliance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>For details on what this looks like from a network level see the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/upgrade-process/">Node Upgrade Process KB&lt;/a> article.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is the upgrade disruptive?&lt;/strong> - Yes. While the appliance is upgrading services will remain available, though performance may be degraded. However, &lt;strong>the reboot step will make all services unavailable&lt;/strong> until the appliance fully boots and starts the Trustgrid service. Typically this takes a few minutes depending on the underlying hardware.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>How long will the upgrade take?&lt;/strong> - This is highly variable but typically this takes between 10 minutes and an hour. Below are a list of things that influence how long the upgrade takes:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Internet bandwidth - This determines how quickly the node can download the updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time since previous update - The longer a node goes without updating the more security packages are likely to be required.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CPU and disk performance - The upgrade process involves significant CPU processing and to a lesser extent disk I/O. The upgrade process is single-threaded, so core speed is more important than number of cores.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="best-practices">Best Practices&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade nodes regularly to ensure access to the latest features and security updates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For clustered nodes:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade the standby node&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change the standby node to be the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/#configured-master">configured master/active&lt;/a> and wait for it to claim this role.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade the new standby node in the cluster&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Utilize an &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/alarms/alert-suppression/#define-alert-suppression-window">Alert Suppression Window&lt;/a> to reduce the number of alarms generated if upgrading many nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="required-permissions">Required Permissions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to perform the below actions a user must have a &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/user-management/policies/">policy&lt;/a> applied with the following permissions to the nodes that will be upgraded.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-json" data-lang="json">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;statements&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">[&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;effect&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;allow&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;actions&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">[&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;nodes::read&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;nodes::upgrade&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;nodes::manage&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;nodes::service:node-upgrade&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;portal::access&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">]&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The above is only a partial policy. Use the policy creator to define a complete policy
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-a-single-node">Upgrading a Single Node&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to the node that will be upgraded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the tool bar click the Upgrade button.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="node-upgrade-button.png" alt="Toolbar showing an Upgrade (surrounded by a red rectangle), Refresh and Info buttons." style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Upgrade button
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When prompted enter the node&amp;rsquo;s name and click confirm.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="node-upgrade-confirm.png" alt="Dialogue asking to enter the node name to confirm" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Node upgrade confirmation
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A dialogue will indicate the command was successfully sent.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="single-node-upgrade-report.png" alt="Dialogue stating &amp;#39;Upgrade in progress" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Node upgrade response
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-multiple-nodes">Upgrading Multiple Nodes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/#node-list-view">Nodes table&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Use the search box or &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/#applying-a-tag-filter-to-the-nodes-table">apply a tag filter&lt;/a> to filter the displayed nodes.
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Note: if you change the search or tag filter any selected nodes will be deselected.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the check boxes to select the desired nodes.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="multi-node-select.png" alt="Nodes table showing two nodes selected" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Nodes table
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the actions dropdown select Upgrade.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="nodes-upgrade-action.png" alt="Action dropdown menu with red box around Upgrade option" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Action &amp;gt; Upgrade
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When prompted, confirm you want to proceed with the bulk upgrade.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="multi-node-upgrade-confirm.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Confirm bulk upgrade
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A table will be presented showing the status of each node upgrade request.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="multi-node-upgrade-report.png" alt="Upgrade Operation Report table showing two nodes were requested to upgrade and both are in progress" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 70%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Upgrade Operation Report
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="monitoring-upgrade-progress">Monitoring Upgrade Progress&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can monitor the upgrade status from a node&amp;rsquo;s Info tab.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="upgrade-status-inprog.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 75%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Info tab, Upgrade in Progress
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two fields
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="upgrade-status">
&lt;th>Upgrade Status&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;p>Shows the most recent status of an upgrade operation on this node. Possibly values are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Progress&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Failed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="completion-time">
&lt;th>Completion Time&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Shows a timestamp for the last time an upgrade operation completed.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Note: if an upgrade is currently &lt;strong>In Progress&lt;/strong>, then this will be the completion time of the prior upgrade operations
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="upgrade-status-completed.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 80%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Example of Completed upgrade status
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Docs: DNS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/dns/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The DNS feature allows nodes in the virtual network to act as DNS servers for ingress VPN traffic. The node can resolve queries custom defines DNS zones and records, or forward queries to upstream DNS servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dns-settings">DNS Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="enable/disable-dns">
&lt;th>Enable/Disable DNS&lt;/th>
&lt;td>This field enables or disables the DNS feature on the virtual network.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="dns-server-ip">
&lt;th>DNS Server IP&lt;/th>
&lt;td>This is the IP address that should be used as the resolver. There is no need to create a VPN route for this IP. If the ingress node was the &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/vpn/dns/">DNS feature enabled&lt;/a> it will automatically handle responses for the query.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-dns-settings.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
DNS Settings
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After making any changes to the DNS settings you will need to &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">review and apply changes&lt;/a> for the updates to take effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dns-zones">DNS Zones&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Optionally you can create custom DNS zones and either:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Configure specific DNS records to resolve to IPs/hosts on the virtual network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure a node as a resolver for this zone. Requests will be forwarded to that node and resolved by its DNS servers or configured upstream servers.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-dns-zones.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 40%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
DNS Zone Settings
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="adding-a-dns-zone">Adding a DNS Zone&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a custom DNS zone:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click the &amp;ldquo;Add Zone&amp;rdquo; button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide a name for the zone (e.g. example.com).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally, provide a description for the zone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">Review and apply changes&lt;/a> to save the zone.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-dns-add-zone.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Adding a DNS Zone
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Once a zone has been added, you can configure either a DNS resolver or specific DNS records.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
You cannot have both custom DNS records and a resolver configured for the same zone.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="configuring-a-dns-resolver">Configuring a DNS Resolver&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the zone name to enter its configuration page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &amp;ldquo;Resolver&amp;rdquo;, select a node from the dropdown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; to save the resolver configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">Review and apply changes&lt;/a> to update the DNS configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="configuring-dns-records">Configuring DNS Records&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>DNS records allow mapping names to IP addresses for hosts on the virtual network. DNS records have the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Field Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr id="name">
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The hostname being mapped (e.g. www). The zone name will be automatically appended.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="record-type">
&lt;th>Record Type&lt;/th>
&lt;td>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A - for records that should resolve to an IP address&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CNAME - for alias/canonical name records&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="value">
&lt;th>Value&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The IP address or hostname being mapped to for A/CNAME records respectively.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr id="ttl">
&lt;th>TTL&lt;/th>
&lt;td>Time To Live - how long records may be cached by other resolvers.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>To add a DNS record:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on the zone name to enter its configuration page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &amp;ldquo;DNS Records&amp;rdquo;, click &amp;ldquo;Add Record&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide the required fields
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="vnet-dns-add-record.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 60%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Add DNS Record prompt
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click save.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) repeat to add more records to the current zone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/review-changes/">Review and apply changes&lt;/a> to save the record(s).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Deleting Trustgrid Nodes</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/deleting-nodes/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-danger" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Be advised:&lt;/strong> Deleting a node is an irreversible action. Delete nodes only after you are certain it is no longer needed.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="best-practices">Best Practices&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/">Disable the node(s)&lt;/a> for several days prior to deleting. This way if it is discovered that it is still needed it is simple to re-enable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/tags/prod-status-tag/">Update any status tag&lt;/a> to indicate the node(s) is being decommissioned.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before deleting, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/#deleting-virtual-network-routes">remove any virtual network routes&lt;/a> with the node as a destination. While these can be removed later, they will be easier to find while the node is still listed as the destination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="deleting-nodes">Deleting Nodes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>If the node(s) is not already disabled, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/management-tasks/changing-node-status/">disable the node(s)&lt;/a> &lt;strong>See best practice above before proceeding&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the node(s) is a member of a cluster, &lt;a href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/clusters/manage-members/#remove-member">remove the node(s) from the cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to the Nodes table and select the target node(s).
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Optionally, Use the search to filter the displayed nodes.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the Actions menu select the Delete option.
&lt;figure class="centered-image">
&lt;img src="delete-node-action.png" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 30%;">
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: center; margin-top: 0.5rem;font-weight:lighter;">
Delete node action
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>If deleting a single node, you will be prompted to enter the name of the node about to be deleted to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If deleting multiple nodes, you will be prompted to enter &lt;code>DELETE&lt;/code> to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>