<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gateway on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/</link><description>Recent content in Gateway on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gateway Server Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</guid><description>Gateways servers are nodes that are configured to receive connections from other Trustgrid nodes (clients). These are the only nodes that need to have ports open and listening on the internet or WAN network.
The server sub-panel provides the settings controlling if a node will act as a server and if so how clients will connect to it.
Gateway Server Types A gateway server can be one of three types:</description></item><item><title>Gateway Client Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</guid><description>Settings on this page determine how a node&amp;rsquo;s client connection to gateway peers behave.
Settings Field Name Description UDP Enabled This settings can be configured on both the gateway server and gateway client sub-panel.
On a server, this will determine if the server will listen for UDP tunnel connections on the configured UDP port. On a client, this will determine if the client will attempt to build UDP tunnels to any server with UDP enabled.</description></item><item><title>Gateway Diagnostics</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</guid><description>The diagnostics page includes stats on aggregate traffic across all peer tunnels regardless of overlay service as well as tools for troubleshooting connectivity.
Gateway Diagnostics Page Gateway Troubleshooting Tool The Troubleshoot Gateway Traffic tool allows you to inspect live diagnostic messages about traffic between this node and its configured peers. Gateway Troubleshooting Tool Clicking the &amp;ldquo;Troubleshoot Gateway Traffic&amp;rdquo; button will open the below diaglog that allows for filtering the output seen in the Troubleshoot Gateway tool by peer, local or service.</description></item></channel></rss>