<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gateway on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/</link><description>Recent content in Gateway on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gateway Client Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-client/</guid><description>Settings on this page determine how a node&amp;rsquo;s client connection to gateway peers behave.
Settings Gateway Client settings Field Name Description Connectivity to Public Gateways Options are Allowed or Denied. If set to Denied this will cause the node to not attempt connections to public gateways. This might be desired if you want the node to only connect to configured private gateways. Or if you have private gateways that do not need to connect to the public gateways in your organization.</description></item><item><title>Gateway Diagnostics</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-diag/</guid><description>Traffic Volume Data This graph displays the traffic volume of all data plane communications between the node and its peers.
Gateway Diagnostics Page</description></item><item><title>Gateway Server Settings</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/nodes/appliances/gateway/gateway-server/</guid><description>Gateways servers are nodes that are configured to receive connections from other Trustgrid nodes (clients). These are the only nodes that need to have ports open and listening on the internet or WAN network.
The server sub-panel provides the settings controlling if a node will act as a server and if so how clients will connect to it.
Gateway Server Types A gateway server can be one of three types:</description></item></channel></rss>