<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Applications on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/applications/</link><description>Recent content in Applications on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/access-policy/</guid><description>An Access Policy is comprised of several rules that determine whether a user is permitted to access a ZTNA application. If no rule matches a user&amp;rsquo;s access attempt, the attempt will be denied.
Each rule has three types of criteria:
Field Name Description Include criteria in this section are logically OR&amp;rsquo;d together. For a rule to apply to an access attempt, at least one of the include criteria must match.</description></item><item><title>RDP App</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/rdp-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/rdp-app/</guid><description>A RDP app is a ZTNA application that allows remote access to an internal RDP server. RDP servers can be hosted internally but exposed to authorized users.
General Field Name Description Name app name Description app description Icon the application&amp;rsquo;s icon (optional) to show in the application dashboard Connectivity Connectivity type:
local to gateway - the application is hosted on the same network as the gateway remote node - the application is hosted on an edge node&amp;rsquo;s network virtual network - the application is accessible over the Trustgrid virtual network from the ZTNA gateway ZTNA Gateway - the ZTNA gateway node that will be used to connect to the application</description></item><item><title>SSH App</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/ssh-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/ssh-app/</guid><description>A SSH app is a ZTNA application that allows remote access to internal SSH servers. SSH servers can be hosted internally but exposed to authorized users.
General Field Name Description Name app name Description app description Icon the application&amp;rsquo;s icon (optional) to show in the application dashboard Connectivity Connectivity type:
local to gateway - the application is hosted on the same network as the gateway remote node - the application is hosted on an edge node&amp;rsquo;s network virtual network - the application is accessible over the Trustgrid virtual network from the ZTNA gateway ZTNA Gateway - the ZTNA gateway node that will be used to connect to the application</description></item><item><title>Trusted Links</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/web-app/trusted-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/web-app/trusted-links/</guid><description>Trusted links allow a user to allow-list only specific URLs when accessed through a ZTNA application. This allows a user to access any URL on the internet through a ZTNA application, but only if the URL is explicitly allowed by the application.
This can be used to permit readonly or certain operations remotely, but still require local access for more sensitive operations.</description></item><item><title>Visibility</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/visibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/visibility/</guid><description>Visibility groups determine what applications a user can see on their application dashboard. A user must be a member of at least one selected group to see an application.</description></item><item><title>VNC App</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/vnc-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/vnc-app/</guid><description>A VNC app is a ZTNA application that allows remote access to an internal VNC server. VNC servers can be hosted internally but exposed to authorized users.
General Field Name Description Name app name Description app description Icon the application&amp;rsquo;s icon (optional) to show in the application dashboard Connectivity Connectivity type:
local to gateway - the application is hosted on the same network as the gateway remote node - the application is hosted on an edge node&amp;rsquo;s network virtual network - the application is accessible over the Trustgrid virtual network from the ZTNA gateway ZTNA Gateway - the ZTNA gateway node that will be used to connect to the application</description></item><item><title>Web App</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/web-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/docs/applications/web-app/</guid><description>A Web App is a ZTNA application that allows remote access to internal web applications. Services such as Jenkins or JIRA can be hosted internally but exposed to authorized users.
General Field Name Description Name app name Description app description Hostname hostname of the internal web application External Address the public URL users will use to access the application Icon the application&amp;rsquo;s icon (optional) to show in the application dashboard Connectivity Connectivity type: local to gateway - the application is hosted on the same network as the gateway remote node - the application is hosted on an edge node&amp;rsquo;s network virtual network - the application is accessible over the Trustgrid virtual network from the ZTNA gateway ZTNA Gateway - the ZTNA gateway node that will be used to connect to the application Destination Node - only available if connectivity type is Remote Node.</description></item></channel></rss>