<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>March</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/march/</guid><description>Improved Identity Provider Integration Trustgrid has supported SAML integration to manage portal access for some time. As we began supporting additional services, such as Remote Access applications, more flexibility was needed.
OpenID Support OpenID is a newer standard for managing communication between an application and an Identity Provider (IdP). It offers additional functionality compared to SAML including the ability to simplify integration.
At this point, Trustgrid supports simplified integration with Google G Suite and Microsoft AzureAD which includes the ability to synchronize groups and group members.</description></item><item><title>August</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/august/</guid><description>Tag Improvements Two major improvements regarding tags.
Cluster Members Inherit Tags Previously you had to set tags at the node and cluster level which required a lot of duplicate effort. Now when you configure tags at the cluster level the member nodes inherit this tag.
Tags Searchable in the Nodes Table With this release if you add a tag as a column to the nodes table, you can then search the table for matching values.</description></item><item><title>September</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/september/</guid><description>Container Improvements Trustgrid has greatly enhanced the container features we support and this release makes these features available to all users.
Container Management You can now stop and start individual containers running as a service from within the portal.
Container Volumes and Mounts Containers on Trustgrid now support creating persistent volumes and mounting them within the container. These volumes can even be encrypted using Trustgrid managed, software-based encryption.
Container Privileges It is now possible to run containers as a privileged user or specify the user/group the container should execute as.</description></item><item><title>December</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/</guid><description>Data Plane Status Table Previously Trustgrid had a visual indicator on the Node detail page to show the Data Plane health of a node, but it only showed the state as Connected, Degraded or Disconnected. While connected and disconnected were clear, there was little information on why the status was Degraded.
With this release hovering over the Data Plane status icon will bring up a pop-up screen showing all the peers and and their connection status.</description></item></channel></rss>