<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edge Node Startup on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/</link><description>Recent content in Edge Node Startup on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration Update Failure Troubleshooting</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/config-update-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/config-update-failure/</guid><description>Symptoms Changes made via the portal or api are not implemented on the actual node In versions after 20240719, the Configuration Update Failure event will be sent by appliance nodes Example Configuration Update Failure event Causes Possible causes include:
The node is unable to resolve Trustgrid.io DNS names, in this case specifically gatekeeper.trustgrid.io The node is unable to connect to the the entire Trustgrid Control Plane networks on port 8443 Troubleshooting These steps should be performed via the Terminal or the appliance console Network Tools Shell.</description></item><item><title>Edge Node Behavior When DNS Resolution Fails</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/dns-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/dns-failure/</guid><description>Symptoms Node does not connect to the Portal Packet captures show repeated DNS queries for gatekeeper.trustgrid.io but no response Cause DNS servers configured on edge node are not accessible A firewall is blocking TCP/UDP port 53 between the edge node and the configured DNS DNS servers configured on edge node cannot resolve public DNS entries for the trustgrid.io domain Troubleshooting Steps Determine the configured DNS Servers - Connecting a monitor to the node will display the current IP configuration including the DNS Servers as shown below: (If possible) Capture traffic between the edge node and the internet and confirm you see both a DNS query (usually for gatekeeper.</description></item><item><title>Edge Node Behavior When SSL / TLS Certificate is Altered</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/ssl-tls-tampering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/help-center/kb/startup-process/ssl-tls-tampering/</guid><description>Products that alter SSL/TLS certificate chains will prevent the node from functioning normally.
Symptoms Node will not connect - This will occur if the SSL/TLS chain is altered on port 8443 Node will not update - This will occur if the SSL/TLS chain is altered on port 443 Packet captures will show something like the below repeating: TLS “Client Hello” Server (Trustgrid IP) will send a reset (RST) Cause The integrity of communication is a critical feature of Trustgrid’s network solution.</description></item></channel></rss>