<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aws on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in Aws on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure HA Trustgrid Gateway Cluster in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</guid><description>Deploy a pair of Trustgrid gateways. Deployment guide includes an example Cloud Formation template that can be used directly or customized for your environment or converted to Terraform if preferred. Gateways can be deployed in the same availability zone or different ones to provide greater redundancy across AWS. Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS.
Under networking &amp;gt; clusters create a cluster using a descriptive and unique name as seen below.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</guid><description>Standing up a Trustgrid node in AWS is easy using an Amazon AMI. Trustgrid nodes in AWS use two network interfaces - a management and a data interface. The management interface communicates with Trustgrid Cloud Management systems. The data interface is used to terminate TLS tunnels from Edge Nodes.
Notes The cloudformation template below works with an AMI currently published in US-EAST1. Deploying in other regions requires working with Trustgrid Support Requires VPC and public subnet Does not create security groups or roles - those have to be managed separately (more below) If using a burstable performance instance types (T2, T3 and T3a) the following is advised:</description></item></channel></rss>