<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aws on</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in Aws on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.trustgrid.io/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS Interface ENA Stats</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-interface-stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-interface-stats/</guid><description>The AWS Stats tool displays Elastic Network Adapter (ENA) statistics for AWS-hosted nodes. These statistics help identify when AWS is throttling network traffic due to instance limits being exceeded. Access requires the service:network-status permission.
Overview When running Trustgrid nodes on AWS EC2 instances, network performance is subject to instance-type-specific limits for bandwidth, packets per second, and connection tracking. The AWS Interface ENA Stats tool allows you to view counters that indicate when these limits have been exceeded, helping diagnose network performance issues.</description></item><item><title>AWS Route Tables Interface Tool</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-route-tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/interface-tools/aws-route-tables/</guid><description>The AWS Route Tables interface tool queries AWS for route tables associated with the selected interface and shows the current route definitions. Use it when validating cluster route failover behavior or investigating unexpected routing.
Accessing AWS Route Tables Open the target node in the Trustgrid portal. Go to Network -&amp;gt; Interfaces. In Interface Tools, click AWS Route Tables. Interface Tools with the AWS Route Tables button highlighted In the service prompt, confirm the interface and click Execute.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/</guid><description>Standing up a Trustgrid node in AWS is easy using an Amazon AMI. Trustgrid nodes in AWS use two network interfaces - a management and a data interface. The management interface communicates with Trustgrid Cloud Management systems. The data interface is used to terminate TLS tunnels from Edge Nodes.
Notes The cloudformation template below works with an AMI currently published in US-EAST-1/2 and US-WEST-1/2. Deploying in other regions requires working with Trustgrid Support Requires VPC and public subnet Does not create security groups or roles - those have to be managed separately (more below) Prerequisites Known Supported Instance Types Architecture t2, t3, t3a, c5, c5n, c6i, c6in, c6a x86_64 only Additional x86_64 instances types may work but have not been tested.</description></item><item><title>Configure HA Trustgrid Gateway Cluster in AWS</title><link>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.trustgrid.io/tutorials/deployments/deploy-aws-ami/configure-ha-gateway-cluster-in-aws/</guid><description>Deploy a pair of Trustgrid gateways. Deployment guide includes an example Cloud Formation template that can be used directly or customized for your environment or converted to Terraform if preferred. Gateways can be deployed in the same availability zone or different ones to provide greater redundancy across AWS. Deploy a Trustgrid Node AMI in AWS.
Under networking &amp;gt; clusters create a cluster using a descriptive and unique name as seen below.</description></item></channel></rss>